[
  {
    "title": "1.1",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Starting to DECAY.",
          "answers": [
            "appear",
            "ripen",
            "rot",
            "change",
            "shrink"
          ],
          "word": "DECAY",
          "correct": "rot"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Why is she so MISERABLE?",
          "answers": [
            "unhappy",
            "greedy",
            "glad",
            "thin",
            "lonely"
          ],
          "word": "MISERABLE",
          "correct": "unhappy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Caused him to TREMBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "jump",
            "stiffen",
            "fall",
            "shake",
            "sweat"
          ],
          "word": "TREMBLE",
          "correct": "shake"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Lost the TROPHY.",
          "answers": [
            "race",
            "chance",
            "jewel",
            "battle",
            "prize"
          ],
          "word": "TROPHY",
          "correct": "prize"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Whom did they ELECT?",
          "answers": [
            "name",
            "vote against",
            "speak to",
            "hope for",
            "choose"
          ],
          "word": "ELECT",
          "correct": "choose"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "You TERRIFY her.",
          "answers": [
            "please",
            "scare",
            "praise",
            "hurt",
            "dislike"
          ],
          "word": "TERRIFY",
          "correct": "scare"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Large TERRITORY.",
          "answers": [
            "building",
            "area",
            "ocean",
            "monster",
            "government"
          ],
          "word": "TERRITORY",
          "correct": "area"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When will it THAW?",
          "answers": [
            "break",
            "rain",
            "flow",
            "melt",
            "freeze"
          ],
          "word": "THAW",
          "correct": "melt"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When will you DEPART?",
          "answers": [
            "begin",
            "finish",
            "leave",
            "come",
            "shop"
          ],
          "word": "DEPART",
          "correct": "leave"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Let them HOLLER.",
          "answers": [
            "yell",
            "sleep",
            "come",
            "laugh",
            "talk"
          ],
          "word": "HOLLER",
          "correct": "yell"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Will he PARTICIPATE?",
          "answers": [
            "lose",
            "be friendly",
            "leave",
            "take part",
            "be eager"
          ],
          "word": "PARTICIPATE",
          "correct": "take part"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RAPID workers.",
          "answers": [
            "angry",
            "good",
            "fast",
            "slow",
            "smart"
          ],
          "word": "RAPID",
          "correct": "fast"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REFUND the money.",
          "answers": [
            "spend",
            "turn down",
            "give away",
            "earn",
            "pay back"
          ],
          "word": "REFUND",
          "correct": "pay back"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Satisfactory RESPONSE.",
          "answers": [
            "pay",
            "ending",
            "beginning",
            "answer",
            "report"
          ],
          "word": "RESPONSE",
          "correct": "answer"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SCORCHED it.",
          "answers": [
            "burned",
            "soaked",
            "tried",
            "cut",
            "dried"
          ],
          "word": "SCORCH",
          "correct": "burned"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do other things besides food DECAY?",
          "word": "DECAY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people like to be MISERABLE?",
          "word": "MISERABLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do the leaves of trees TREMBLE when the wind blows through them?",
          "word": "TREMBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an Olympic gold medal a TROPHY?",
          "word": "TROPHY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are governors ELECTED?",
          "word": "ELECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are some people TERRIFIED of the dark?",
          "word": "TERRIFY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are all TERRITORIES the same size?",
          "word": "TERRITORY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If you take frozen food out of the freezer, will it THAW?",
          "word": "THAW",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually say \"Hello\" when they DEPART?",
          "word": "DEPART",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually HOLLER in the library?",
          "word": "HOLLER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are people who are watching a baseball game PARTICIPATING in it?",
          "word": "PARTICIPATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is someone who learns a language in a few months a RAPID learner?",
          "word": "RAPID",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a store usually REFUND your money if you returned an item that you had broken?",
          "word": "REFUND",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a wink be a RESPONSE?",
          "word": "RESPONSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a piece of paper be SCORCHED?",
          "word": "SCORCH",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "She DECAYED it until it was all used up.",
          "word": "DECAY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I'm sorry I hurt you; I didn't mean to make you MISERABLE.",
          "word": "MISERABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She TREMBLED the cup of coffee onto the floor.",
          "word": "TREMBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Each year the winning team receives a large TROPHY.",
          "word": "TROPHY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They gave us a choice, so we ELECTED to stay here.",
          "word": "ELECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The news that there was no school today filled us all with TERROR.",
          "word": "TERRIFY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The explorers came upon a TERRITORY they had never heard of before.",
          "word": "TERRITORY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When the temperature dropped below zero, everything began to THAW.",
          "word": "THAW",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Their DEPARTURE was a sad event for those of us who stayed behind.",
          "word": "DEPART",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She HOLLERED for help when she saw the monster.",
          "word": "HOLLER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They wanted the whole school to PARTICIPATE in selecting a nickname for the team.",
          "word": "PARTICIPATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He became very RAPID whenever anyone disagreed with him.",
          "word": "RAPID",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If you mail in this coupon, we will send you a fifty-cent REFUND.",
          "word": "REFUND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We had to wait three weeks for a RESPONSE to our request for a new telephone.",
          "word": "RESPONSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They SCORCHED the sink so that it would be completely clean.",
          "word": "SCORCH",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "DECAY",
          "answers": [
            "spoil",
            "rot",
            "wait"
          ],
          "word": "DECAY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MISERABLE",
          "answers": [
            "short",
            "lonely",
            "sad"
          ],
          "word": "MISERABLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TREMBLE",
          "answers": [
            "fear",
            "shake",
            "eat"
          ],
          "word": "TREMBLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TROPHY",
          "answers": [
            "award",
            "medal",
            "name"
          ],
          "word": "TROPHY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ELECT",
          "answers": [
            "write",
            "vote",
            "pick"
          ],
          "word": "ELECT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TERRIFY",
          "answers": [
            "frighten",
            "anger",
            "scare"
          ],
          "word": "TERRIFY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TERRITORY",
          "answers": [
            "rock",
            "district",
            "land"
          ],
          "word": "TERRITORY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "THAW",
          "answers": [
            "heat",
            "harden",
            "melt"
          ],
          "word": "THAW",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEPART",
          "answers": [
            "go",
            "leave",
            "run"
          ],
          "word": "DEPART",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HOLLER",
          "answers": [
            "shout",
            "scream",
            "laugh"
          ],
          "word": "HOLLER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PARTICIPATE",
          "answers": [
            "know",
            "join",
            "share"
          ],
          "word": "PARTICIPATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RAPID",
          "answers": [
            "fast",
            "crawling",
            "swift"
          ],
          "word": "RAPID",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REFUND",
          "answers": [
            "earn",
            "repay",
            "return"
          ],
          "word": "REFUND",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RESPONSE",
          "answers": [
            "letter",
            "time",
            "answer"
          ],
          "word": "RESPONSE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SCORCH",
          "answers": [
            "burn",
            "grow",
            "blister"
          ],
          "word": "SCORCH",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "DECAY": {
        "word": "DECAY",
        "phonetic": "(di-kA')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to rot, spoil, go bad \nDECAY means to _rot_ or _go bad_, to _spoil_. The word usually suggests a slow natural change from a good condition to a worse one. The word can be used about physical changes or about the breakdown of the mind, morals, or the like. \n\"The apples ripened, fell off the tree, and then DECAYED.\" \n\"The stink of the DECAYING garbage was overpowering.\" \n\"His athletic skills had DECAYED from lack of practice.\" \nDECAY is also a noun which means _rot_ or _ruin_. \n\"In that section of town many old houses were abandoned and had fallen into a state of DECAY.\" \n\"He brushed his teeth every day to prevent tooth DECAY.\""
      },
      "MISERABLE": {
        "word": "MISERABLE",
        "phonetic": "(miz'-ÔøΩr-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": " unhappy, wretched, worthless, very uncomfortable \nMISERY is a state of suffering and great unhappiness. \n\"They tried to make her feel better, but no one could relieve her MISERY.\" \nMISERABLE means \"full of MISERY,\" _unhappy_. See _-able_ under Suffixes. \n\"Her cold made her feel MISERABLE.\" \n\"The dog was MISERABLE when its master went away.\" \nMISERABLE can also mean \"causing MISERY,\" _wretched_. \n\"This MISERABLE rainy weather has got to end.\" \n\"They lived in MISERABLE conditions in the slum.\" \nOther forms of the word: MISERY, n."
      },
      "TREMBLE": {
        "word": "TREMBLE",
        "phonetic": "(trem'-bÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to shake, shiver, shudder \nTREMBLE means to _shake_ or _shiver_, because of fear, cold, anger, or even sickness. \n\"He was so angry that his voice TREMBLED when he tried to speak.\" \n\"When he came out of the water, his lips were blue with cold and he TREMBLED all over.\" \n\"The needle TREMBLED slightly and then stopped on zero.\""
      },
      "TROPHY": {
        "word": "TROPHY",
        "phonetic": "(trO'-fE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a prize, award \nA TROPHY is something that is given to a person in memory of a victory or a success. It could be a statue, a medal, a cup, or something similar. \n\"He keeps his bowling TROPHIES in a special cabinet.\" \n\"The TROPHY for the top student is a plaque with his or her name on it.\""
      },
      "ELECT": {
        "word": "ELECT",
        "phonetic": "(i-lekt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to choose, select by vote, decide upon, pick out \nTo ELECT basically means to choose, and is sometimes used in this way: \n\"We ELECTED to go home first.\" \nUsually, though, ELECT means \"to choose among candidates for a political office.\" \n\"When someone is ELECTED president, he is chosen by the voters to be president.\" \n\"Alice was ELECTED class treasurer by fifty-seven votes.\" \nAn ELECTION is an act of choosing. In an ELECTION, voters choose whom they want to be in office. An ELECTIVE course is one which the student may choose to take, as opposed to a course which he is required to take. \nOther forms of the word: ELECTION, n. ELECTIVE, adj."
      },
      "TERRIFY": {
        "word": "TERRIFY",
        "phonetic": "(ter'-ÔøΩfl)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to scare, frighten, fill with fear \nTo TERRIFY someone is to make him extremely scared or frightened, to the point where he almost loses his senses. \"He is TERRIFIED of fire.\" \n\"Don't TERRIFY the child with those foolish ghost stories.\" \nThe noun from TERRIFY is TERROR. TERROR is great fear or horror. \n\"The sound of the bombs falling filled them with TERROR.\" \n\"The king ruled not by kindness, but by TERROR.\" \nOther forms of the word: TERROR, n."
      },
      "TERRITORY": {
        "word": "TERRITORY",
        "phonetic": "{ter'-ÔøΩtor-E)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an area, district, region, land \nA TERRITORY is an area of land belonging to a person or government. Animals also have TERRITORIES, which are the areas they consider theirs, and which they will defend against other animals. \n\"The backyard fence marks the boundary of my cat's TERRITORY.\" \n\"Several tribes held the large TERRITORY in common.\" \nDistricts assigned to traveling salespeople are called TERRITORIES also. \"Mr. Smith's TERRITORY covers all of New York state outside of New York City.\" \nOther forms of the word: TERRITORIAL, adj."
      },
      "THAW": {
        "word": "THAW",
        "phonetic": "(tho)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to melt, become liquid, become unfrozen. \nTHAW means to _melt_, to _become unfrozen_. \n\"It was several weeks before the last of the ice THAWED.\" \n\"I forgot to THAW the meat for supper.\" THAW is often used in a broader sense about feelings that become warmer. \n\"They had been enemies for years, but finally relations between them THAWED.\" \nTHAW is also a noun. \"After the spring THAW the streets were inches deep in water.\""
      },
      "DEPART": {
        "word": "DEPART",
        "phonetic": "{di-pahrt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to go away, leave \nTo DEPART is to go away. \n\"They stayed here for three days and then DEPARTED.\" \n\"Our ship DEPARTS next week.\" \n\"We were having such an enjoyable time at the show that we didn't want to DEPART.\" \n\"We DEPARTED from our usual habit of going to bed early.\" \nThe noun from DEPART is DEPARTURE. \n\"The bad weather delayed the plane's DEPARTURE.\" \nOther forms of the word: DEPARTURE, n."
      },
      "HOLLER": {
        "word": "HOLLER",
        "phonetic": "{hol'-Jr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to yell, shout, cry out \nTo HOLLER is to _shout_, to _make a loud noise_, usually because you are excited, unhappy, or want to get someone's attention. \n\"Sally HOLLERED to her friends across the lake.\" \n\"He HOLLERED for help, but no one came.\" \"He was so afraid that he started to HOLLER when anyone came near him.\" \n\"Don't HOLLER; I can hear you perfectly well.\""
      },
      "PARTICIPATE": {
        "word": "PARTICIPATE",
        "phonetic": "{pahr-tis'-ÔøΩpAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to take part in, share in \nTo PARTICIPATE in something is to _take part_ in it. You can see the word _part_ in PARTICIPATE. \n\"Everyone must PARTICIPATE in the singing.\" \n\"It's hard to play a football game if no one else wants to PARTICIPATE.\" \n\"The teacher asked us to PARTICIPATE in the discussion.\" \nA PARTICIPANT is someone who PARTICIPATES. \n\"All the PARTICIPANTS in the show should be congratulated.\" \nOther forms of the word: PARTICIPANT, n. PARTICIPATION, n. Usage: PARTICIPATE is usually followed by in."
      },
      "RAPID": {
        "word": "RAPID",
        "phonetic": "(rap'-id)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "quick, fast, speedy, swift \nRAPID is another word for _fast_. \n\"We are making RAPID progress toward solving the problem.\" \n\"The student gave RAPID answers to all of the teacher's questions.\" \n\"We walked RAPIDLY along the dark street.\" \nThe noun from RAPID is RAPIDITY. \n\"Their RAPIDITY makes it hard for us to keep up with them.\" \n\"We were amazed at the RAPIDITY with which she solved the problem.\" \nOther forms of the word: RAPIDITY, n."
      },
      "REFUND": {
        "word": "REFUND",
        "phonetic": "(ri-fuhnd')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to pay back, repay, give back \nREFUND means to _pay back_. See _re-_ under Prefixes. It is usually used when speaking of money. \n\"If you are not fully satisfied with our product, we will cheerfully REFUND your money.\" \n\"He paid them too much, so they REFUNDED the extra amount to him.\" \nREFUND is also a noun, meaning a repayment. \n\"She paid too much in taxes to the government, so they sent her a REFUND.\" \nWhen used as a noun, the word is pronounced rE'-fuhnd."
      },
      "RESPONSE": {
        "word": "RESPONSE",
        "phonetic": "(ri-spons')",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an answer, reply \nTo RESPOND to something is to say something in return, to _answer_. \n\"When asked about her health, she RESPONDED that she had never felt better.\" \nRESPONSE is the noun from RESPOND. A RESPONSE is an _answer_, a _reply_. \n\"When the teacher asked who had thrown the pencil, there was no RESPONSE.\" \n\"I asked him if he would go, and his RESPONSE was that it would depend on the weather.\" \nA RESPONSE doesn't have to be spoken. \n\"When they asked him a rude question, his RESPONSE was to slam the door in their faces.\" \nOther forms of the word: RESPOND, v."
      },
      "SCORCH": {
        "word": "SCORCH",
        "phonetic": "(skorch)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to burn slightly To SCORCH something is to burn it slightly, usually just on the surface. Often something that has been SCORCHED turns brown or dries up. \n\"The leaves were SCORCHED by the hot sun.\" \n\"He SCORCHED his shirt when he tried to iron it.\" \n\"The meat was SCORCHED when she left it in the oven for too long.\" \nOther forms of the word: SCORCHING, adj."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "1.2",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "ACCOMPANY him.",
          "answers": [
            "work for",
            "leave",
            "go with",
            "meet",
            "deal with"
          ],
          "word": "ACCOMPANY",
          "correct": "go with"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PERMIT him to go.",
          "answers": [
            "ask",
            "remind",
            "order",
            "allow",
            "want"
          ],
          "word": "PERMIT",
          "correct": "allow"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Eager to GREET him.",
          "answers": [
            "welcome",
            "hurt",
            "know",
            "speak to",
            "leave"
          ],
          "word": "GREET",
          "correct": "welcome"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COUNTERFEIT bills.",
          "answers": [
            "real",
            "fake",
            "smaller",
            "foreign",
            "useless"
          ],
          "word": "COUNTERFEIT",
          "correct": "fake"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To DISCUSS their parents.",
          "answers": [
            "think about",
            "shame",
            "write to",
            "talk about",
            "speak to"
          ],
          "word": "DISCUSS",
          "correct": "talk about"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISCARD the clothing.",
          "answers": [
            "ignore",
            "dislike",
            "lose",
            "throwaway",
            "find"
          ],
          "word": "DISCARD",
          "correct": "throw away"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Another ACHE.",
          "answers": [
            "pain",
            "memory",
            "feeling",
            "idea",
            "problem"
          ],
          "word": "ACHE",
          "correct": "pain"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We shall OVERCOME them.",
          "answers": [
            "support",
            "love",
            "visit",
            "lead",
            "defeat"
          ],
          "word": "OVERCOME",
          "correct": "defeat"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Began to QUIVER.",
          "answers": [
            "freeze",
            "choke",
            "shake",
            "fall",
            "spin"
          ],
          "word": "QUIVER",
          "correct": "shake"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Not enough NOURISHMENT.",
          "answers": [
            "praise",
            "weight",
            "food",
            "exercise",
            "love"
          ],
          "word": "NOURISHMENT",
          "correct": "food"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COURAGEOUS action.",
          "answers": [
            "unbelievable",
            "polite",
            "generous",
            "brave",
            "cowardly"
          ],
          "word": "COURAGEOUS",
          "correct": "brave"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ANNUAL events.",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "yearly",
            "weekly",
            "unusual",
            "monthly"
          ],
          "word": "ANNUAL",
          "correct": "yearly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Approached the LOBBY.",
          "answers": [
            "entrance hall",
            "hotel",
            "doctor's office",
            "elevator",
            "top floor"
          ],
          "word": "LOBBY",
          "correct": "entrance hall"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Wanted to CONTRIBUTE.",
          "answers": [
            "give",
            "steal",
            "join",
            "praise",
            "work"
          ],
          "word": "CONTRIBUTE",
          "correct": "give"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Noticed the SMUDGE.",
          "answers": [
            "dirty mark",
            "hard candy",
            "freckle",
            "soap",
            "swamp"
          ],
          "word": "SMUDGE",
          "correct": "dirty mark"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Does pain usually ACCOMPANY an injury?",
          "word": "ACCOMPANY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do banks give people PERMISSION to rob them?",
          "word": "PERMIT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you GREET people when they leave?",
          "word": "GREET",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people like COUNTERFEIT money for their pay?",
          "word": "COUNTERFEIT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people DISCUSS things they keep secret?",
          "word": "DISCUSS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people like to DISCARD money?",
          "word": "DISCARD",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it fun to have an ACHE?",
          "word": "ACHE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it hard to OVERCOME a powerful enemy?",
          "word": "OVERCOME",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a leaf QUIVER?",
          "word": "QUIVER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people need NOURISHMENT?",
          "word": "NOURISHMENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a person who tries to save people trapped in a burning building be called COURAGEOUS?",
          "word": "COURAGEOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is Washington's Birthday an ANNUAL holiday?",
          "word": "ANNUAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people often live in LOBBIES?",
          "word": "LOBBY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most churches accept CONTRIBUTIONS?",
          "word": "CONTRIBUTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": " Is a SMUDGE usually beautiful?",
          "word": "SMUDGE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He hated people, so he always found someone to ACCOMPANY him.",
          "word": "ACCOMPANY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "David wasn't PERMITTED to leave his room until he said he was sorry.",
          "word": "PERMIT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Susan GREETED us with a warm smile.",
          "word": "GREET",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I could see at a glance that the stamp was a COUNTERFEIT.",
          "word": "COUNTERFEIT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "No one listened to our DISCUSSION of Egyptian mummies.",
          "word": "DISCUSS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Instead of DISCARDING the old furniture he fixed it up and sold it.",
          "word": "DISCARD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The flu made Jane ACHE all over.",
          "word": "ACHE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We OVERCAME and stayed a few nights at our friend's house.",
          "word": "OVERCOME",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The force of the car crash made the telephone pole QUIVER.",
          "word": "QUIVER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He ran away after he broke the window because he was afraid to be NOURISHED.",
          "word": "NOURISHMENT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was COURAGEOUS of him to run away when the other children were in trouble.",
          "word": "COURAGEOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She takes her ANNUAL vacation the first two weeks in August.",
          "word": "ANNUAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He stood in the LOBBY trying to decide which elevator to take.",
          "word": "LOBBY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bill CONTRIBUTED his lack of success to bad luck.",
          "word": "CONTRIBUTE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "By the time she finished eating, her lipstick was all SMUDGED.",
          "word": "SMUDGE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "ACCOMPANY",
          "answers": [
            "stay with",
            "go with",
            "go toward"
          ],
          "word": "ACCOMPANY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PERMIT",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "let",
            "help"
          ],
          "word": "PERMIT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GREET",
          "answers": [
            "find",
            "welcome",
            "meet"
          ],
          "word": "GREET",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COUNTERFEIT",
          "answers": [
            "broken",
            "worthless",
            "false"
          ],
          "word": "COUNTERFEIT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISCUSS",
          "answers": [
            "talk",
            "argue",
            "laugh"
          ],
          "word": "DISCUSS",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISCARD",
          "answers": [
            "throw away",
            "go away",
            "give away"
          ],
          "word": "DISCARD",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ACHE",
          "answers": [
            "sickness",
            "injury",
            "hatred"
          ],
          "word": "ACHE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OVERCOME",
          "answers": [
            "disagree",
            "weaken",
            "beat"
          ],
          "word": "OVERCOME",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "QUIVER",
          "answers": [
            "drop",
            "swing",
            "tremble"
          ],
          "word": "QUIVER",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NOURISHMENT",
          "answers": [
            "food",
            "time",
            "help"
          ],
          "word": "NOURISHMENT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COURAGEOUS",
          "answers": [
            "brave",
            "daring",
            "successful"
          ],
          "word": "COURAGEOUS",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ANNUAL",
          "answers": [
            "yearly",
            "regular",
            "unusual"
          ],
          "word": "ANNUAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LOBBY",
          "answers": [
            "hall",
            "waiting room",
            "doorway"
          ],
          "word": "LOBBY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONTRIBUTE",
          "answers": [
            "give",
            "help",
            "sell"
          ],
          "word": "CONTRIBUTE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SMUDGE",
          "answers": [
            "blur",
            "aging",
            "dirt"
          ],
          "word": "SMUDGE",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "ACCOMPANY": {
        "word": "ACCOMPANY",
        "phonetic": "(a-kuhm'-pa-nE)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to go with, be with \nYou can see the word _company_ in ACCOMPANY. To ACCOMPANY someone is to be _in company_ with him, to go along with him. \n\"We will ACCOMPANY him as far as the bus stop.\" \n\"The president arrived, ACCOMPANIED by several Secret Service men.\" \n\"High winds ACCOMPANIED the snowstorm.\" \nACCOMPANY is often used in the field of music. \n\"The singer will be ACCOMPANIED by a pianist.\""
      },
      "PERMIT": {
        "word": "PERMIT",
        "phonetic": "(pronounced",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to allow, authorize, make possible \nTo PERMIT something is to allow it, to give your consent to it. \n\"Her father PERMITTED her to go to the dance.\" \n\"Smoking is not PERMITTED inside the building.\" The noun from PERMIT is PERMISSION, which is the act of allowing. \n\"She was given PERMISSION to speak to the class.\" \n\"The airport denied the plane PERMISSION to land.\" \nPERMIT (pronounced PER-mit) is also a noun, meaning PERMISSION, especially PERMISSION in written form such as a certificate or license, which allows someone to do something. \n\"The school parking PERMIT was pasted on his car's windshield.\" \nOther forms of the word: PERMISSION, n. \nPERMISSIVE, adj. \nPERMISSIBLE, adj."
      },
      "GREET": {
        "word": "GREET",
        "phonetic": "(grEt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to welcome, meet \nTo GREET someone is to welcome him, to say hello to him in a friendly way. \n\"We all went over to GREET the new neighbors.\" \n\"Is that any way to GREET an old friend?\" \nGREET can also mean to _meet_ or _receive_. \n\"The play was GREETED with polite applause.\" \n\"They GREETED his speech with boos and hisses.\" \nA GREETING is the act or words that you use to GREET someone. \n\"He received a warm GREETING when he arrived home.\" \nOther forms of the word: GREETING, n."
      },
      "COUNTERFEIT": {
        "word": "COUNTERFEIT",
        "phonetic": "(kown'-t:>r-fit)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "fake, phony, not genuine \nCOUNTERFEIT can be an adjective, a noun, or a verb. As an adjective, COUNTERFEIT means _fake_ or _phony_. \n\"They tried to spend the COUNTERFEIT money as if it were real.\" \n\"She was caught with the COUNTERFEIT dollar bills in her possession.\" \nA COUNTERFEIT (noun) is a copy or imitation which someone pretends is the real thing, usually in order to cheat a person. \n\"The expert said the supposedly priceless painting was a COUNTERFEIT and actually wasn't worth anything.\" \nFinally, COUNTERFEIT is a verb meaning to fake or pretend. \n\"Jane COUNTERFEITED great joy at the gift of the pocketbook. She really thought it was ugly.\" \nMany people choose _useless_ as the meaning of COUNTERFEIT. COUNTERFEIT money may be useless, but the basic meaning is _fake_, _not genuine_."
      },
      "DISCUSS": {
        "word": "DISCUSS",
        "phonetic": "(dis-kuhs')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to talk about, talk over \nTo DISCUSS something is to talk about it, to exchange opinions about it. \n\"We DISCUSSED where the picture should be hung.\" \n\"The teacher DISCUSSED the meanings of various words.\" \n\"I want to DISCUSS your behavior with you.\" \n\"It's hard to DISCUSS anything with Tim. He just gets excited and starts yelling.\" \nThe noun from DISCUSS is DISCUSSION. \n\"We had a long DISCUSSION about how to do the job.\" \nOther forms of the word: DISCUSSION, n."
      },
      "DISCARD": {
        "word": "DISCARD",
        "phonetic": "(dis-kahrd')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to throw away, get rid of \nSee _dis-_ under Prefixes. DISCARD means to _throw away_. The word was first used only about throwing away cards that weren't useful in games like poker or gin rummy. \n\"He picked up the queen of spades and DISCARDED the two of clubs.\" \nNow DISCARD is used to indicate throwing away anything that isn't useful. \n\"Sheila DISCARDED some old, broken toys.\" \n\"I wanted to DISCARD the book, but since he said it might be valuable, I kept it.\""
      },
      "ACHE": {
        "word": "ACHE",
        "phonetic": "(Ak)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a dull pain \nAn ACHE is a dull, steady pain. \n\"Jane felt an ACHE in her legs after she had been running for an hour.\" \n\"Cold, wet weather always caused an ACHE in his injured knee.\" \nACHE is also a verb, meaning \"to feel a dull steady pain.\" \n\"His head ACHED from all the noise in the room.\" \nACHE is often used in the sense \"to long for something so much that it is almost painful.\" \n\"She ACHED to see him one last time before she left.\""
      },
      "OVERCOME": {
        "word": "OVERCOME",
        "phonetic": "(O-vÔøΩr-kuhm')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to defeat, surmount, conquer \nTo OVERCOME something is to get the better of it. You can OVERCOME a person, a feeling, or a thing. \n\"It may take years, but we will OVERCOME the enemy.\" \"He OVERCAME the urge to smoke a cigarette.\" \nTo be OVERCOME _by_ or _with_ something is to be weakened or overpowered by it. \n\"She was OVERCOME with sadness when she remembered what he had said.\" \n\"They were OVERCOME by the gas fumes escaping from the car.\""
      },
      "QUIVER": {
        "word": "QUIVER",
        "phonetic": "(kw1v'-ÔøΩ)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to shake, tremble \nTo QUIVER is to shake or tremble slightly. It is more often used about things than about people. \n\"The needle QUIVERED for a while, then stopped on zero.\" \n\"The arrow QUIVERED in the target.\" \n\"The animal QUIVERED with fear as the men approached.\" \nIn the Pretest, many people choose _freeze_ as the meaning of QUIVER, probably because QUIVER looks like _shiver_, and you shiver when its very cold."
      },
      "NOURISHMENT": {
        "word": "NOURISHMENT",
        "phonetic": "(nuhr'-ish-mÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "food, sustenance \nTo NOURISH something is to keep it alive and strong by feeding. \n\"They needed to NOURISH their plants, so they bought some special plant food.\" \nNOURISHMENT is that which supports life and growth; it is food or anything else that NOURISHES. \n\"Even when you are sick and don't feel like eating, you must still take some NOURISHMENT.\" \n\"Just as your body needs food, your mind needs NOURISHMENT too.\" \nOther forms of the word: NOURISH, v."
      },
      "COURAGEOUS": {
        "word": "COURAGEOUS",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩrA'-jÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "having COURAGE, brave, fearless COURAGEOUS comes from the word COURAGE, which means _bravery_. See _-ous_ under Suffixes. COURAGEOUS means _brave_, _fearless_, _having courage_. \n\"It was very COURAGEOUS of him to stand up for what he felt was right in the face of the others' disapproval.\" \n\"Her COURAGEOUS attempt to swim the English Channel was unsuccessful.\" \n\"COURAGEOUS people do not run and hide when things become dangerous.\" \nOther forms of the word: COURAGE, n."
      },
      "ANNUAL": {
        "word": "ANNUAL",
        "phonetic": "(an'-yU-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "yearly ANNUAL means \"coming or happening every year.\" \n\"We will put on our seventh ANNUAL flower show this spring.\" \n\"The party was so successful we decided to make it an ANNUAL event.\" \n\"His ANNUAL income went up ten percent last year.\""
      },
      "LOBBY": {
        "word": "LOBBY",
        "phonetic": "(lob'-E)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an entrance hall, waiting room \nA LOBBY is a hall, room, or corridor that is used as an entrance or waiting area. \n\"He sat and waited in the LOBBY of the hotel until his friends came downstairs.\" \nThe LOBBIES of places like the Senate or the House of Representatives were where members of Congress would meet with the public. A LOBBY has therefore also come to mean a group of people who attempt to influence lawmakers to vote in a certain way. \n\"The shipping industry LOBBY spent a great deal of money trying to get this bill passed.\" \nA LOBBYIST is someone who attempts to influence lawmakers in this way. Other forms of the word: LOBBYIST, n."
      },
      "CONTRIBUTE": {
        "word": "CONTRIBUTE",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-trib'-yUt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to give, donate CONTRIBUTE has two related meanings. First, CONTRIBUTE means \"to give along with others.\" The word is usually used about giving money to a charity, but it can be used about giving other things as well. \n\"She CONTRIBUTED several good ideas to the project.\" \n\"If everyone CONTRIBUTES a few hours of his time the house will be painted very quickly.\" \nCONTRIBUTE can also mean \"to help bring about.\" \n\"Extreme tiredness CONTRIBUTED to his coming down with a very bad cold.\" \n\"A good education CONTRIBUTED to his success in politics.\" \nA CONTRIBUTION, the noun from CONTRIBUTE, is a gift. \n\"She has made many CONTRIBUTIONS to charity in the past year.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONTRIBUTION, n."
      },
      "SMUDGE": {
        "word": "SMUDGE",
        "phonetic": "(smuhj)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a dirty mark, smear, dirt \nA SMUDGE is a blurred, streaky mark, the kind that is made when a bit of dirt is rubbed, or when something is incompletely erased. \n\"There were SMUDGES on the window where the child had put his greasy fingers.\" \n\"The paper was covered with SMUDGES after she had finished erasing all her mistakes.\" \nSMUDGE is also a verb. \n\"He SMUDGED the paper even more when he tried to clean it up.\" \n\"She SMUDGED her cheek when she rubbed it with her dirty hand.\""
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "1.3",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He IMITATES my work.",
          "answers": [
            "looks at",
            "destroys",
            "laughs at",
            "copies",
            "uses"
          ],
          "word": "IMITATE",
          "correct": "copies"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Make them SQUIRM.",
          "answers": [
            "cry",
            "beg",
            "twist about",
            "jump",
            "straighten up"
          ],
          "word": "SQUIRM",
          "correct": "twist about"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Extremely SOCIABLE.",
          "answers": [
            "quiet",
            "friendly",
            "funny",
            "kind",
            "political"
          ],
          "word": "SOCIABLE",
          "correct": "friendly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ACHIEVE recognition.",
          "answers": [
            "gain",
            "lose",
            "hate",
            "hope for",
            "demand"
          ],
          "word": "ACHIEVE",
          "correct": "gain"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "You RESEMBLE him.",
          "answers": [
            "hate",
            "lie to",
            "meet",
            "are like",
            "live near"
          ],
          "word": "RESEMBLE",
          "correct": "are like"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Need some SHELTER.",
          "answers": [
            "heat",
            "rest",
            "protection",
            "excitement",
            "advice"
          ],
          "word": "SHELTER",
          "correct": "protection"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He GRASPED the plate.",
          "answers": [
            "dropped",
            "threw",
            "stole",
            "took hold of",
            "breathed onto"
          ],
          "word": "GRASP",
          "correct": "took hold of"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We mustn't STUMBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "run",
            "jump",
            "complain",
            "trip",
            "stop"
          ],
          "word": "STUMBLE",
          "correct": "trip"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHATTER the window.",
          "answers": [
            "break",
            "darken",
            "drop",
            "close",
            "fix"
          ],
          "word": "SHATTER",
          "correct": "break"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Why must we STOOP?",
          "answers": [
            "stand up",
            "lose",
            "change",
            "dig",
            "bend down"
          ],
          "word": "STOOP",
          "correct": "bend down"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Everyone seemed so DOWNCAST.",
          "answers": [
            "tired",
            "depressed",
            "uncomfortable",
            "hopeful",
            "steady"
          ],
          "word": "DOWNCAST",
          "correct": "depressed"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Began to SPROUT.",
          "answers": [
            "spring up",
            "flow",
            "ripen",
            "slide",
            "fall off"
          ],
          "word": "SPROUT",
          "correct": "spring up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They APPROACHED the top.",
          "answers": [
            "found",
            "hit",
            "neared",
            "left",
            "missed"
          ],
          "word": "APPROACH",
          "correct": "neared"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECOVER the money.",
          "answers": [
            "steal",
            "keep",
            "look for",
            "beg for",
            "get back"
          ],
          "word": "RECOVER",
          "correct": "get back"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ABBREVIATE it.",
          "answers": [
            "change",
            "quicken",
            "spell",
            "shorten",
            "lengthen"
          ],
          "word": "ABBREVIATE",
          "correct": "shorten"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Can a parrot IMITATE the sound of human speech?",
          "word": "IMITATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a baby SQUIRM if he didn't want to be held?",
          "word": "SQUIRM",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a person who is always looking for a fight very SOCIABLE?",
          "word": "SOCIABLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most students ACHIEVE perfect grades on all their exams?",
          "word": "ACHIEVE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there any RESEMBLANCE between horses and donkeys?",
          "word": "RESEMBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people need SHELTER during a snowstorm?",
          "word": "SHELTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you GRASP an idea?",
          "word": "GRASP",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a good ice skater STUMBLE a lot?",
          "word": "STUMBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a light bulb SHATTER?",
          "word": "SHATTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are you standing when you STOOP?",
          "word": "STOOP",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a person be DOWNCAST if his best friend moved away?",
          "word": "DOWNCAST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most trees SPROUT leaves in the fall?",
          "word": "SPROUT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you APPROACH something without reaching it?",
          "word": "APPROACH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people RECOVER from a cold?",
          "word": "RECOVER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is Dr. an ABBREVIATION for doctor?",
          "word": "ABBREVIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Mary tried to IMITATE her older sister in everything she did.",
          "word": "IMITATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SQUIRMED with displeasure whenever someone called him by his real name.",
          "word": "SQUIRM",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We chatted SOCIABLY for a while over a cup of tea.",
          "word": "SOCIABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He received several awards for his ACHIEVEMENTS in science.",
          "word": "ACHIEVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The crowd RESEMBLED to welcome the new mayor.",
          "word": "RESEMBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The tree didn't give us enough SHELTER from the rain, so we ran into the house.",
          "word": "SHELTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He GRASPED the end of the rope and pulled it toward him.",
          "word": "GRASP",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The wounded man STUMBLED to the door of the hospital, where he fainted.",
          "word": "STUMBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SHATTERED the boards together with nails so that they wouldn't move.",
          "word": "SHATTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Jane had to really STOOP to jump over the fence.",
          "word": "STOOP",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She looked at them with a DOWNCAST expression and said her parents wouldn't let her go.",
          "word": "DOWNCAST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Several weeds began to SPROUT up in the new lawn.",
          "word": "SPROUT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When they saw the big dog APPROACH them, they ran away as fast as they could.",
          "word": "APPROACH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were not allowed to keep the treasure they RECOVERED from the sunken ship.",
          "word": "RECOVER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Paul ABBREVIATED the rope in half with a knife.",
          "word": "ABBREVIATE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "IMITATE",
          "answers": [
            "create",
            "act like",
            "copy"
          ],
          "word": "IMITATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SQUIRM",
          "answers": [
            "jump",
            "twist",
            "wriggle"
          ],
          "word": "SQUIRM",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SOCIABLE",
          "answers": [
            "friendly",
            "unwelcome",
            "neighborly"
          ],
          "word": "SOCIABLE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ACHIEVE",
          "answers": [
            "get",
            "reach",
            "give"
          ],
          "word": "ACHIEVE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RESEMBLE",
          "answers": [
            "match",
            "compare",
            "differ"
          ],
          "word": "RESEMBLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHELTER",
          "answers": [
            "safety",
            "beauty",
            "warmth"
          ],
          "word": "SHELTER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GRASP",
          "answers": [
            "understand",
            "take",
            "hit"
          ],
          "word": "GRASP",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STUMBLE",
          "answers": [
            "trip",
            "bend",
            "fall"
          ],
          "word": "STUMBLE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHATTER",
          "answers": [
            "explode",
            "break",
            "rot"
          ],
          "word": "SHATTER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STOOP",
          "answers": [
            "bend",
            "spin",
            "sink"
          ],
          "word": "STOOP",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DOWNCAST",
          "answers": [
            "unhappy",
            "miserable",
            "ill"
          ],
          "word": "DOWNCAST",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SPROUT",
          "answers": [
            "bud",
            "grow",
            "decrease"
          ],
          "word": "SPROUT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "APPROACH",
          "answers": [
            "way",
            "chance",
            "path"
          ],
          "word": "APPROACH",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECOVER",
          "answers": [
            "get back",
            "win back",
            "look back"
          ],
          "word": "RECOVER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ABBREVIATE",
          "answers": [
            "age",
            "cut",
            "shorten"
          ],
          "word": "ABBREVIATE",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "IMITATE": {
        "word": "IMITATE",
        "phonetic": "(im'-ÔøΩtAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to copy, follow the example of, try to be like \nTo IMITATE something is to try to be like it, to copy it. You can IMITATE a person or a thing. \n\"He tried to IMITATE the sound of a duck.\" \n\"She wants to IMITATE the figure skaters she sees on television.\" \nAn IMITATION is something that is a copy of something else. \n\"The building is an IMITATION of an ancient Greek temple.\" \n\"He did a funny IMITATION of a man slipping on a banana peel.\" \nOther forms of the word: IMITATION, n."
      },
      "SQUIRM": {
        "word": "SQUIRM",
        "phonetic": "(skwerm)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to twist about, wiggle, wriggle \nTo SQUIRM means \"to twist the body about,\" to _wiggle_ or _wriggle_. \n\"The baby SQUIRMED so much I almost dropped him.\" \n\"He's trying to SQUIRM through the cellar window.\" \nPeople often twist about when they feel uncomfortable or embarrassed, and SQUIRM is also used to express this sense. \n\"Try not to SQUIRM in your chair while I introduce you to my uncle.\""
      },
      "SOCIABLE": {
        "word": "SOCIABLE",
        "phonetic": "(s0'-shÔøΩb:)I)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "friendly, liking company, companionable \nSOCIABLE means \"liking the company of other people,\" _friendly_. A SOCIABLE person just naturally likes to be with other people, even if they are strangers. \n\"They are a SOCIABLE couple, always inviting friends over.\" \n\"We played a SOCIABLE game of poker.\" \n\"We always enjoy the company of SOCIABLE people.\" \nSOCIABLE is the opposite of hostile or unfriendly. You cannot, for example, have a SOCIABLE fight."
      },
      "ACHIEVE": {
        "word": "ACHIEVE",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩchEv')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to gain, accomplish, get \nACHIEVE means to gain or to get, often with some degree of difficulty. \n\"He ACHIEVED his goal of learning to walk again after he had been crippled.\" \n\"She realized that it was necessary to study to ACHIEVE an A in math.\" \n\"Most of us have to work hard to ACHIEVE any success.\" \nThe noun from ACHIEVE is ACHIEVEMENT, which means an accomplishment. \n\"His greatest ACHIEVEMENT was to score the winning touchdown.\" \n\"She is not content to get by on her previous ACHIEVEMENTS, but is always looking for new fields to conquer.\" \nOther forms of the word: ACHIEVEMENT, n."
      },
      "RESEMBLE": {
        "word": "RESEMBLE",
        "phonetic": "(ri-zem'-b:)I)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to be like, look like, act like \nRESEMBLE means \"to be like or look like\" somebody or something. \n\"She RESEMBLES her mother, particularly around the eyes.\" \n\"The twins don't RESEMBLE each other at all.\" \n\"The son RESEMBLES his father in his patience and good humor.\" \nThe noun from RESEMBLE is RESEMBLANCE. \n\"The RESEMBLANCE between distant relatives is often remarkable.\" \nOther forms of the word: RESEMBLANCE, n."
      },
      "SHELTER": {
        "word": "SHELTER",
        "phonetic": "(shel'-t:)r)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "protection, safety \nSHELTER is used in two senses. First, it is a building or place that gives protection. \n\"After half an hour they reached the ski SHELTER.\" \n\"We stood in the bus SHELTER to keep out of the strong wind.\" \nSecond, SHELTER means protection itself. \n\"We tried to find SHELTER from the heavy rain.\" \n\"The family sought SHELTER in their basement from the bombs.\" \nSHELTER is also used as a verb and means to protect. \n\"The doorway of the building SHELTERED us from the storm.\" \n\"The beach umbrella SHELTERS us from the burning sun.\""
      },
      "GRASP": {
        "word": "GRASP",
        "phonetic": "(grasp)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to take, take hold of, seize, clutch; to understand, comprehend To GRASP something is to take hold of it. \n\"He GRASPED the handlebars of his bicycle.\" \n\"She GRASPED the cup firmly with both hands so that it wouldn't fall.\" GRASP is also used to mean \"to take hold of mentally,\" to _understand_. \n\"I fail to GRASP how your plan will help us.\" \n\"It took a lot of explaining, but finally Jim seemed to GRASP the idea.\""
      },
      "STUMBLE": {
        "word": "STUMBLE",
        "phonetic": "(stuhm'-bÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to trip, walk unsteadily, make a mistake \nTo STUMBLE is to trip and almost fall, often as the result of hitting something that is in your way. \n\"The hidden wire caused him to STUMBLE, but he managed to stay on his feet.\" \nTo STUMBLE is also to walk along unsteadily, to stagger, as if you were about to fall at any second. \n\"The drunk STUMBLED along, barely able to stand up.\" \nIn general use the word can also mean \"to speak or act clumsily,\" to blunder or founder. \n\"Johnny STUMBLED over every word as he tried to read the sentence.\" \n\"We didn't know anything about it, so we just STUMBLED along, doing the best we could.\""
      },
      "SHATTER": {
        "word": "SHATTER",
        "phonetic": "(shat'-ÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to break SHATTER means \"to break into small pieces.\" \nSHATTER is used in connection with glass or anything like glass that breaks easily. \n\"The bottle rolled off the table and SHATTERED on the floor.\" \n\"The windshield SHATTERED when the car hit the tree.\" \nSHATTER can be used in a broader sense about health, hopes, dreams, nerves, and the like. \n\"His nerves were SHATTERED by the terrible battle.\""
      },
      "STOOP": {
        "word": "STOOP",
        "phonetic": "(stUp)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to bend down, bow down, lower oneself \nTo STOOP is to bend down from the waist. \n\"Jim STOOPED over to pick up a dime on the floor.\" \n\"He STOOPED so that he wouldn't hit his head on the pipe.\" \nFrom this physical sense STOOP has come to mean \"to do something that is beneath you\" in terms of either rank or morals. \n\"How could you STOOP to telling such an awful lie?\" \n\"Why did the famous actor STOOP to doing television commercials?\""
      },
      "DOWNCAST": {
        "word": "DOWNCAST",
        "phonetic": "(down'-kast)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "depressed, sad, discouraged \nThe word cast in DOWNCAST means _throw_, and DOWNCAST was originally a verb which meant to _throw down_ or _overthrow_. Now DOWNCAST is only used as an adjective to describe spirits or looks that are \"thrown down\" because something sad has happened. \n\"We tried to cheer him up because he seemed DOWNCAST.\" \n\"You look so DOWNCAST. What's wrong?\" \n\"Bobby has a right to be DOWNCAST. His fumble cost us the game.\" \n\"Almost everyone feels DOWNCAST on a gray, gloomy day.\""
      },
      "SPROUT": {
        "word": "SPROUT",
        "phonetic": "(sprowt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to spring up, begin to grow, send out leaves or buds \nTo SPROUT means to _spring up_, to _begin to grow_. SPROUT is most often used about plants or other growing things, but it has also come to be used about anything that grows suddenly or quickly. \n\"Because of the sudden increase in population, new towns SPROUTED up almost overnight.\" \n\"When he was fourteen his beard began to SPROUT.\" \nSPROUT can also mean \"to cause to grow, to send out new leaves.\" \n\"The tree SPROUTED new buds in the spring.\" \nUsage: SPROUT is often followed by _up_."
      },
      "APPROACH": {
        "word": "APPROACH",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩprOch')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to near, come near \nAPPROACH means to _come near_ or _get near_. \n\"We all felt relieved as we watched him APPROACH us without tripping.\" \n\"What is the right way to APPROACH the king's throne?\" \n\"She was APPROACHING the age to leave home.\" \nAPPROACH is also a noun that means a _road_ or _way_ to something. When APPROACH is used to mean _way_, it can be used in either the sense of a _path_ or a _method_. \n\"We'll have to use another APPROACH (method) to get him to agree.\" \n\"The APPROACH (path) to the highway was blocked by snow.\""
      },
      "RECOVER": {
        "word": "RECOVER",
        "phonetic": "(ri-kuhv'-ÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to get back; to become well \nTo RECOVER something is to get or win it back. See _re-_ under Prefixes. \n\"She RECOVERED the ring she had lost.\" \n\"They RECOVERED his shoe from the bottom of the pond.\" \n\"You'll never RECOVER all the money you have wasted.\" \nWhen a person RECOVERS _from_ something, he gets better, becomes well. \n\"He RECOVERED from the sickness.\" \n\"She is fully RECOVERED from her accident.\" \nRECOVERY (the noun) is the act of getting back or getting better. \n\"He was pleased by the quick RECOVERY of his lost wallet.\" \n\"Her RECOVERY from the illness will take many months.\" \nOther forms of the word: RECOVERY, n."
      },
      "ABBREVIATE": {
        "word": "ABBREVIATE",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩbrE'-vE-At)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to shorten \nTo ABBREVIATE something is to make it shorter by leaving out parts. The word is used particularly when talking about the shortening of words and phrases. \n\"The words 'United States of America' are ABBREVIATED to \"USA\". \n\"His name was Albert, but he ABBREVIATED it to Al in order to save space.\" \nABBREVIATE can be used about other things as well. \n\"The mayor's speech had to be ABBREVIATED because we ran out of time.\" \nThe noun from ABBREVIATE is ABBREVIATION. \n\"Mr. is the ABBREVIATION for Mister.\" \nOther forms of the word: ABBREVIATION, n."
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "ABBREVIATE",
        "DEPART",
        "OVERCOME",
        "RESEMBLE",
        "STOOP",
        "ANNUAL",
        "DOWNCAST",
        "PARTICIPATE",
        "RESPONSE",
        "TERRIFY",
        "APPROACH",
        "ELECT",
        "QUIVER",
        "SHATTER",
        "TERRITORY",
        "CONTRIBUTE",
        "GREET",
        "RAPID",
        "SMUDGE",
        "TROPHY",
        "COURAGEOUS",
        "IMITATE",
        "ACCOMPANY",
        "DISCARD",
        "MISERABLE",
        "SCORCH",
        "SQUIRM",
        "ACHE",
        "DISCUSS",
        "NOURISHMENT",
        "SHELTER",
        "STUMBLE",
        "ACHIEVE",
        "GRASP",
        "PERMIT",
        "SOCIABLE",
        "THAW",
        "COUNTERFEIT",
        "HOLLER",
        "RECOVER",
        "SPROUT",
        "TREMBLE",
        "DECAY",
        "LOBBY",
        "REFUND"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "His hand",
          "part2": "with nervousness as he tried to put the key in the lock.",
          "answer": "quivered"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The dirty eraser made all kinds of",
          "part2": "on the clean paper.",
          "answer": "smudges"
        },
        {
          "part1": "When it was time to",
          "part2": "we got in the car and drove away.",
          "answer": "depart"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Everyone ran away when they heard the baseball",
          "part2": "the window.",
          "answer": "shatter"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He",
          "part2": "his father; they both have the same way of talking and laughing.",
          "answer": "resembles"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She decided to",
          "part2": "the problem in a different way, and started all over again.",
          "answer": "approach"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The voters",
          "part2": "Franklin D. Roosevelt president four times.",
          "answer": "elected"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Our",
          "part2": "picnic is held every June 1st regardless of the weather.",
          "answer": "annual"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The thought of jumping off that bridge",
          "part2": "me; I don't think I can do it.",
          "answer": "terrifies"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He tried to",
          "part2": "his habit of biting his nails, but it wasn't easy.",
          "answer": "overcome"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Everyone tries to",
          "part2": "his style of writing, but no one can do it as well as he can.",
          "answer": "imitate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The rich man",
          "part2": "a large sum of money to the school for a new gymnasium.",
          "answer": "contributed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The doctor told Johnny he couldn't",
          "part2": "in any sport that involved jumping.",
          "answer": "participate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Jim won so many",
          "part2": "for his running ability that he had to have a special case to hold them all.",
          "answer": "trophies"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Jill was,",
          "part2": "all day until her sister came and cheered her up.",
          "answer": "downcast"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The basketball player always had to",
          "part2": "going through a doorway.",
          "answer": "stoop"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His only",
          "part2": "to their questions was a silent shake of his head.",
          "answer": "response"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He",
          "part2": "us at the door with a handshake.",
          "answer": "greeted"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He",
          "part2": "\"Massachusetts\" to \"MA\" in addressing the letter.",
          "answer": "abbreviated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The general praised the",
          "part2": "soldier for holding off the enemy by himself while the rest of the troops retreated.",
          "answer": "courageous"
        },
        {
          "part1": "That certainly was a(n)",
          "part2": "time for the race; it was over in less than ten seconds.",
          "answer": "rapid"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His sales",
          "part2": "covered four New England states.",
          "answer": "territory"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The doctor said he wasn't getting enough",
          "part2": "and should eat better food.",
          "answer": "nourishment"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The baby",
          "part2": "the pencil and wouldn't let go.",
          "answer": "grasped"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She",
          "part2": "her old dishes when she bought a new set.",
          "answer": "discarded"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The",
          "part2": "was so crowded it seemed as though everyone was trying to check out of the hotel at the same time.",
          "answer": "lobby"
        },
        {
          "part1": "After a few warm days in April our plants began to",
          "part2": "tiny buds.",
          "answer": "sprout"
        },
        {
          "part1": "In late spring the frozen river finally",
          "part2": "and started to flow again.",
          "answer": "thawed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It only took Jim a couple of days to",
          "part2": "from his cold.",
          "answer": "recover"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We will",
          "part2": "you to come with us only if you keep quiet.",
          "answer": "permit"
        },
        {
          "part1": "My mother said that I couldn't go to the movie alone, so my sister had to",
          "part2": "me.",
          "answer": "accompany"
        },
        {
          "part1": "When the candle fell over, it",
          "part2": "a small section of the tablecloth.",
          "answer": "scorched"
        },
        {
          "part1": "For years after his injury he felt a(n)",
          "part2": "in his foot whenever he exercised.",
          "answer": "ache"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Bill",
          "part2": "over the pile of bricks and almost fell.",
          "answer": "stumbled"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The overripe fruit began to",
          "part2": "in the hot sun.",
          "answer": "decay"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The kitten managed to",
          "part2": "into a small space behind the desk.",
          "answer": "squirm"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Her hands began to",
          "part2": "with fear as she got ready to sing the song.",
          "answer": "tremble"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The hotel provided",
          "part2": "for all those left homeless by the flood.",
          "answer": "shelter"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The clerk called the police when the man tried to buy food with a(n)",
          "part2": "twenty-dollar bill.",
          "answer": "counterfeit"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Her grandfather was almost deaf, so Mary had to",
          "part2": "whenever she had something to say to him.",
          "answer": "holler"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The vacuum cleaner stopped working three days after we got it, so we took it back to the store and demanded that they",
          "part2": "our money.",
          "answer": "refund"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He practiced hard to",
          "part2": "his goal of learning how to swim.",
          "answer": "achieve"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We're very good friends; if she's unhappy then I'm",
          "part2": "too.",
          "answer": "miserable"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I like to go to parties where people are",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "sociable"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She refused to",
          "part2": "her reasons for not coming.",
          "answer": "discuss"
        }
      ]
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "1.4",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "What does she REPRESENT?",
          "answers": [
            "leave out",
            "dislike",
            "expect",
            "stand for",
            "mean"
          ],
          "word": "REPRESENT",
          "correct": "stand for"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LASHED the prisoner.",
          "answers": [
            "lost",
            "killed",
            "helped",
            "cut",
            "whipped"
          ],
          "word": "LASH",
          "correct": "whipped"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To RELY on it.",
          "answers": [
            "work",
            "agree",
            "improve",
            "depend",
            "give up"
          ],
          "word": "RELY",
          "correct": "depend"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To SOB constantly.",
          "answers": [
            "shake",
            "cry",
            "cough",
            "shout",
            "laugh"
          ],
          "word": "SOB",
          "correct": "cry"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Seven PACES.",
          "answers": [
            "feet",
            "flights",
            "steps",
            "horses",
            "jumps"
          ],
          "word": "PACE",
          "correct": "steps"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Different METHOD.",
          "answers": [
            "look",
            "idea",
            "ending",
            "way",
            "church"
          ],
          "word": "METHOD",
          "correct": "way"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Told to RETREAT.",
          "answers": [
            "enjoy",
            "push forward",
            "go back",
            "forget",
            "fall down"
          ],
          "word": "RETREAT",
          "correct": "go back"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Several RECKLESS men.",
          "answers": [
            "angry",
            "slow",
            "lazy",
            "careless",
            "penniless"
          ],
          "word": "RECKLESS",
          "correct": "careless"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SWIFT animals.",
          "answers": [
            "fast",
            "small",
            "happy",
            "wild",
            "tired"
          ],
          "word": "SWIFT",
          "correct": "fast"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REGAIN the land.",
          "answers": [
            "lose",
            "aim for",
            "get back",
            "keep",
            "enjoy"
          ],
          "word": "REGAIN",
          "correct": "get back"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A rare OPPORTUNITY.",
          "answers": [
            "offer",
            "chance",
            "problem",
            "disagreement",
            "sale"
          ],
          "word": "OPPORTUNITY",
          "correct": "chance"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Easy to IRRITATE.",
          "answers": [
            "annoy",
            "hate",
            "harm",
            "refuse",
            "calm"
          ],
          "word": "IRRITATE",
          "correct": "annoy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Who REQUESTED it?",
          "answers": [
            "searched for",
            "returned",
            "asked for",
            "needed",
            "disapproved of"
          ],
          "word": "REQUEST",
          "correct": "asked for"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A beautiful POSE.",
          "answers": [
            "race",
            "body",
            "picture",
            "flower",
            "position"
          ],
          "word": "POSE",
          "correct": "position"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INVESTIGATE the charges.",
          "answers": [
            "forget",
            "agree with",
            "prove",
            "look into",
            "pay for"
          ],
          "word": "INVESTIGATE",
          "correct": "look into"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Does a penny REPRESENT a lot of money?",
          "word": "REPRESENT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a horse usually run faster when the rider LASHES it?",
          "word": "LASH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you RELY on a liar to tell the truth?",
          "word": "RELY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you SOB while holding your breath?",
          "word": "SOB",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do nervous people sometimes PACE back and forth?",
          "word": "PACE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there more than one METHOD for learning how to swim?",
          "word": "METHOD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do soldiers ever RETREAT?",
          "word": "RETREAT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Should people drive cars RECKLESSLY?",
          "word": "RECKLESS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are turtles SWIFT?",
          "word": "SWIFT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it possible to REGAIN something you never had?",
          "word": "REGAIN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people have an OPPORTUNITY to go to the moon?",
          "word": "OPPORTUNITY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a fly buzzing around a person's head be IRRITATING?",
          "word": "IRRITATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it more polite to REQUEST something than to demand it?",
          "word": "REQUEST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do models POSE for pictures?",
          "word": "POSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do astronomers INVESTIGATE the stars?",
          "word": "INVESTIGATE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "That ambassador REPRESENTS Canada.",
          "word": "REPRESENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The angry man LASHED out at everyone who criticized him.",
          "word": "LASH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Blanche said that she had always RELIED on the kindness of strangers.",
          "word": "RELY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She SOBBED with laughter at the funny jokes.",
          "word": "SOB",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was going at such a fast PACE that no one could keep up with him.",
          "word": "PACE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It seems that every week someone comes up with a new METHOD for teaching arithmetic.",
          "word": "METHOD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The soldiers RETREATED to attack the enemy.",
          "word": "RETREAT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He is very RECKLESS about his health; he eats too much, smokes too much, and drinks too much.",
          "word": "RECKLESS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bob SWIFTLY recovered the fumble and raced for a touchdown.",
          "word": "SWIFT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It took several weeks for him to REGAIN confidence in his driving ability after the terrible accident.",
          "word": "REGAIN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He just never had the OPPORTUNITIES to succeed that we have had.",
          "word": "OPPORTUNITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The rash on her arm was further IRRITATED by her constant scratching.",
          "word": "IRRITATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He REQUESTED that we stop talking.",
          "word": "REQUEST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She wore beautiful POSES around her neck.",
          "word": "POSE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He INVESTIGATED the possibility of buying a new car.",
          "word": "INVESTIGATE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "REPRESENT",
          "answers": [
            "stand for",
            "act for",
            "hope for"
          ],
          "word": "REPRESENT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LASH",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "wound",
            "hit"
          ],
          "word": "LASH",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RELY",
          "answers": [
            "enjoy",
            "count on",
            "expect"
          ],
          "word": "RELY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SOB",
          "answers": [
            "weep",
            "cry",
            "chuckle"
          ],
          "word": "SOB",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PACE",
          "answers": [
            "walk",
            "run",
            "jump"
          ],
          "word": "PACE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "METHOD",
          "answers": [
            "plan",
            "stop",
            "system"
          ],
          "word": "METHOD",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RETREAT",
          "answers": [
            "go back",
            "escape",
            "decide"
          ],
          "word": "RETREAT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECKLESS",
          "answers": [
            "careless",
            "useless",
            "thoughtless"
          ],
          "word": "RECKLESS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SWIFT",
          "answers": [
            "large",
            "speedy",
            "quick"
          ],
          "word": "SWIFT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REGAIN",
          "answers": [
            "get",
            "want",
            "recover"
          ],
          "word": "REGAIN",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OPPORTUNITY",
          "answers": [
            "event",
            "opening",
            "chance"
          ],
          "word": "OPPORTUNITY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IRRITATE",
          "answers": [
            "inflame",
            "bother",
            "refuse"
          ],
          "word": "IRRITATE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REQUEST",
          "answers": [
            "want",
            "show",
            "ask"
          ],
          "word": "REQUEST",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "POSE",
          "answers": [
            "stand",
            "sleep",
            "sit"
          ],
          "word": "POSE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INVESTIGATE",
          "answers": [
            "remember",
            "search",
            "study"
          ],
          "word": "INVESTIGATE",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "REPRESENT": {
        "word": "REPRESENT",
        "phonetic": "(rep-ri-zent')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to stand for, act for, portray \nTo REPRESENT something is to stand for it, to be a picture or sign of it. \n\"The flag is a symbol that REPRESENTS our country.\" \n\"These written notes REPRESENT musical sounds.\" \n\"The scenery in the play is supposed to REPRESENT an African jungle.\" \nTo REPRESENT also means to _speak_ or _act for_ someone or something. \n\"Bill will REPRESENT our school at the track meet.\" \n\"Senator Jones REPRESENTS our state in Congress.\" \nOther forms of the word: REPRESENTATION, n. REPRESENTATIVE, adj."
      },
      "LASH": {
        "word": "LASH",
        "phonetic": "(lash)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to strike, whip, beat \nTo LASH someone is to hit him with a whip, or as if with a whip. \n\"He LASHED the thief twenty times for punishment.\" \n\"He LASHED the horse with his whip.\" \n\"The rain LASHED against the windows.\" \nTo give someone a \"tongue-LASHING\" is to speak to him very angrily, to make him feel as if you were LASHING him with a whip. To LASH _out_ at someone is to attack him violently, with words or blows. \n\"In his talk the coach LASHED out at the players who didn't try.\""
      },
      "RELY": {
        "word": "RELY",
        "phonetic": "(ri-11)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to depend, trust, have faith \nTo RELY _on_ or _upon_ someone is to depend on them, to put your trust in them. \n\"I RELIED on him to help me out.\" \n\"We're RELYING on you to keep our secret.\" \n\"He can be RELIED on to get us to the airport on time.\" \nThe noun form of RELY is RELIANCE, which means trust, confidence. \n\"We place our RELIANCE on you to get us out of trouble.\" \nThe adjective is RELIABLE. Someone who is RELIABLE can be RELIED upon. \n\"He is a RELIABLE worker. You can count on him to do the job right.\" \nOther forms of the word: RELIABLE, adj. RELIANCE, n. Usage: RELY is usually followed by on or upon."
      },
      "SOB": {
        "word": "SOB",
        "phonetic": "(sob)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to cry, weep \nTo SOB is to cry in gasping bursts, while taking sharp breaths. \n\"She SOBBED in relief that the child was not injured.\" \n\"We heard him SOBBING quietly in his room.\" \nSOB is also a noun. \n\"We couldn't understand what the unhappy child was saying as she tried to talk between SOBS.\" \n\"The first angry crying gave way to long SOBS.\" \n\"His chest heaved with SOBS.\""
      },
      "PACE": {
        "word": "PACE",
        "phonetic": "(pAs)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a step; rate of moving \nA PACE is a step in walking or running. \n\"He took a PACE or two and then stopped.\" It is also the distance of a step. \n\"She measured off six PACES from the tree.\" \nThe word is also used to indicate the rate of walking or moving. \n\"He worked at a steady PACE all day long.\" \n\"He changed his PACE and started to run instead of walk.\" \nPACE is also a verb meaning to step or walk. \n\"He PACED back and forth across the room.\""
      },
      "METHOD": {
        "word": "METHOD",
        "phonetic": "(meth'-ÔøΩd)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a way, manner, system \nA METHOD is an orderly, logical way of doing something. \n\"There are several METHODS for teaching words.\" \n\"His METHOD for doing jigsaw puzzles is quite different from my system.\" \n\"It takes days to learn the right METHOD for operating this machine.\" \nA METHODICAL person does everything in an orderly way, according to a METHOD. He always thinks things through before acting. \n\"He was very METHODICAL about dressing. He put everything on in a certain order and in a certain way.\" \nOther forms of the word: METHODICAL, adj."
      },
      "RETREAT": {
        "word": "RETREAT",
        "phonetic": "(ri-trEt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to go back, draw back, withdraw \nTo RETREAT is to go back, especially from a dangerous or difficult situation. \n\"When the enemy attacked, the army was forced to RETREAT.\" \n\"If we RETREAT, will people think we are cowards?\" \nRETREAT is also a noun. \n\"The general said that a RETREAT was the only way to save the army.\""
      },
      "RECKLESS": {
        "word": "RECKLESS",
        "phonetic": "(rek'-lÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "careless, heedless, rash, foolhardy, wild \nSee _-less_ under Suffixes. RECK is an old word which means to _take care_, _be concerned_. Someone who is RECKLESS does not take enough care, is thoughtless or wild. \n\"The RECKLESS driver went down the narrow street at a hundred miles per hour.\" \"He raced after the criminal, completely RECKLESS of the danger.\" \"She lost everything she owned through her RECKLESS gambling.\""
      },
      "SWIFT": {
        "word": "SWIFT",
        "phonetic": "(swift)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "fast, quick, prompt \nSWIFT means _fast_ or _quick_; the word usually suggests smoothness of movement. \n\"We had all we could do to keep from overturning in the SWIFT waters of the river.\" \n\"He ran so SWIFTLY that the others never caught up with him.\" \n\"The days of summer pass SWIFTLY and the vacation is over before you know it.\" \n\"There was a SWIFT change in the weather from blue skies to heavy rain.\""
      },
      "REGAIN": {
        "word": "REGAIN",
        "phonetic": "(rE-gAn')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to get back, recover \nSee _re-_ under Prefixes. To REGAIN something is to gain it or get it back after you have lost it. The word is usually used about qualities or states rather than physical objects. \n\"After being in prison for ten years, he finally REGAINED his freedom.\" \n\"It took Jane a while to REGAIN her health after her operation.\" \n\"They lost the lead, then REGAINED it.\" \n\"He REGAINED his balance after nearly slipping on the ice.\""
      },
      "OPPORTUNITY": {
        "word": "OPPORTUNITY",
        "phonetic": "(op-ÔøΩr-tU'-ni-tE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a chance \nAn OPPORTUNITY is a favorable time or chance for doing something. \n\"This is a golden OPPORTUNITY for making all kinds of money.\" \n\"If I only had the OPPORTUNITY I'd show them what a good player I am.\" \n\"We had plenty of OPPORTUNITIES to win. We just couldn't seem to take advantage of them.\" \n\"Jane had no OPPORTUNITY to speak to the teacher after school.\" \nUsage: OPPORTUNITY is often followed by _to_ or _for_."
      },
      "IRRITATE": {
        "word": "IRRITATE",
        "phonetic": "(Er'-ÔøΩtAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to annoy, cause anger; to make sore, inflame \nSee _-ate2_ under Suffixes. IRRITATE has two different meanings. To IRRITATE someone is to cause him to become angry, to annoy him. \n\"The student's endless questions quickly IRRITATED the impatient teacher.\" \n\"After several weeks, Jane found her roommate's sloppy habits to be extremely IRRITATING.\" \n\"The mother was very IRRITATED by her children's constant whining.\" \nIn another sense, to IRRITATE something is to cause it to become sore or inflamed. \n\"The woman's eyes were IRRITATED by the smoke-filled air.\" \nIRRITABLE is the adjective from IRRITATE and means _bad-tempered_. \n\"Hot weather always made him very IRRITABLE, and on those days we tried our best to avoid him.\" \nOther forms of the word: IRRITABLE, adj. IRRITATION, n."
      },
      "REQUEST": {
        "word": "REQUEST",
        "phonetic": "(ri-kwest)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to ask, ask for \nTo REQUEST something is to ask for it, usually very politely. \n\"He REQUESTED a new pair of shoes from his parents.\" \n\"I REQUESTED him to come early.\" \n\"All I REQUEST of you is that you be on time.\" \n\"They REQUEST that we be silent until they are finished.\" \nREQUEST is also a noun. \n\"At their REQUEST we shall come to the party.\" \n\"They turned down his REQUEST for a raise.\""
      },
      "POSE": {
        "word": "POSE",
        "phonetic": "(pOz)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a position of the body, attitude \nA POSE is a fixed position of the body, especially one that is taken up while your picture is being taken or painted. \n\"He had an odd POSE in the painting, leaning to the side with one foot in the air.\" \nPOSE has also come to mean any way of behaving which may seem unnatural or put on just to impress people. \n\"She acted very friendly towards us, but it was all just a POSE. Really she disliked us intensely.\" \nAs a verb, POSE means \"to hold a physical position.\" \n\"His wife used to POSE for his paintings.\" \nIt can also mean \"to take on a false character, to claim to be.\" \n\"The robber POSED as a janitor in order to get into the apartment.\""
      },
      "INVESTIGATE": {
        "word": "INVESTIGATE",
        "phonetic": "(in-ves'-ti-gAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to look into, examine in detail, study \nINVESTIGATE comes from the Latin word for _footprint_. The word was used in Latin when talking about tracking down animals by following their footprints. In English, to INVESTIGATE something is to make careful study of it, to look into it closely. \n\"The policeman INVESTIGATED the crime.\" \n\"We will have to INVESTIGATE how much a new radio costs.\" \n\"He INVESTIGATED the area for clues.\" \nMany people confuse the meaning of INVESTIGATE with the word prove. You might INVESTIGATE a crime, for example, to prove who did it, but INVESTIGATE only means to look into or study. Other forms of the word: INVESTIGATION, n."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "1.5",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Were you MISTREATED?",
          "answers": [
            "abused",
            "confused",
            "cheated",
            "helped",
            "frightened"
          ],
          "word": "MISTREAT",
          "correct": "abused"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FURIOUS loser.",
          "answers": [
            "born",
            "timid",
            "roaring",
            "angry",
            "apparent"
          ],
          "word": "FURIOUS",
          "correct": "angry"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CAUTIOUS speech.",
          "answers": [
            "dull",
            "careful",
            "quick",
            "unplanned",
            "interesting"
          ],
          "word": "CAUTIOUS",
          "correct": "careful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Small QUANTITY.",
          "answers": [
            "help",
            "value",
            "amount",
            "understanding",
            "increase"
          ],
          "word": "QUANTITY",
          "correct": "amount"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It had EXPIRED.",
          "answers": [
            "ended",
            "continued",
            "been lost",
            "changed",
            "burned up"
          ],
          "word": "EXPIRE",
          "correct": "ended"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ELIMINATE all the rest.",
          "answers": [
            "set fire to",
            "give away",
            "cut up",
            "add",
            "get rid of"
          ],
          "word": "ELIMINATE",
          "correct": "get rid of"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Story of the BANDIT.",
          "answers": [
            "robber",
            "cowboy",
            "deserter",
            "lawman",
            "musician"
          ],
          "word": "BANDIT",
          "correct": "robber"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TIRESOME events.",
          "answers": [
            "private",
            "exciting",
            "usual",
            "boring",
            "harmful"
          ],
          "word": "TIRESOME",
          "correct": "boring"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "There are NUMEROUS objections.",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "real",
            "many",
            "funny",
            "few"
          ],
          "word": "NUMEROUS",
          "correct": "many"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISTANT lights.",
          "answers": [
            "clear",
            "tiny",
            "different",
            "nearby",
            "far-off"
          ],
          "word": "DISTANT",
          "correct": "far off"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "This ALTITUDE.",
          "answers": [
            "place",
            "height",
            "flight",
            "depth",
            "mountain"
          ],
          "word": "ALTITUDE",
          "correct": "height"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PERMANENT peace.",
          "answers": [
            "historic",
            "present",
            "lasting",
            "uneasy",
            "brief"
          ],
          "word": "PERMANENT",
          "correct": "lasting"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Near the BORDER.",
          "answers": [
            "bottom",
            "middle",
            "area",
            "forest",
            "edge"
          ],
          "word": "BORDER",
          "correct": "edge"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were ASSEMBLED.",
          "answers": [
            "brought together",
            "lied to",
            "crowded",
            "turned in",
            "scattered"
          ],
          "word": "ASSEMBLE",
          "correct": "brought together"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PECULIAR people.",
          "answers": [
            "dishonest",
            "average",
            "many",
            "odd",
            "lonely"
          ],
          "word": "PECULIAR",
          "correct": "odd"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Should children be MISTREATED?",
          "word": "MISTREAT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are happy people usually FURIOUS?",
          "word": "FURIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would you need to use CAUTION if you were walking on a tightrope?",
          "word": "CAUTIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is 4 a greater QUANTITY than 3?",
          "word": "QUANTITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Have you EXPIRED?",
          "word": "EXPIRE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people favor the ELIMINATION of war?",
          "word": "ELIMINATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a BANDIT break the law?",
          "word": "BANDIT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are TIRESOME people fun to be with?",
          "word": "TIRESOME",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are there NUMEROUS stars in the sky?",
          "word": "NUMEROUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are the stars DISTANT from Earth?",
          "word": "DISTANT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can people live at a low ALTITUDE?",
          "word": "ALTITUDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a summer job a PERMANENT one?",
          "word": "PERMANENT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there a BORDER between the United States and Canada?",
          "word": "BORDER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When you buy a book, does it usually have to be ASSEMBLED?",
          "word": "ASSEMBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a six-foot-wide potato be PECULIAR?",
          "word": "PECULIAR",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Her mother MISTREATED her to another piece of cake after supper.",
          "word": "MISTREAT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bill gets FURIOUS whenever anyone is late for an appointment with him.",
          "word": "FURIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He CAUTIOUSLY avoided going near the large dog.",
          "word": "CAUTIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We don't care if we make a smaller QUANTITY of chairs, as long as the quality remains good.",
          "word": "QUANTITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His library card EXPIRED six months ago.",
          "word": "EXPIRE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They tried to ELIMINATE her from the race because she was too young.",
          "word": "ELIMINATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BANDITS of armed men wandered through the streets of the deserted city.",
          "word": "BANDIT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was so TIRESOME after the long trip that he fell asleep right away.",
          "word": "TIRESOME",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was NUMEROUS last night.",
          "word": "NUMEROUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We could barely see them on the DISTANT hill.",
          "word": "DISTANT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Jim grew to an ALTITUDE of well over six feet.",
          "word": "ALTITUDE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "This was supposed to be our PERMANENT home, but we moved again after a few years.",
          "word": "PERMANENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Soldiers patrolled the BORDER between the two countries.",
          "word": "BORDER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They ASSEMBLED each other so much we thought they were twins.",
          "word": "ASSEMBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "This fish is PECULIAR to the Pacific Ocean.",
          "word": "PECULIAR",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "MISTREAT",
          "answers": [
            "warn",
            "hurt",
            "starve"
          ],
          "word": "MISTREAT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FURIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "angry",
            "fearful",
            "mad"
          ],
          "word": "FURIOUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CAUTIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "slow",
            "sharp",
            "safe"
          ],
          "word": "CAUTIOUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "QUANTITY",
          "answers": [
            "amount",
            "number",
            "length"
          ],
          "word": "QUANTITY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXPIRE",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "die",
            "hurt"
          ],
          "word": "EXPIRE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ELIMINATE",
          "answers": [
            "lose",
            "worry",
            "remove"
          ],
          "word": "ELIMINATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BANDIT",
          "answers": [
            "thief",
            "slob",
            "criminal"
          ],
          "word": "BANDIT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TIRESOME",
          "answers": [
            "annoying",
            "cruel",
            "dull"
          ],
          "word": "TIRESOME",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NUMEROUS",
          "answers": [
            "tall",
            "many",
            "often"
          ],
          "word": "NUMEROUS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISTANT",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "far",
            "long"
          ],
          "word": "DISTANT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ALTITUDE",
          "answers": [
            "height",
            "width",
            "tallness"
          ],
          "word": "ALTITUDE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PERMANENT",
          "answers": [
            "forever",
            "constant",
            "usual"
          ],
          "word": "PERMANENT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BORDER",
          "answers": [
            "side",
            "edge",
            "point"
          ],
          "word": "BORDER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ASSEMBLE",
          "answers": [
            "join",
            "gather",
            "attack"
          ],
          "word": "ASSEMBLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PECULIAR",
          "answers": [
            "happy",
            "different",
            "strange"
          ],
          "word": "PECULIAR",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "MISTREAT": {
        "word": "MISTREAT",
        "phonetic": "(mis-trEt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to treat badly, abuse \nSee _mis-_ under Prefixes. To MISTREAT someone is to treat him badly, to do wrong to him, either physically or in some other way. \n\"Look at all the cuts on that dog. I think his owner MISTREATS him.\" \n\"Alice complained that she had been MISTREATED by her teachers.\" \n\"The parents were accused of MISTREATING their children by not giving them enough to eat.\" \nCheat is often chosen as the meaning of MISTREAT on the Pretest. MISTREAT is a much more general word than cheat, however. You can MISTREAT a person by doing wrong to him in any way, not just by cheating him. Other forms of the word: MISTREATMENT, n."
      },
      "": {
        "word": "FURIOUS",
        "phonetic": "(fyur'-E-gs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "angry, violent, stormy, fierce \nFURY is violent anger. \n\"The mother was filled with FURY when she saw them hurting her child.\" FURIOUS is the adjective from FURY. See _-ous_ under Suffixes. Someone who is FURIOUS is full of wild anger. \n\"Her father was FURIOUS when Jill wrecked his car.\" \n\"She was mildly upset, but everyone else was really FURIOUS.\" FURIOUS also means \"full of activity,\" wild, energetic. \n\"He put on a FURIOUS finish to come from behind and win the race.\" \n\"With one FURIOUS burst of activity, they completely cleaned the house in two hours.\" \nOther forms of the word: FURY, n."
      },
      "CAUTIOUS": {
        "word": "CAUTIOUS",
        "phonetic": "(ko'-shgs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "careful, watchful \nTo be CAUTIOUS is to be careful, to pay close attention so that you don't make a mistake or so that you don't hurt anyone. \n\"You must be CAUTIOUS when you cross a busy street.\" \n\"She patted the kitten CAUTIOUSLY so that it wouldn't become alarmed and run away.\" \n\"The burglar made a CAUTIOUS approach to the darkened house.\" \nCAUTION is the noun from CAUTIOUS; it means _care_, _alertness_. \n\"You must use CAUTION when dealing with poisons.\" \n\"He answered with a great deal of CAUTION. He was afraid to say something he didn't mean.\" \nOther forms of the word: CAUTION, n., v."
      },
      "QUANTITY": {
        "word": "QUANTITY",
        "phonetic": "(kwon'-tg-tE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an amount, number \nQUANTITY is something that can be measured. When you ask \"How much?\" or \"How many?\" you are asking about the QUANTITY of something. \n\"There is a large QUANTITY of dog food left over.\" \n\"We need a small QUANTITY of nails to build this bookcase.\" \nMany people pick value as the meaning of QUANTITY. This is probably due to a confusion between QUANTITY and _quality_. _Quality_ has to do with how good something is. \n\"We're not interested in _quality_ but in QUANTITY. We don't care how good they are as long as there are a lot of them.\""
      },
      "EXPIRE": {
        "word": "EXPIRE",
        "phonetic": "(ek-splr')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to die, come to an end, cease \nSee _ex-_ under Prefixes. EXPIRE originally meant \"to breathe out.\" From this it has come to mean \"to breathe one's last,\" to _die_. When used about people the word always means to _die_. \n\"After a long illness, he EXPIRED early this morning.\" When used about things it means to end or cease. \n\"The contract will EXPIRE at midnight\"—that is, it will no longer be in effect after that time. \n\"The senator's term of office will EXPIRE next year.\" \nWith food, the word means to _go bad_. \n\"Her roommate threw out the expired milk.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXPIRATION, n."
      },
      "ELIMINATE": {
        "word": "ELIMINATE",
        "phonetic": "(i-lim'-g--nAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to remove, get rid of, throw out, take away \nELIMINATE comes from a Latin word which means \"to throw out of doors,\" and this is the original meaning of the word. See _ex-_ under Prefixes. Today the word simply means to throw out or get rid of, and doesn't necessarily mean to throw something outside. \n\"The doctors found a new medicine that completely ELIMINATED the disease.\" \n\"The judges ELIMINATED him from the contest.\" \nThe noun form of ELIMINATE is ELIMINATION. An \"ELIMINATION tournament\" is one in which the loser of a game or match is removed from the competition. \nOther forms of the word: ELIMINATION, n."
      },
      "BANDIT": {
        "word": "BANDIT",
        "phonetic": "(ban'-dit)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a robber, outlaw \nA BANDIT was originally a member of a gang of people who banded together in order to rob. Now BANDIT is used about anyone who robs people, alone or as part of a gang. \n\"He was held up by a BANDIT in broad daylight.\" \n\"The BANDITS fled to a cabin in the hills.\""
      },
      "TIRESOME": {
        "word": "TIRESOME",
        "phonetic": "(tlr'-sÔøΩm)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "boring, tedious, dull, annoying \nSomething that is TIRESOME makes you tired. The word is usually used about people or things that are so boring they make you want to fall asleep. The word, however, does not mean _tired_; it means _causing tiredness_. \n\"Having to write the same sentence fifty times is an extremely TIRESOME exercise.\" \n\"Jim can make exciting events seem TIRESOME.\" \nSometimes TIRESOME suggests the meaning _annoying_ more than _boring_. \n\"She was a very TIRESOME person to deal with, always whining and complaining.\""
      },
      "NUMEROUS": {
        "word": "NUMEROUS",
        "phonetic": "(nU'-mÔøΩr-ÔøΩs",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "many \nNUMEROUS comes from the Latin word for _number_. The word means \"great in number,\" _many_. See _-ous_ under Suffixes. \"There are NUMEROUS reasons why we can't come. I will only tell you a few.\" \n\"NUMEROUS people applied for the job, but only one would get it.\" \n\"The people who helped me are too NUMEROUS to mention.\" \n\"NUMEROUS colleges want our star quarterback to play for them.\""
      },
      "DISTANT": {
        "word": "DISTANT",
        "phonetic": "(dis'-tÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "far off \nDISTANT means _far off_, _far away_. \n\"Jim wanted to leave home and travel to DISTANT lands.\" \n\"The sound of DISTANT church bells came faintly to us.\" \n\"The sun is 93 million miles DISTANT from the Earth.\" \nDISTANT can be used about time as well as space. \n\"In the DISTANT past people lived in caves and not in houses.\" \nOther forms of the word: DISTANCE, n."
      },
      "ALTITUDE": {
        "word": "ALTITUDE",
        "phonetic": "(al'-tÔøΩ-tUd)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "height \nALTITUDE refers to height from earth. It is used about things, not people. \n\"The planes rose to an ALTITUDE of 20,000 feet above sea level.\" \n\"The city is located in the mountains at an ALTITUDE of 5,000 feet.\" \n\"At this ALTITUDE it becomes very difficult to breathe.\" \nThe ALTITUDE of something can be described as either high or low. \n\"He flew the helicopter at a very low ALTITUDE as he tried to spot where the plane had crashed.\""
      },
      "PERMANENT": {
        "word": "PERMANENT",
        "phonetic": "(per'm:r-nÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "lasting, unchanging \nPERMANENT means _lasting_, \"meant to be the same for a long time.\" \n\"This is only my summer home; my PERMANENT home is in New York City.\" \n\"After several temporary jobs, he got a PERMANENT job in the post office.\" \n\"He received a PERMANENT injury from the accident.\" \n\"The dentist put a PERMANENT filling in the patient's tooth.\" \nOther forms of the word: PERMANENCE, n."
      },
      "BORDER": {
        "word": "BORDER",
        "phonetic": "(bor'-dÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "edge, boundary, frontier \nBORDER has many meanings and uses, but the main one is the _edge_ of something. \"There was a BORDER of gold around the invitation.\" \nA BORDER is a boundary between two countries. \"We crossed the BORDER into Canada late in the afternoon.\" \n\"You have to stop at the BORDER and show your passport.\" \nBORDER is also a verb which means \"to lie along or be adjacent to the BORDER of.\" \n\"Our farm BORDERS the state highway.\" \n\"The city is BORDERED by the ocean to the east.\""
      },
      "ASSEMBLE": {
        "word": "ASSEMBLE",
        "phonetic": "(a-sem'-bÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to bring together, gather together \nASSEMBLE means to _bring together_ or _gather together_. The word usually suggests an orderly gathering of people with a common purpose. \n\"The troops were ASSEMBLED on the parade ground.\" \n\"The senators will ASSEMBLE tomorrow to vote on the new law.\" \nASSEMBLE can also mean to _put together_. \n\"It took us three days to ASSEMBLE the jigsaw puzzle.\" \n\"He thinks he can ASSEMBLE a new car from the parts of old ones.\" \nOther forms of the word: ASSEMBLY, n."
      },
      "PECULIAR": {
        "word": "PECULIAR",
        "phonetic": "(pi-kyUl'-yÔøΩ)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "odd, strange, different, unusual; unique, characteristic \nPECULIAR means odd, strange, \"different from anyone or anything else.\" \n\"He had a PECULIAR way of talking that no one else could imitate.\" \n\"It was very PECULIAR that everyone was absent on the same day.\" \nAnother meaning of PECULIAR is \"belonging only to one person, group, place, or the like.\" \nIn this sense PECULIAR is usually followed by _to_. \n\"This kind of house is PECULIAR to New England. You won't find it anywhere else.\" \nOther forms of the word: PECULIARITY, n."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "1.6",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He EXHALED slowly.",
          "answers": [
            "died",
            "coughed",
            "breathed out",
            "smoked",
            "breathed in"
          ],
          "word": "EXHALE",
          "correct": "breathed out"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HURDLE the wall.",
          "answers": [
            "jump over",
            "surround",
            "climb",
            "run into",
            "knock down"
          ],
          "word": "HURDLE",
          "correct": "jump over"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We must DEFEND them.",
          "answers": [
            "insult",
            "protect",
            "admire",
            "help",
            "attack"
          ],
          "word": "DEFEND",
          "correct": "protect"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She saw the HAZARD.",
          "answers": [
            "wild bird",
            "danger",
            "electrical wire",
            "signal",
            "fire"
          ],
          "word": "HAZARD",
          "correct": "danger"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The boiler ERUPTED.",
          "answers": [
            "broke down",
            "roared",
            "shut off",
            "burst forth",
            "became rusty"
          ],
          "word": "ERUPT",
          "correct": "burst forth"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONCEAL it.",
          "answers": [
            "look for",
            "break",
            "show",
            "hide",
            "lose"
          ],
          "word": "CONCEAL",
          "correct": "hide"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Started to BLUSH.",
          "answers": [
            "grin",
            "redden",
            "tremble",
            "sob",
            "run"
          ],
          "word": "BLUSH",
          "correct": "redden"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXAMINE the results.",
          "answers": [
            "spoil",
            "talk about",
            "remember",
            "forget",
            "look into"
          ],
          "word": "EXAMINE",
          "correct": "look into"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONSTRUCT the palace.",
          "answers": [
            "tear down",
            "build",
            "repair",
            "write about",
            "visit"
          ],
          "word": "CONSTRUCT",
          "correct": "build"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Another REGULATION.",
          "answers": [
            "announcement",
            "question",
            "rule",
            "decision",
            "suggestion"
          ],
          "word": "REGULATION",
          "correct": "rule"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "So much GRIME.",
          "answers": [
            "frost",
            "junk",
            "water",
            "dirt",
            "rust"
          ],
          "word": "GRIME",
          "correct": "dirt"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Quite a HANDICAP.",
          "answers": [
            "help",
            "prize",
            "disadvantage",
            "decision",
            "loss"
          ],
          "word": "HANDICAP",
          "correct": "disadvantage"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Aware of his DISGRACE.",
          "answers": [
            "shame",
            "crime",
            "clumsiness",
            "reward",
            "sadness"
          ],
          "word": "DISGRACE",
          "correct": "shame"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To BAIT them.",
          "answers": [
            "invite",
            "expect",
            "interest",
            "kill",
            "annoy"
          ],
          "word": "BAIT",
          "correct": "annoy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SPLENDID appearance.",
          "answers": [
            "innocent",
            "magnificent",
            "dull",
            "improved",
            "holy"
          ],
          "word": "SPLENDID",
          "correct": "magnificent"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do rocks EXHALE?",
          "word": "EXHALE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you HURDLE a building?",
          "word": "HURDLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you DEFEND a person with words?",
          "word": "DEFEND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Should you avoid a HAZARD?",
          "word": "HAZARD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a tall tree ERUPT from the ground overnight?",
          "word": "ERUPT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a thought be CONCEALED?",
          "word": "CONCEAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually BLUSH because they are sleepy?",
          "word": "BLUSH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do doctors EXAMINE their patients?",
          "word": "EXAMINE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are houses CONSTRUCTED before people live in them?",
          "word": "CONSTRUCT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most schools have REGULATIONS?",
          "word": "REGULATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does taking a shower make you GRIMY?",
          "word": "GRIME",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a small dog have a HANDICAP in a fight with a large one?",
          "word": "HANDICAP",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it DISGRACEFUL to help someone in need?",
          "word": "DISGRACE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is cheese used as BAIT to catch mice?",
          "word": "BAIT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a rubbish dump SPLENDID?",
          "word": "SPLENDID",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He EXHALED the wonderful smell of bread baking.",
          "word": "EXHALE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The car went out of control and HURDLED into the wall.",
          "word": "HURDLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He kept DEFENDING them until finally they called the police, and he was ar rested.",
          "word": "DEFEND",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was a HAZARDOUS job, so no one wanted to do it.",
          "word": "HAZARD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "An outburst of applause ERUPTED from the audience when the act was over.",
          "word": "ERUPT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She couldn't CONCEAL how happy she was to see them.",
          "word": "CONCEAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She BLUSHED when he told her he loved her.",
          "word": "BLUSH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We EXAMINED the paper carefully to see if there were any mistakes.",
          "word": "EXAMINE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She cleaned the room and CONSTRUCTED it every day.",
          "word": "CONSTRUCT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Your actions were against REGULATIONS, and you must be punished.",
          "word": "REGULATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The rain washed away some of the GRIME on his face.",
          "word": "GRIME",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "In the race, the faster drivers were given the HANDICAP of a head start.",
          "word": "HANDICAP",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His manners are a DISGRACE. No one should eat with him.",
          "word": "DISGRACE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The students BAITED the teacher by making fun of everything he said and did.",
          "word": "BAIT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The SPLENDOR of the sight made us gasp.",
          "word": "SPLENDID",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "EXHALE",
          "answers": [
            "feel",
            "breathe",
            "sneeze"
          ],
          "word": "EXHALE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HURDLE",
          "answers": [
            "bump",
            "leap",
            "jump"
          ],
          "word": "HURDLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEFEND",
          "answers": [
            "guard",
            "win",
            "save"
          ],
          "word": "DEFEND",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HAZARD",
          "answers": [
            "danger",
            "threat",
            "fog"
          ],
          "word": "HAZARD",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ERUPT",
          "answers": [
            "spurt",
            "crash",
            "explode"
          ],
          "word": "ERUPT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONCEAL",
          "answers": [
            "bury",
            "hide",
            "fake"
          ],
          "word": "CONCEAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BLUSH",
          "answers": [
            "fear",
            "redden",
            "shame"
          ],
          "word": "BLUSH",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXAMINE",
          "answers": [
            "know",
            "study",
            "search"
          ],
          "word": "EXAMINE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONSTRUCT",
          "answers": [
            "fix",
            "make",
            "build"
          ],
          "word": "CONSTRUCT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REGULATION",
          "answers": [
            "order",
            "request",
            "law"
          ],
          "word": "REGULATION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GRIME",
          "answers": [
            "sickness",
            "dirt",
            "filth"
          ],
          "word": "GRIME",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HANDICAP",
          "answers": [
            "disadvantage",
            "disability",
            "condition"
          ],
          "word": "HANDICAP",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISGRACE",
          "answers": [
            "badness",
            "bashfulness",
            "shame"
          ],
          "word": "DISGRACE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BAIT",
          "answers": [
            "tease",
            "touch",
            "attract"
          ],
          "word": "BAIT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SPLENDID",
          "answers": [
            "grand",
            "dangerous",
            "tremendous"
          ],
          "word": "SPLENDID",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "EXHALE": {
        "word": "EXHALE",
        "phonetic": "(eks-hAI')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to breathe out \nSee _ex-_ under Prefixes. To EXHALE is to breathe out. \n\"He took a deep breath, then EXHALED slowly.\" \n\"He EXHALED the air from his lungs.\" \nThe opposite of EXHALE is INHALE, to breathe in. Other forms of the word: EXHALATION, n."
      },
      "HURDLE": {
        "word": "HURDLE",
        "phonetic": "(herd'-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to jump over, overcome, surmount \nA HURDLE is an obstacle that you jump over in certain running races. To HURDLE something is to jump over it the way a runner would jump over a HURDLE. \n\"With one tremendous leap, the horse HURDLED the high fence.\" \nYou can HURDLE any kind of obstacle or barrier. \n\"If we can HURDLE this final problem the project will be a success.\" \n\"Students had to HURDLE a difficult series of tests before they were admitted to the school.\" \nHURDLE is sometimes confused with _hurtle_, which means \"to move with great speed.\" \n\"He _hurtled_ down the mountainside, HURDLING several fallen trees along the way.\""
      },
      "DEFEND": {
        "word": "DEFEND",
        "phonetic": "(di-fend')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to protect, guard \nTo DEFEND something is to protect it, to keep it from harm. \n\"The high wall DEFENDS the city against its enemies.\" \n\"His friends DEFENDED him when he was being attacked.\" \nYou can DEFEND someone from other things besides physical harm. \n\"The teacher DEFENDED Bill's right to say what was on his mind.\" \nThe act of DEFENDING is called DEFENSE. \n\"In DEFENSE of their kittens, mother cats will attack much larger animals.\" \n\"The government spends a great deal of money for the DEFENSE of the country.\" \nOther forms of the word: DEFENSE, n."
      },
      "HAZARD": {
        "word": "HAZARD",
        "phonetic": "(haz'-ÔøΩrd)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "danger, risk, peril \nOriginally HAZARD was a game of chance using dice. HAZARD has come to be used about anything that has a chance of being harmful, a possible source of danger or injury. \"The ice on the roads is a real HAZARD to drivers.\" \n\"The building inspector said that the loose electrical wires were a HAZARD.\" \nThe adjective from HAZARD is HAZARDOUS, meaning _dangerous_ or _risky_. \n\"Cigarette smoking is HAZARDOUS to your health.\" \n\"Going over Niagara Falls in a barrel is certainly a HAZARDOUS feat.\" \nOther forms of the word: HAZARDOUS, adj."
      },
      "ERUPT": {
        "word": "ERUPT",
        "phonetic": "(i-ruhpt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to burst forth, explode, break out \nTo ERUPT is to burst forth, suddenly and usually violently. See _ex-_ under Prefixes. When a volcano ERUPTS, steam and lava pour out of it. \n\"A cheer ERUPTED from the crowd when we scored the winning touchdown.\" \n\"Her face ERUPTS in a rash whenever she eats strawberries.\" \n\"Hal kept his anger under control all day, but it finally ERUPTED at something Ann said.\" \nAn ERUPTION is an outburst or an explosion. \n\"The sudden ERUPTION of fighting between the two countries surprised everyone.\" \nOther forms of the word: ERUPTION, n."
      },
      "CONCEAL": {
        "word": "CONCEAL",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-sEI')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to hide, keep secret \nTo CONCEAL something is to hide it from sight. \n\"Ann CONCEALED the letter under her pillow.\" \n\"He CONCEALED his face with a mask.\" \n\"Several large trees CONCEALED the house from view.\" \nYou can also CONCEAL ideas, plans, conditions, facts, and so on. \n\"He cleverly CONCEALED his real opinion by agreeing with everything we said.\" \n\"It was impossible to CONCEAL the truth from her. She guessed it right away.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONCEALMENT, n."
      },
      "BLUSH": {
        "word": "BLUSH",
        "phonetic": "(bluh",
        "pos": "sh)",
        "deftext": "v.: to redden, become red \nBLUSH means to _redden_ or to _become red_. When people BLUSH, their faces become red, usually because they are embarrassed or ashamed. \n\"David BLUSHED as he accepted the award for being the top student.\" \n\"She tries hard to appear calm, but whenever she meets him she BLUSHES.\" \nBLUSH is also used as a noun. \n\"Andy covered his face with his hands to hide his BLUSHES.\" \n\"Samantha admitted with a BLUSH that she had lied.\""
      },
      "EXAMINE": {
        "word": "EXAMINE",
        "phonetic": "(ig-zam'-ÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to look at carefully, search, inspect, test, question \nTo EXAMINE something is to look at it carefully in order to find out something about it or to learn from it. You can EXAMINE things. \n\"He EXAMINED the boat for leaks.\" \n\"The dentist EXAMINED his teeth.\" \nOr you can EXAMINE people, by asking questions instead of just looking. \n\"The lawyer EXAMINED the witness.\" \n\"The teacher EXAMINED the students in algebra.\" \nAn EXAMINATION is an act of EXAMINING, a test. \n\"Did you pass the final EXAMINATION?\" \n\"The luggage underwent a thorough EXAMINATION.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXAMINATION, n."
      },
      "CONSTRUCT": {
        "word": "CONSTRUCT",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-struhkt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to build, put together \nCONSTRUCT means to _build_, especially by putting together parts. \n\"We are going to CONSTRUCT a small shed in our backyard for all the gardening equipment.\" \n\"That big hotel was CONSTRUCTED in less than six months.\" \nYou can CONSTRUCT other things besides buildings. \n\"He can CONSTRUCT a kite out of newspaper and cardboard.\" \n\"She CONSTRUCTED her argument very carefully by putting all the facts together and in order.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONSTRUCTION, n."
      },
      "REGULATION": {
        "word": "REGULATION",
        "phonetic": "(re-gyÔøΩIA'-shÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a rule, order \nA REGULATION is a rule, an order which must be followed. \n\"It says in the school REGULATIONS that you are to be here by 8:30.\" \n\"They were careful to follow all the safety REGULATIONS.\" \n\"None of the REGULATIONS covers this particular problem.\" \n\"It is against company REGULATIONS for a worker to be absent without good reason.\" \nOther forms of the word: REGULATE, v. REGULATORY, adj."
      },
      "GRIME": {
        "word": "GRIME",
        "phonetic": "(grim)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "dirt, soot, dust \nGRIME is dirt, especially a coating of dirt on the surface of something. \n\"There was a layer of GRIME on the windowsill that no amount of scrubbing could remove.\" \n\"After working in the mine all day his face was covered with GRIME.\" \nGRIMY means \"covered with GRIME,\" _dirty_. \n\"Don't touch that white tablecloth with your GRIMY hands.\" \nOther forms of the word: GRIMY, adj."
      },
      "HANDICAP": {
        "word": "HANDICAP",
        "phonetic": "(han'-dE-kap)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a disadvantage, disability \nHANDICAP is a term in horse racing. In some races, in order to make them fairer or more exciting, the faster horses are given more weight to carry than the slower horses. This extra weight is called a HANDICAP. HANDICAP has come into general use, meaning \"any kind of burden or disadvantage which lessens your chance of success.\" \n\"His poor background in mathematics was quite a HANDICAP when he tried to study engineering.\" \n\"She didn't think of her blindness as a HANDICAP; she thought of it as a challenge to be overcome.\" \nHANDICAP can also be a verb. \n\"We were HANDICAPPED by our inability to speak Spanish.\""
      },
      "DISGRACE": {
        "word": "DISGRACE",
        "phonetic": "(dis-grAs')",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "shame, dishonor \nSee _dis-_ under Prefixes. One meaning of _grace_ is _favor_ or _goodwill_. To be in someone's \"good graces\" is to enjoy his honor and approval. DISGRACE is a lack of _grace_; it is shame or dishonor. \n\"His crimes brought DISGRACE on his entire family.\" \nA DISGRACE is also the thing or person that causes the shame. \n\"That worker is a DISGRACE to the company. He should be fired.\" \nSomething which is DISGRACEFUL causes DISGRACE. \n\"Your conduct is DISGRACEFUL. You should be ashamed of yourself.\" \nOther forms of the word: DISGRACEFUL, adj."
      },
      "BAIT": {
        "word": "BAIT",
        "phonetic": "(bAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to lure, entice; to attack, tease, harass _BAIT is related to the word _bite_. BAIT as a noun is food, or something like food, put on a hook to attract a fish. As a verb, BAIT has developed two different meanings. To BAIT someone can be to lure them the way a fish is lured, by holding out something to tempt them. \"The phony message BAITED the enemy into attacking us just where we wanted them to.\" \nTo BAIT is also to torment, annoy, or harass, usually in speech or writing. \n\"An angry woman in the crowd BAITED the speaker until he lost his temper.\" \n\"The other team BAITED us the whole game about our poor record.\""
      },
      "SPLENDID": {
        "word": "SPLENDID",
        "phonetic": "(splen'-did)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "magnificent, grand, excellent \nSPLENDID comes from a Latin word meaning to _shine_. Something that is SPLENDID shines out; it is brilliant or magnificent. \n\"She looked SPLENDID in her fancy new gown.\" \n\"This is a SPLENDID book. I recommend it highly.\" \n\"We had a SPLENDID opportunity to score, but we weren't able to.\" \nThe noun from SPLENDID is SPLENDOR. SPLENDOR is _magnificence_ or _excellence_. \n\"We were amazed by the SPLENDOR of every room in the palace.\" \nOther forms of the word: SPLENDOR, n."
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "ALTITUDE",
        "CONSTRUCT",
        "HANDICAP",
        "OPPORTUNITY",
        "REGULATION",
        "BAIT",
        "ELIMINATE",
        "HAZARD",
        "PERMANENT",
        "REPRESENT",
        "BORDER",
        "EXHALE",
        "INVESTIGATE",
        "RECKLESS",
        "RETREAT",
        "CAUTIOUS",
        "FURIOUS",
        "IRRITATE",
        "REGAIN",
        "TIRESOME",
        "CONCEAL",
        "ASSEMBLE",
        "DISTANT",
        "HURDLE",
        "PACE",
        "REQUEST",
        "BANDIT",
        "ERUPT",
        "LASH",
        "PECULIAR",
        "SOB",
        "BLUSH",
        "EXAMINE",
        "METHOD",
        "POSE",
        "SPLENDID",
        "DEFEND",
        "EXPIRE",
        "MISTREAT",
        "QUANTITY",
        "SWIFT",
        "DISGRACE",
        "GRIME",
        "NUMEROUS",
        "RELY"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "They want to",
          "part2": "a new office building next to the park.",
          "answer": "construct"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The dull man made a long and",
          "part2": "speech about something no one was interested in.",
          "answer": "tiresome"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The students were told to",
          "part2": "all unnecessary words from their compositions.",
          "answer": "eliminate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The police",
          "part2": "the report that the store had been broken into.",
          "answer": "investigated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They wanted",
          "part2": "peace. They never wanted the world to be at war again.",
          "answer": "permanent"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His lack of experience was a serious",
          "part2": "for him when he started the job.",
          "answer": "handicap"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His constant talking",
          "part2": "everyone, so we told him to be quiet.",
          "answer": "irritated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Our club has several",
          "part2": "which all members must obey.",
          "answer": "regulations"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They",
          "part2": "him into changing jobs by promising him a large increase in salary.",
          "answer": "baited"
        },
        {
          "part1": "You must be",
          "part2": "when you use that knife. It is very sharp and you might hurt someone.",
          "answer": "cautious"
        },
        {
          "part1": "When I saw the angry crowd, I felt that my best bet was to",
          "part2": "to the safety of the police station.",
          "answer": "retreat"
        },
        {
          "part1": "When she realized she had breathed in harmful fumes, she",
          "part2": "quickly.",
          "answer": "exhaled"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Alice was so",
          "part2": "she shouted and raged for half an hour.",
          "answer": "furious"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She has been involved in several car accidents and has been arrested many times for",
          "part2": "driving.",
          "answer": "reckless"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Our car was searched at the",
          "part2": "between France and Germany.",
          "answer": "border"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He",
          "part2": "the secret paper behind a loose brick in the fireplace.",
          "answer": "concealed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The plane climbed to a higher",
          "part2": "to avoid the storm clouds.",
          "answer": "altitude"
        },
        {
          "part1": "This is the perfect",
          "part2": "to ask the teacher to let us leave school early.",
          "answer": "opportunity"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The former champion",
          "part2": "his title after someone else had had it for a year.",
          "answer": "regained"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Since you are our class president, you will",
          "part2": "us at the national meeting of student leaders.",
          "answer": "represent"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We thought the broken glass was a real",
          "part2": ", so we swept it up and threw it away.",
          "answer": "hazard"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The entire group was told to",
          "part2": "at eight o'clock outside the gym.",
          "answer": "assemble"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It was quite a(n)",
          "part2": "for the school to rank last in the state in reading ability.",
          "answer": "disgrace"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The little boy started to",
          "part2": "when he realized he was lost.",
          "answer": "sob"
        },
        {
          "part1": "This dress comes in",
          "part2": "sizes; I'm sure one of them will fit you.",
          "answer": "numerous"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We thought it was a(n)",
          "part2": "movie. All of us loved it.",
          "answer": "splendid"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He's acting very",
          "part2": "this morning. Why is he doing such strange things?",
          "answer": "peculiar"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It takes a larger",
          "part2": "of food to feed a big dog than a small cat.",
          "answer": "quantity"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The map said the treasure was buried seven",
          "part2": "from the rock.",
          "answer": "paces"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Many people died when the volcano",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "erupted"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Our confidence in her has never been misplaced; we can",
          "part2": "on her to do exactly what she is told to do.",
          "answer": "rely"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Everyone admired her graceful",
          "part2": "in the painting.",
          "answer": "pose"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She pointed to the bruises on her arm to show how she had been",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "mistreated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "In that country criminals are sometimes",
          "part2": "with whips.",
          "answer": "lashed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Three masked",
          "part2": "held up a liquor store today and escaped with five hundred dollars.",
          "answer": "bandits"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He",
          "part2": "whenever people compliment him. It embarrasses him a great deal.",
          "answer": "blushes"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The bank turned down his",
          "part2": "for a loan.",
          "answer": "request"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The soldiers could no longer",
          "part2": "the city, so the citizens were moved out.",
          "answer": "defend"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The next house was so",
          "part2": "from them that it took an hour to drive there.",
          "answer": "distant"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The deer",
          "part2": "the stream with a mighty bound.",
          "answer": "hurdled"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The electrician",
          "part2": "the wires and said they were very dangerous.",
          "answer": "examined"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Everyone has a different",
          "part2": "for cleaning the house.",
          "answer": "method"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Our insurance policy will",
          "part2": "next month unless we decide to renew it.",
          "answer": "expire"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The runner was so",
          "part2": "that he won the race easily.",
          "answer": "swift"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The mechanic's hands were covered with a thick layer of",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "grime"
        }
      ]
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "1.7",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Talk about the TRAGEDY.",
          "answers": [
            "story",
            "crime",
            "excitement",
            "victory",
            "disaster"
          ],
          "word": "TRAGEDY",
          "correct": "disaster"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Which PORTION is yours?",
          "answers": [
            "share",
            "drink",
            "seat",
            "one",
            "room"
          ],
          "word": "PORTION",
          "correct": "share"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He INTERRUPTED the conversation.",
          "answers": [
            "lost track of",
            "started",
            "overheard",
            "broke in on",
            "tired of"
          ],
          "word": "INTERRUPT",
          "correct": "broke in on"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Near the MOUND.",
          "answers": [
            "ocean",
            "hole",
            "cliff",
            "grave",
            "pile"
          ],
          "word": "MOUND",
          "correct": "pile"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Aware of the STRESS.",
          "answers": [
            "time",
            "pressure",
            "loss",
            "danger",
            "calmness"
          ],
          "word": "STRESS",
          "correct": "pressure"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Will he INTRUDE?",
          "answers": [
            "go home",
            "give up",
            "come uninvited",
            "arrive late",
            "object"
          ],
          "word": "INTRUDE",
          "correct": "come uninvited"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He NEGLECTED to write.",
          "answers": [
            "promised",
            "failed",
            "remembered",
            "hoped",
            "hated"
          ],
          "word": "NEGLECT",
          "correct": "failed"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Without any OBJECTION.",
          "answers": [
            "purpose",
            "support",
            "protest",
            "alarm",
            "effort"
          ],
          "word": "OBJECTION",
          "correct": "protest"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They RECOMMEND caution.",
          "answers": [
            "ignore",
            "reward",
            "demand",
            "promise",
            "advise"
          ],
          "word": "RECOMMEND",
          "correct": "advise"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there any POSSIBILITY?",
          "answers": [
            "trust",
            "chance",
            "truth",
            "hope",
            "need"
          ],
          "word": "POSSIBILITY",
          "correct": "chance"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Argued about the SOLUTION.",
          "answers": [
            "vote",
            "problem",
            "direction",
            "answer",
            "chapter"
          ],
          "word": "SOLUTION",
          "correct": "answer"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBSERVE his behavior.",
          "answers": [
            "note",
            "talk about",
            "copy",
            "hide",
            "improve"
          ],
          "word": "OBSERVE",
          "correct": "note"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LURED by gold.",
          "answers": [
            "attracted",
            "improved",
            "excited",
            "unaffected",
            "ruined"
          ],
          "word": "LURE",
          "correct": "attracted"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PURCHASE the car.",
          "answers": [
            "park",
            "steal",
            "buy",
            "keep",
            "sell"
          ],
          "word": "PURCHASE",
          "correct": "buy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They looked very SNUG.",
          "answers": [
            "confident",
            "happy",
            "uneasy",
            "sleepy",
            "comfortable"
          ],
          "word": "SNUG",
          "correct": "comfortable"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Does a TRAGEDY have a happy ending?",
          "word": "TRAGEDY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are some PORTIONS larger than others?",
          "word": "PORTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you INTERRUPT a meeting?",
          "word": "MOUND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a MOUND always huge?",
          "word": "INTERRUPT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a person who is under a lot of STRESS usually be carefree and happy?",
          "word": "STRESS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do invited guests INTRUDE?",
          "word": "INTRUDE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do businesses like people to NEGLECT to pay their bills?",
          "word": "NEGLECT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people OBJECT to receiving a present?",
          "word": "OBJECTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would you RECOMMEND buying a phone that doesn't work?",
          "word": "RECOMMEND",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it POSSIBLE to see something that is invisible?",
          "word": "POSSIBILITY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people like to get the right SOLUTION to a problem?",
          "word": "SOLUTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do Americans OBSERVE the Fourth of July as a holiday?",
          "word": "OBSERVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a movie theater LURE customers by showing terrible movies?",
          "word": "LURE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does it take money to PURCHASE most things?",
          "word": "PURCHASE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a person caught outside in a snowstorm feel SNUG?",
          "word": "SNUG",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "She is so tender-hearted that even the death of an ant strikes her as TRAGIC.",
          "word": "TRAGEDY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Please read the PORTION of the story starting on page 35 and ending on page",
          "word": "PORTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "After the program was over it was INTERRUPTED.",
          "word": "INTERRUPT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The child made a MOUND of rocks at the beach.",
          "word": "MOUND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The doctor STRESSED the importance of keeping fit.",
          "word": "STRESS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She put the \"Do Not Disturb\" sign on her door to prevent any INTRUSIONS.",
          "word": "INTRUDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He NEGLECTED some of the small details and concentrated on the important problems.",
          "word": "NEGLECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Their OBJECTION was to make it to the top of the mountain before dark.",
          "word": "OBJECTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They RECOMMENDED that we leave early if we wanted to get to the show on time.",
          "word": "RECOMMEND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We thought that there was no POSSIBILITY that we could lose the game.",
          "word": "POSSIBILITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her SOLUTION for any problem was to forget about it.",
          "word": "SOLUTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He OBSERVED that the days got longer in the springtime.",
          "word": "OBSERVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We put some food at the bottom of the tree to LURE the kitten down.",
          "word": "LURE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Because he needed money, Tom was forced to PURCHASE his car.",
          "word": "PURCHASE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She was quite SNUG in her comfortable chair by the fireplace.",
          "word": "SNUG",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "TRAGEDY",
          "answers": [
            "misfortune",
            "danger",
            "sorrow"
          ],
          "word": "TRAGEDY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PORTION",
          "answers": [
            "all",
            "some",
            "most"
          ],
          "word": "PORTION",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTERRUPT",
          "answers": [
            "hear",
            "stop",
            "break"
          ],
          "word": "MOUND",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MOUND",
          "answers": [
            "pile",
            "mountain",
            "hill"
          ],
          "word": "INTERRUPT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STRESS",
          "answers": [
            "quality",
            "importance",
            "pressure"
          ],
          "word": "STRESS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTRUDE",
          "answers": [
            "refuse",
            "enter",
            "bother"
          ],
          "word": "INTRUDE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NEGLECT",
          "answers": [
            "wonder",
            "forget",
            "miss"
          ],
          "word": "NEGLECT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBJECTION",
          "answers": [
            "disagreement",
            "insult",
            "opposition"
          ],
          "word": "OBJECTION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECOMMEND",
          "answers": [
            "speak",
            "praise",
            "suggest"
          ],
          "word": "RECOMMEND",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "POSSIBILITY",
          "answers": [
            "likelihood",
            "chance",
            "refusal"
          ],
          "word": "POSSIBILITY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SOLUTION",
          "answers": [
            "decision",
            "answer",
            "test"
          ],
          "word": "SOLUTION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBSERVE",
          "answers": [
            "see",
            "say",
            "hear"
          ],
          "word": "OBSERVE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LURE",
          "answers": [
            "attract",
            "tempt",
            "attack"
          ],
          "word": "LURE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PURCHASE",
          "answers": [
            "see",
            "get",
            "buy"
          ],
          "word": "PURCHASE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SNUG",
          "answers": [
            "warm",
            "tight",
            "sleepy"
          ],
          "word": "SNUG",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "TRAGEDY": {
        "word": "TRAGEDY",
        "phonetic": "(traj'-ÔøΩdE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a disaster, calamity, misfortune \nA TRAGEDY is a very sad event that usually ends in some kind of misfortune or disaster. Originally, a TRAGEDY was a play that ended very unhappily, the opposite of _comedy_. Now, in addition to being a play or book with a sad ending, a TRAGEDY is any kind of disaster that can happen to a person. \n\"We were all saddened by the TRAGEDY of the president's death.\" \n\"He acted as if it were a TRAGEDY that he couldn't have the car that evening.\" \nThe adjective from TRAGEDY is TRAGIC, which means _very sad_, _unfortunate_. \n\"The once famous star died in TRAGIC circumstances.\" \n\"He has such a low, sad voice that everything he says sounds TRAGIC.\" \nOther forms of the word: TRAGIC, adj."
      },
      "PORTION": {
        "word": "PORTION",
        "phonetic": "(por'-shJn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a share, part \nA PORTION is a part or share in something. \n\"I think that his PORTION of the money is larger than mine.\" \n\"Each child received a PORTION of the marbles.\" \nThe word is often used about food, meaning \"the share of the food given to one person.\" \n\"The restaurant gave them such large PORTIONS that no one could finish.\""
      },
      "MOUND": {
        "word": "MOUND",
        "phonetic": "(mownd)",
        "pos": "n",
        "deftext": "a pile, heap, small hill \nA MOUND is a small pile. The word is often used about piled-up earth. \n\"The small MOUND in the backyard made them think something might be buried there.\" \nMOUND can also be used about anything that is piled up. \n\"There was a MOUND of dishes in the sink.\" \n\"He had a MOUND of dirty clothes in his room.\""
      },
      "INTERRUPT": {
        "word": "INTERRUPT",
        "phonetic": "(in-tÔøΩruhpt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to break in on, break off \nTo INTERRUPT someone is to break in on him while he is doing or saying something, so that he has to stop. \n\"She kept INTERRUPTING the teacher to ask silly questions.\" \n\"I locked the door of my room so that I wouldn't be INTERRUPTED while I was studying.\" \nYou can also INTERRUPT things like programs. \n\"They INTERRUPTED the program to give a special news bulletin.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTERRUPTION, n."
      },
      "STRESS": {
        "word": "STRESS",
        "phonetic": "(stres)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "pressure, emphasis \nSTRESS is a noun and a verb. It has several different uses, all having to do with pressure or importance put on something. STRESS can mean _importance_ or _emphasis_. \n\"They place too much STRESS on having a winning football team at that school.\" \nIt is the _force_ with which a particular word is spoken. \n\"He always STRESSED the first word in the sentence.\" \nSTRESS is also mental or emotional pressure. \n\"With all her problems, she has been under a lot of STRESS lately.\" \n_Danger_ is often chosen as a meaning of STRESS on the Pretest. _Danger_ might cause STRESS in the sense of mental pressure, but the words have different meanings."
      },
      "INTRUDE": {
        "word": "INTRUDE",
        "phonetic": "(in-trUd')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to enter or come uninvited, trespass \nTo INTRUDE is to force yourself into a place where you are not welcome. \n\"I hope I'm not INTRUDING on you, but I'd like to talk with you for a few minutes.\" \n\"People are always INTRUDING on my privacy.\" \nOther things besides people can INTRUDE. \n\"The noises INTRUDED on my thoughts.\" \nAn INTRUSION is an act of INTRUDING. \n\"I was annoyed at these constant INTRUSIONS.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTRUDER, n. INTRUSION, n. INTRUSIVE, adj. Usage: INTRUDE is usually followed by _on_ or _upon_."
      },
      "NEGLECT": {
        "word": "NEGLECT",
        "phonetic": "(ni-glekt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to fail to do, overlook, forget \nTo NEGLECT to do something is to fail to do it, either purposely or not. \n\"Bill NEGLECTED to follow the instructions, and as a result he did it all wrong.\" \n\"Mary's mother got mad at her when she NEGLECTED to make her bed.\" \nIn a slightly different use, to NEGLECT something is to fail to pay proper attention to it, to ignore it. \n\"They NEGLECTED their homework in order to watch television.\" \n\"Sally's parents were so busy with other matters that they often NEGLECTED her.\" \nOther forms of the word: NEGLECTFUL, adj."
      },
      "OBJECTION": {
        "word": "OBJECTION",
        "phonetic": "(ob-jek'-shÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a protest \nTo OBJECT to something is to speak in opposition to it. \n\"I OBJECT to the way you keep calling me a child. I'm practically an adult.\" \nAn OBJECTION is something said in opposition, disagreement, or refusal. \n\"When we asked if we could go, he said he had no OBJECTION.\" \n\"Their OBJECTION to our plan was that it would cost too much money.\" \n\"I raised a strong OBJECTION to the idea of starting the game later.\" \nOther forms of the word: OBJECT, v."
      },
      "RECOMMEND": {
        "word": "RECOMMEND",
        "phonetic": "(rek-ÔøΩmend')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to speak favorably of, advise, suggest \nTo RECOMMEND is to speak favorably of, to say that someone or something is suited for a job or a purpose. \n\"I RECOMMEND him to you highly. He's perfect for the job.\" \n\"We RECOMMEND this paint for your house. It will last for years.\" \nWhen you RECOMMEND that someone do something, you suggest it as a good thing to do. \n\"The teacher RECOMMENDS that Susan watch less television and study more.\" \n\"The doctor RECOMMENDS that you stay in bed today.\" \nOther forms of the word: RECOMMENDATION, n."
      },
      "POSSIBILITY": {
        "word": "POSSIBILITY",
        "phonetic": "(pos-ÔøΩbil'-ÔøΩtE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "chance, likelihood \nSomething that is POSSIBLE can be done or can happen. \n\"It is POSSIBLE that we will all pass the test.\" \nPOSSIBILITY is the state of being POSSIBLE. If there is a POSSIBILITY of something happening, we are not sure that it will happen, but it may happen. \n\"There is a POSSIBILITY that it will rain tomorrow.\" \n\"Is there any POSSIBILITY that you will be here early?\" \nOther forms of the word: POSSIBLE, adj."
      },
      "SOLUTION": {
        "word": "SOLUTION",
        "phonetic": "(sÔøΩIU'-shÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an answer, explanation \nSOLUTION is the noun from the verb to solve. A SOLUTION is the answer to a problem or the explanation of a difficulty or a mystery. \n\"Everyone has suggestions about how to find the SOLUTION to the unemployment problem.\" \n\"Tom spent hours puzzling over the question without success, but Richard saw the SOLUTION immediately.\" \n\"A fight is not the best SOLUTION for a disagreement.\""
      },
      "OBSERVE": {
        "word": "OBSERVE",
        "phonetic": "(ob-zerv')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to note, notice, watch carefully; to pay attention to; to remark, comment \nOBSERVE has several common meanings. To OBSERVE something is to watch it carefully, to take notice of it. \n\"He OBSERVED them walking down the street just before dawn.\" \n\"She OBSERVED that the animals in the zoo didn't like the new lights.\" \nTo OBSERVE a rule is to follow it. To OBSERVE a holiday is to celebrate it. To OBSERVE also means \"to say by way of a comment.\" \n\" 'I think they're getting tired,' Mary OBSERVED, as she watched the children play.\" \nOther forms of the word: OBSERVANCE, n. OBSERVATION, n. OBSERVATORY, n."
      },
      "LURE": {
        "word": "LURE",
        "phonetic": "(IUr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to tempt, attract, entice \nOriginally, a LURE was a bunch of feathers roughly resembling a bird which was used to attract and recall a trained hawk from its flight. From this the word came to be used about anything that attracts or tempts someone. \n\"The LURE of the sea has drawn many men away from their homes.\" \nTo LURE therefore means to attract or tempt. \n\"The football game on TV LURED them away from their homework.\" \n\"The hope of becoming rich LURED many people to California during the Gold Rush.\" \nThe artificial bait used by fishers is also called a LURE."
      },
      "PURCHASE": {
        "word": "PURCHASE",
        "phonetic": "(per'-chÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to buy \nTo PURCHASE something is to buy it. \n\"We always PURCHASE our groceries at the supermarket.\" \n\"He went to the city to PURCHASE a ring.\" \n\"Money can't PURCHASE love.\" \nPURCHASE is also a noun, meaning \"something that is bought.\" \n\"She put all her PURCHASES into one bag.\" \nMost people who get this item wrong think PURCHASE means sell, which is the exact opposite of the correct meaning."
      },
      "SNUG": {
        "word": "SNUG",
        "phonetic": "(snuhg)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "comfortable, cozy, warm \nSNUG was originally used about ships that are neat and well-prepared for bad weather. To be SNUG now means to be _comfortable_, especially to be warm and dry and protected from the weather. \n\"She felt very SNUG in her warm bed as she listened to the wind howl outside.\" \nSNUG is also used about places and things that make us feel comfortable. \n\"As he shoveled snow he wished he were back in his SNUG little room sitting by the fireplace.\" \nIn a different sense, SNUG means closely fitting, tight. \n\"This coat is a bit SNUG. Perhaps I should try on a larger size.\""
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "1.8",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Her real AFFECTION.",
          "answers": [
            "reason",
            "goal",
            "hatred",
            "love",
            "opinion"
          ],
          "word": "AFFECTION",
          "correct": "love"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MODERN drama.",
          "answers": [
            "nearby",
            "present-day",
            "first-class",
            "difficult",
            "old"
          ],
          "word": "MODERN",
          "correct": "present-day"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He took the DUPLICATE.",
          "answers": [
            "document",
            "picture",
            "copy",
            "next one",
            "original"
          ],
          "word": "DUPLICATE",
          "correct": "copy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Never HESITATED.",
          "answers": [
            "began",
            "hurried",
            "paused",
            "worried",
            "changed"
          ],
          "word": "HESITATE",
          "correct": "paused"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FLING the ball.",
          "answers": [
            "drop",
            "hit",
            "hold on to",
            "throw",
            "run with"
          ],
          "word": "FLING",
          "correct": "throw"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A COMICAL story.",
          "answers": [
            "sad",
            "new",
            "true",
            "stupid",
            "funny"
          ],
          "word": "COMICAL",
          "correct": "funny"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OVERCAST days.",
          "answers": [
            "cold",
            "cloudy",
            "windy",
            "sunny",
            "rainy"
          ],
          "word": "OVERCAST",
          "correct": "cloudy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Little PERSPIRATION.",
          "answers": [
            "smell",
            "dryness",
            "effort",
            "warmth",
            "sweat"
          ],
          "word": "PERSPIRATION",
          "correct": "sweat"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He often CHUCKLES.",
          "answers": [
            "gives up",
            "dresses up",
            "tells jokes",
            "laughs quietly",
            "frowns"
          ],
          "word": "CHUCKLE",
          "correct": "laughs quietly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He NUDGED his brother.",
          "answers": [
            "attacked",
            "hated",
            "tripped",
            "touched",
            "defeated"
          ],
          "word": "NUDGE",
          "correct": "touched"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GLOSSY appearance.",
          "answers": [
            "dull",
            "hard",
            "valuable",
            "shiny",
            "dark"
          ],
          "word": "GLOSSY",
          "correct": "shiny"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Remembered the DISTRICT.",
          "answers": [
            "area",
            "house",
            "decision",
            "street",
            "government"
          ],
          "word": "DISTRICT",
          "correct": "area"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The IDENTICAL marks.",
          "answers": [
            "close",
            "same",
            "slanted",
            "different",
            "clear"
          ],
          "word": "IDENTICAL",
          "correct": "same"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To CALCULATE the bill.",
          "answers": [
            "ignore",
            "pass around",
            "compute",
            "notice",
            "pay"
          ],
          "word": "CALCULATE",
          "correct": "compute"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Upset by their ATTENDANCE.",
          "answers": [
            "absence",
            "treatment",
            "position",
            "opinion",
            "presence"
          ],
          "word": "ATTENDANCE",
          "correct": "presence"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do people ordinarily show their AFFECTION by kicking each other?",
          "word": "AFFECTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is the wheel a MODERN invention?",
          "word": "MODERN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If something is unique, does it have any DUPLICATES?",
          "word": "DUPLICATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a person HESITATE while he is writing?",
          "word": "HESITATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you FLING a refrigerator very far?",
          "word": "FLING",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a clown COMICAL?",
          "word": "COMICAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If the sky is OVERCAST, is it sunny?",
          "word": "OVERCAST",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people PERSPIRE more when it's cold than when it is hot?",
          "word": "PERSPIRATION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a sad story cause people to CHUCKLE?",
          "word": "CHUCKLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a NUDGE softer than a punch?",
          "word": "NUDGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a concrete sidewalk GLOSSY?",
          "word": "GLOSSY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a DISTRICT be very large?",
          "word": "DISTRICT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a five dollar bill IDENTICAL to a ten dollar bill?",
          "word": "IDENTICAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a tree CALCULATE?",
          "word": "CALCULATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you ATTEND a play that you've never seen before?",
          "word": "ATTENDANCE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "She comes from a very AFFECTIONATE family; the children never leave the house without first kissing their mother.",
          "word": "AFFECTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was a very MODERN idea; no one would have thought such a thing a few years ago.",
          "word": "MODERN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She DUPLICATED to us about her report card; she had really failed two courses.",
          "word": "DUPLICATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Sally HESITATED for several minutes before she agreed.",
          "word": "HESITATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "How far can you FLING that stone?",
          "word": "FLING",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The teacher became very COMICAL and yelled at us for being late.",
          "word": "COMICAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I feel as gloomy as the weather when the sky is OVERCAST.",
          "word": "OVERCAST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The PERSPIRATION soaked through his shirt as he struggled to lift the boxes.",
          "word": "PERSPIRATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He CHUCKLED as he remembered the jokes the comedian had told.",
          "word": "CHUCKLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He pushed it with all his might but it didn't NUDGE.",
          "word": "NUDGE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "This new shampoo is supposed to make your hair GLOSSY.",
          "word": "GLOSSY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She lived in a rundown shack in the poor DISTRICT of town.",
          "word": "DISTRICT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She wore the IDENTICAL wedding gown that her mother had worn thirty years ago.",
          "word": "IDENTICAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Jim CALCULATED the distance from the Earth to the moon.",
          "word": "CALCULATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Because of the rain, the ATTENDANCE at the game was poor.",
          "word": "ATTENDANCE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "AFFECTION",
          "answers": [
            "love",
            "admiration",
            "obedience"
          ],
          "word": "AFFECTION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MODERN",
          "answers": [
            "young",
            "silly",
            "new"
          ],
          "word": "MODERN",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DUPLICATE",
          "answers": [
            "similar",
            "future",
            "twin"
          ],
          "word": "DUPLICATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HESITATE",
          "answers": [
            "pause",
            "decide",
            "wait"
          ],
          "word": "HESITATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FLING",
          "answers": [
            "toss",
            "hurl",
            "catch"
          ],
          "word": "FLING",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMICAL",
          "answers": [
            "breezy",
            "laughable",
            "joking"
          ],
          "word": "COMICAL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OVERCAST",
          "answers": [
            "cloudy",
            "windy",
            "foggy"
          ],
          "word": "OVERCAST",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PERSPIRATION",
          "answers": [
            "sweat",
            "rest",
            "work"
          ],
          "word": "PERSPIRATION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CHUCKLE",
          "answers": [
            "grin",
            "shout",
            "laugh"
          ],
          "word": "CHUCKLE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NUDGE",
          "answers": [
            "push",
            "touch",
            "run"
          ],
          "word": "NUDGE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GLOSSY",
          "answers": [
            "soft",
            "smooth",
            "shiny"
          ],
          "word": "GLOSSY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISTRICT",
          "answers": [
            "section",
            "house",
            "region"
          ],
          "word": "DISTRICT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IDENTICAL",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "exact",
            "similar"
          ],
          "word": "IDENTICAL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CALCULATE",
          "answers": [
            "think",
            "laugh",
            "count"
          ],
          "word": "CALCULATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ATTENDANCE",
          "answers": [
            "miss",
            "presence",
            "meeting"
          ],
          "word": "ATTENDANCE",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "AFFECTION": {
        "word": "AFFECTION",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩfek'-shÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "love, fondness \nAFFECTION is a warm feeling of fondness and tenderness. It is almost the same as love, although usually not quite as strong. \n\"He has a very real AFFECTION for his father.\" \n\"He felt little AFFECTION toward the town where he had grown up.\" \nThe adjective form of AFFECTION is AFFECTIONATE, which means _loving_ or _fond_. \n\"The teacher's AFFECTIONATE attitude toward the young children makes them like her in return.\" \n\"He gave the dog an AFFECTIONATE pat.\" \nOther forms of the word: AFFECTIONATE, adj."
      },
      "MODERN": {
        "word": "MODERN",
        "phonetic": "(mod'-ÔøΩrn)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "present-day, up-to-date \nMODERN means \n\"having to do with present or recent times.\" \n\"It is a MODERN building, built just a few years ago.\" \n\"Are people happier in MODERN times than they were in the past?\" \n\"She believes that anything that is MODERN is better than something that is old.\""
      },
      "DUPLICATE": {
        "word": "DUPLICATE",
        "phonetic": "(dU'-pli-kit)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a copy, double \nDUPLICATE is related to the word _double_. \nBoth come from a Latin word meaning _two_. A DUPLICATE is an exact copy of something. \n\"This machine can make several DUPLICATES of that letter in just a few seconds.\" \n\"The twins are exact DUPLICATES of each other; even their voices sound the same.\" \nDUPLICATE may also be used as an adjective. \n\"We have DUPLICATE keys to the car. We keep one set in the desk.\" \nAs a verb, the word means \"to make a copy of.\" \n\"She tried to DUPLICATE the teacher's movements.\" \n\"He DUPLICATED the directions for getting to his house and sent everyone a copy.\" \nOther forms of the word: DUPLICATION, n."
      },
      "HESITATE": {
        "word": "HESITATE",
        "phonetic": "(hez'-ÔøΩtAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to pause, delay for a moment \nTo HESITATE is to show signs of uncertainty by pausing or delaying for a short time. \n\"We could tell he had not studied enough from the way he HESITATED before he spelled each word.\" \n\"The cat HESITATED before stepping on the new- fallen snow.\" \n\"If you need anything, do not HESITATE to ask for it.\" \nHESITATION is the noun from HESITATE. It is the act of pausing or holding back. \n\"Midway through the actor's speech there were several long HESITATIONS, and it became obvious that he had forgotten his lines.\" \nOther forms of the word: HESITANT, adj. HESITATION, n."
      },
      "FLING": {
        "word": "FLING",
        "phonetic": "(fling)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to throw, hurl, cast \nFLING means just about the same as _throw_, but often adds a sense of force or violence to _throw_. \n\"Angrily he FLUNG the books across the room.\" \n\"Tom FLUNG the stone with all his might.\" \n\"The wrestler FLINGS his opponent to the ground.\" \nTo \"FLING your arms up in the air\" is to raise them suddenly and unexpectedly. Usage: The past tense of FLING is FLUNG."
      },
      "COMICAL": {
        "word": "COMICAL",
        "phonetic": "(kom'-i-kÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "funny, humorous, amusing \nCOMICAL means _funny_ or _amusing_. \n\"The puppy’s actions were so COMICAL that we burst out laughing.\" \n\"She entered the room with a COMICAL expression on her face, and we knew that something funny had happened.\" \n\"He tries to amuse us with COMICAL stories, but we don't think they're funny at all.\" \nThe noun form of COMICAL is COMIC. A COMIC is a person who amuses others by telling funny stories and jokes. Other forms of the word: COMIC, n."
      },
      "OVERCAST": {
        "word": "OVERCAST",
        "phonetic": "(O'-vÔøΩr-kast)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "cloudy, gloomy \nOVERCAST is used about clouds and the weather and means _clouded over_, _cloudy_. \n\"The sky was OVERCAST, and it looked as if it were going to rain.\" \n\"November was filled with cold, OVERCAST days.\" \nOVERCAST is also a noun. \n\"The few breaks in the OVERCAST convinced us that the weather was going to clear up.\" \nThe most popular incorrect answer on the Pretest is _rainy_. OVERCAST just means _cloudy_, however; when the sky is OVERCAST it might or might not rain."
      },
      "PERSPIRATION": {
        "word": "PERSPIRATION",
        "phonetic": "(per-spÔøΩ-rA'-shÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "sweat \nPERSPIRATION is a polite word for _sweat_. \"He was covered with PERSPIRATION after the 100-yard dash.\" \"The horse's PERSPIRATION looks like white foam.\" \"The room was so warm that everyone's face was shining with PERSPIRATION.\" The verb form is PERSPIRE. \"We PERSPIRED in the hot sunlight.\" \n_Effort_ is often chosen as the meaning of PERSPIRATION. _Effort_ might cause to sweat, but _effort_ and PERSPIRATION are not the same thing. Other forms of the word: PERSPIRE, v."
      },
      "CHUCKLE": {
        "word": "CHUCKLE",
        "phonetic": "(chuh'-kÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to laugh quietly \nTo CHUCKLE is to laugh, usually quietly or to yourself. \n\"He CHUCKLED while he read the funny story, and sometimes he laughed out loud.\" \n\"You're not supposed to CHUCKLE when Ken is talking to you even if you think he's funny.\" \nCHUCKLE is also used as a noun and means a laugh. \n\"We got a few CHUCKLES out of the show, but in general it wasn't very funny.\""
      },
      "NUDGE": {
        "word": "NUDGE",
        "phonetic": "(nuhj)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to touch or push gently \nTo NUDGE someone is to touch or push him slightly, in order to call attention to something or to get him to do something. \n\"She NUDGED him and pointed to her watch, letting him know it was time to go.\" \n\"We NUDGED Henry forward until he was at the front of the stage.\" \nNUDGE is also a noun. \n\"I gave him a NUDGE and told him to come with me.\""
      },
      "GLOSSY": {
        "word": "GLOSSY",
        "phonetic": "(glos'-E)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "smooth and shiny, highly polished \nThe GLOSS of something is its smooth, shining surface. \n\"Feel the GLOSS of this silk shirt.\" \nSomething which is GLOSSY has a smooth, shining surface. See _-y_ under Suffixes. \n\"He polished his car until the entire surface was GLOSSY.\" \n\"You could see your face reflected in his GLOSSY leather shoes.\" \nOther forms of the word: GLOSS, n."
      },
      "DISTRICT": {
        "word": "DISTRICT",
        "phonetic": "(dis'-trikt)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an area, region \nA DISTRICT is an area that has a special purpose or a special character that makes it different from other areas. It can be either large or small. \n\"In New York, the financial DISTRICT is centered around Wall Street.\" \n\"The DISTRICT where we live is marked off by rivers at either end.\" \n\"There isn't any high school in our DISTRICT, so we have to go into the city.\" \n\"Several DISTRICTS of the town were without electricity because of the storm last night.\" \nThe DISTRICT of Columbia is a special area that contains the capital of the United States."
      },
      "IDENTICAL": {
        "word": "IDENTICAL",
        "phonetic": "(1-den'-ti-kÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "same Two things that are IDENTICAL are the same; they are exactly alike and agree in every detail. IDENTICAL twins are twins who look exactly alike. \n\"This print is IDENTICAL to the one we saw in the art gallery two weeks ago.\" \n\"No two people have IDENTICAL fingerprints. Everyone's fingerprints are different.\""
      },
      "CALCULATE": {
        "word": "CALCULATE",
        "phonetic": "(kal'-kyÔøΩ-IAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to compute, count, figure \nCalculus was a Latin word for _pebble_. People used to use pebbles to help in adding or subtracting numbers. So to CALCULATE is to work with numbers, to _compute_. \"If we know how many miles we have to go, we can CALCULATE how long it will take.\" \n\"Jim's father CALCULATED the cost of sending him to college.\" \nPeople now often have CALCULATORS to do their CALCULATING for them. \n\"We are allowed to use our pocket CALCULATORS during the math test.\" \nCALCULATING is an adjective meaning _scheming_ or _acting ruthlessly_. \n\"We acquired the business thanks to her calculating efforts.\" \nAnother meaning of CALCULATE is to think or suppose from reasoning. \n\"I CALCULATED that Smith will win the election.\" \nOther forms of the word: CALCULATION, n. CALCULATING, adj. CALCULATOR, n."
      },
      "ATTENDANCE": {
        "word": "ATTENDANCE",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩ-ten'-dÔøΩns)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "presence \nTo ATTEND something is to be present at it. \n\"They ATTENDED church every Sunday.\" \nATTENDANCE is the noun from ATTEND. ATTENDANCE means the presence of one or more people at some place. \n\"We were surprised by the ATTENDANCE of Bill Johnson at Sam's funeral. They had been enemies for years.\" \n\"Seven pupils got certificates for perfect ATTENDANCE this year.\" \nATTENDANCE also means \"the number of persons who are present at something.\" \n\"School ATTENDANCE has gone down because fewer children are being born.\" \n\"There was a large ATTENDANCE at the concert.\" \nOther forms of the word: ATTEND, v."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "1.9",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Started to WILT.",
          "answers": [
            "fall",
            "droop",
            "stink",
            "grow",
            "lean"
          ],
          "word": "WILT",
          "correct": "droop"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Too many SPECTATORS.",
          "answers": [
            "athletes",
            "generals",
            "onlookers",
            "businessmen",
            "visitors"
          ],
          "word": "SPECTATOR",
          "correct": "onlookers"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were DURABLE.",
          "answers": [
            "distant",
            "lasting",
            "wonderful",
            "brief",
            "average"
          ],
          "word": "DURABLE",
          "correct": "lasting"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DIRECT path.",
          "answers": [
            "straight",
            "short",
            "first",
            "winding",
            "only"
          ],
          "word": "DIRECT",
          "correct": "straight"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Started to TRICKLE.",
          "answers": [
            "boil",
            "shine",
            "drip",
            "melt",
            "stick"
          ],
          "word": "TRICKLE",
          "correct": "drip"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONSIDER the results.",
          "answers": [
            "hear of",
            "throw away",
            "question",
            "believe",
            "think about"
          ],
          "word": "CONSIDER",
          "correct": "think about"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He PLUNGED in.",
          "answers": [
            "rowed",
            "stepped",
            "dived",
            "floated",
            "rolled"
          ],
          "word": "PLUNGE",
          "correct": "dived"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Another DELEGATE.",
          "answers": [
            "representative",
            "lawyer",
            "citizen",
            "spy",
            "gentleman"
          ],
          "word": "DELEGATE",
          "correct": "representative"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Were you CERTAIN?",
          "answers": [
            "sure",
            "right",
            "nearby",
            "worried",
            "present"
          ],
          "word": "CERTAIN",
          "correct": "sure"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Their AGONY.",
          "answers": [
            "delight",
            "heaviness",
            "hard decision",
            "great pain",
            "great danger"
          ],
          "word": "AGONY",
          "correct": "great pain"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Watched them SLUMP.",
          "answers": [
            "leap",
            "dance",
            "walk",
            "sag",
            "fall"
          ],
          "word": "SLUMP",
          "correct": "sag"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COURTEOUS act.",
          "answers": [
            "polite",
            "elegant",
            "royal",
            "rude",
            "planned"
          ],
          "word": "COURTEOUS",
          "correct": "polite"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Their prices may VARY.",
          "answers": [
            "go up",
            "be high",
            "come down",
            "be shocking",
            "change"
          ],
          "word": "VARY",
          "correct": "change"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEFINITE information.",
          "answers": [
            "never-ending",
            "exact",
            "important",
            "unclear",
            "useful"
          ],
          "word": "DEFINITE",
          "correct": "exact"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SCARCE animals.",
          "answers": [
            "common",
            "injured",
            "tiny",
            "rare",
            "frightening"
          ],
          "word": "SCARCE",
          "correct": "rare"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do flowers WILT if it doesn't rain for a long time?",
          "word": "WILT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If you go to watch a football game, are you a SPECTATOR?",
          "word": "SPECTATOR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are rocks DURABLE?",
          "word": "DURABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a curving road be a DIRECT route between two places?",
          "word": "DIRECT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can catsup TRICKLE?",
          "word": "TRICKLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would Los Angeles be CONSIDERED a large city?",
          "word": "CONSIDER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a diver PLUNGE into the water?",
          "word": "PLUNGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are DELEGATES sometimes elected?",
          "word": "DELEGATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you have to be CERTAIN of the answer before you ask a question?",
          "word": "CERTAIN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a severe burn cause AGONY?",
          "word": "AGONY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a soldier standing at attention SLUMP?",
          "word": "SLUMP",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it COURTEOUS to slam a door in someone's face?",
          "word": "COURTEOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you VARY the clothes you wear?",
          "word": "VARY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is \"No, you absolutely can't go\" a DEFINITE answer?",
          "word": "DEFINITE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is ice SCARCE at the South Pole?",
          "word": "SCARCE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Our excitement began to WILT when it began to appear that we really could win the championship.",
          "word": "WILT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The SPECTATOR ruled the country cruelly and unjustly.",
          "word": "SPECTATOR",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "What they did to him was DURABLE. They should be arrested.",
          "word": "DURABLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He went DIRECTLY to the school after leaving his home.",
          "word": "DIRECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We couldn't understand how the magician was able to TRICKLE us so easily.",
          "word": "TRICKLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He slowed down out of CONSIDERATION for the other people who couldn't walk that fast.",
          "word": "CONSIDER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The plane PLUNGED up into the air.",
          "word": "PLUNGE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The DELEGATES to the United Nations come from all over the world.",
          "word": "DELEGATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He thought it was a CERTAINTY that he would win the match, but he lost instead.",
          "word": "CERTAIN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Nothing could relieve his AGONY when his wife was killed.",
          "word": "AGONY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SLUMPED to the ground after being hit by the ball.",
          "word": "SLUMP",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The woman complained about the children's lack of COURTESY. None of them would even speak to her.",
          "word": "COURTEOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her feelings about school VARY; sometimes she likes it, and sometimes she doesn't.",
          "word": "VARY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He wanted some DEFINITE news, not just hints and rumors.",
          "word": "DEFINITE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "That summer there was such a SCARCITY of water that no one was allowed to take a bath.",
          "word": "SCARCE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "WILT",
          "answers": [
            "sink",
            "soften",
            "slump"
          ],
          "word": "WILT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SPECTATOR",
          "answers": [
            "watcher",
            "attendant",
            "player"
          ],
          "word": "SPECTATOR",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DURABLE",
          "answers": [
            "big",
            "strong",
            "tough"
          ],
          "word": "DURABLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DIRECT",
          "answers": [
            "straight",
            "unusual",
            "short"
          ],
          "word": "DIRECT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TRICKLE",
          "answers": [
            "gush",
            "flow",
            "drip"
          ],
          "word": "TRICKLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONSIDER",
          "answers": [
            "regard",
            "hope",
            "think"
          ],
          "word": "CONSIDER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PLUNGE",
          "answers": [
            "sink",
            "lose",
            "fall"
          ],
          "word": "PLUNGE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DELEGATE",
          "answers": [
            "represent",
            "chase",
            "entrust"
          ],
          "word": "DELEGATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CERTAIN",
          "answers": [
            "excellent",
            "sure",
            "confident"
          ],
          "word": "CERTAIN",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AGONY",
          "answers": [
            "danger",
            "suffering",
            "sorrow"
          ],
          "word": "AGONY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SLUMP",
          "answers": [
            "tire",
            "droop",
            "widen"
          ],
          "word": "SLUMP",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COURTEOUS",
          "answers": [
            "friendly",
            "smart",
            "helpful"
          ],
          "word": "COURTEOUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VARY",
          "answers": [
            "change",
            "wonder",
            "differ"
          ],
          "word": "VARY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEFINITE",
          "answers": [
            "possible",
            "sure",
            "clear"
          ],
          "word": "DEFINITE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SCARCE",
          "answers": [
            "little",
            "few",
            "none"
          ],
          "word": "SCARCE",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "WILT": {
        "word": "WILT",
        "phonetic": "(wilt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to droop, sag \nTo WILT is to _droop_, to lose freshness or spirit. The word is often used about plants or flowers. \n\"The lack of water caused many plants to WILT.\" \nThe word can also be used in a more general sense. \n\"Our enthusiasm for the trip started to WILT when we found out how much it was going to cost.\" \n\"The witness's confidence WILTED under the harsh questioning of the lawyer.\" \n\"Our team started well, but WILTED late in the game.\""
      },
      "SPECTATOR": {
        "word": "SPECTATOR",
        "phonetic": "(spek'-tA-tÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an onlooker, viewer, watcher \nThe form _spect_ is seen in many words and always means to _see_ or to _look at_. Some examples are: _spectacles_ (eyeglasses); _inspect_ (to examine carefully); and _spectacular_ (wonderful to look at). A SPECTATOR is someone who is looking on at what is happening; he does not take part in the event, but simply watches it. \n\"The SPECTATORS were amused by the clown.\" \n\"We were unwilling SPECTATORS of the robbery.\" \n\"The SPECTATORS at the tennis match cheered the winner.\""
      },
      "DURABLE": {
        "word": "DURABLE",
        "phonetic": "(dur'-ÔøΩ-bÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "lasting, enduring, permanent, strong See _-able_ under Suffixes. The _dur_ part of the word comes from a Latin word meaning to _last_. It is also found in the English word _endure_. Something that is DURABLE is able to last. It won't break or fall apart easily. \n\"These toys are DURABLE. Your child will use them for years.\" \n\"He was a DURABLE athlete. He never missed a game because of injury.\" \n\"The can opener wasn't very DURABLE. If you dropped it on the floor it would need to be repaired.\" \nOther forms of the word: DURABILITY, n."
      },
      "DIRECT": {
        "word": "DIRECT",
        "phonetic": "(di-rekt')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "straight, straightforward \nDIRECT means _straight_, \"going from one point to another by the shortest path.\" \n\"We wanted to take the DIRECT route to the beach, but he wanted to drive all over the place and see the sights.\" \n\"Go DIRECTLY home. Don't stop anywhere.\" \nDIRECT is also used about other things besides routes and distances, but it has the same general meaning. \n\"The accident was a DIRECT result of your carelessness.\" \n\"Don't beat around the bush. I want a DIRECT answer.\" \nOther forms of the word: DIRECTION, n."
      },
      "TRICKLE": {
        "word": "TRICKLE",
        "phonetic": "(trik'-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to drip, flow slowly \nTRICKLE means to _drip_ or _flow slowly_. It is used about water, blood, oil, or other liquids. \"Blood was TRICKLING out of his mouth.\" \n\"The water TRICKLED out of the faucet.\" \nTRICKLE can also be used about other things that can be said to flow. \n\"The sugar TRICKLED through her fingers.\" \n\"The students TRICKLED out of the classroom.\" \nTRICKLE is also a noun. \n\"She wiped the TRICKLE of blood from his lips.\" \n_Melt_ is often chosen as the meaning of TRICKLE on the Pretest. Something like an ice cube may TRICKLE as it melts, but things that are not melting may TRICKLE as well."
      },
      "CONSIDER": {
        "word": "CONSIDER",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-sid'-ÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to think about \nTo CONSIDER means to _think about_ in some way. \n\"You must CONSIDER how your father will feel if you do that.\" \n\"I've never CONSIDERED him stupid, just a little slow-moving.\" \nCONSIDERATION is the act of CONSIDERING. \n\"You should take into CONSIDERATION the fact that she's only two years old.\" \nIn a different sense, CONSIDERATION means _thoughtfulness_. \n\"He showed great CONSIDERATION for his parents by always letting them know when he expected to be back.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONSIDERATION, n. CONSIDERATE, adj."
      },
      "PLUNGE": {
        "word": "PLUNGE",
        "phonetic": "(pluhnj)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to dive, submerge, dip \nTo PLUNGE is to dive down into something such as water or a hole. \n\"The kite PLUNGED into the lake.\" \n\"Alice lost her balance and PLUNGED into the well.\" \nTo PLUNGE something is to thrust it, throw it, or cause it to fall into something. \n\"He PLUNGED the shovel into the ground.\" \n\"She turned out the lights and PLUNGED the room into darkness.\" \n\"The stock market crash PLUNGED the nation into a depression.\" \nThe most commonly chosen incorrect answer is _step_. To _step_ into something is also to go into it, but PLUNGE suggests a much more complete and sudden movement."
      },
      "DELEGATE": {
        "word": "DELEGATE",
        "phonetic": "(del'-ÔøΩgAt)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a representative, deputy \nA DELEGATE is a person who has the power to act for someone else. The word is often used about people elected to represent a group at a convention or conference. \n\"The DELEGATES met to vote on the party's position on these matters.\" \n\"Each class in the school elected a DELEGATE to represent it in the student government.\" \nDELEGATE is also a verb meaning \"to appoint as a representative.\" \n\"We DELEGATED Jim to be the spokesperson for the club.\" \nDELEGATE can also mean to _entrust_ or _assign_. \n\"He DELEGATED complete authority to us to act as we saw fit in this matter.\" \nOther forms of the word: DELEGATION, n."
      },
      "CERTAIN": {
        "word": "CERTAIN",
        "phonetic": "(sert'-ÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "sure \nIf something is CERTAIN, it is sure; there is no doubt about it. Both people and things can be CERTAIN. \n\"Gloria is CERTAIN that it will be sunny on the day of the picnic.\" \n\"A CERTAIN cure for hiccups is to hold your breath.\" \n\"There is no CERTAIN way to prevent war from breaking out.\" \nThe noun form of CERTAIN is CERTAINTY. A CERTAINTY is an outcome or result that is sure; there is no doubt about it. \n\"He was assured of winning; it was a CERTAINTY that he would come in first.\" \nMany people confuse CERTAIN with _right_. You can be CERTAIN of something, though, and be wrong. Other forms of the word: CERTAINTY, n."
      },
      "AGONY": {
        "word": "AGONY",
        "phonetic": "(ag'-ÔøΩnE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "great pain, torment \nAGONY is great pain or suffering, either of the mind or of the body. \n\"Her headaches caused her constant AGONY.\" \n\"He felt extreme AGONY when he saw the results of his careless driving.\" \n\"She looked on in AGONY as the soldiers took away all her possessions.\" \nTo AGONIZE is to suffer AGONY. \n\"Susan AGONIZED over her hopeless situation, but couldn't do anything about it.\" \nOther forms of the word: AGONIZE, v. \nAGONIZED, adj. \nAGONIZING, adj."
      },
      "SLUMP": {
        "word": "SLUMP",
        "phonetic": "(sluhmp)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to sag, droop, slouch \nSLUMP means \"to drop down heavily,\" to _sag_ or _slouch_. \n\"His shoulders SLUMPED under the weight of the pack he carried.\" \nSomeone who SLUMPS is often tired. \n\"He staggered into the room and SLUMPED down into a chair.\" \nSLUMP is sometimes used of other things besides people. \n\"The ice cream business always SLUMPS during the cold weather.\" \nSLUMP is also a noun. \n\"There has been a SLUMP in the price of corn.\""
      },
      "COURTEOUS": {
        "word": "COURTEOUS",
        "phonetic": "(ker'-tE-:;is)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "polite, well-mannered \nTo be COURTEOUS is to be polite, to have good manners. \n\"The COURTEOUS boy held the door open for his mother.\" \n\"Even though he was very angry at the rude question, he managed to give a COURTEOUS answer.\" \n\"With a COURTEOUS smile, she stepped aside to let the woman with all the packages get on the bus first.\" \nThe noun form of COURTEOUS is COURTESY, which means _politeness_ or _polite behavior_. \n\"She showed great COURTESY to the unexpected visitor, although she was tired and wanted to go to bed.\" \nOther forms of the word: COURTESY, n."
      },
      "VARY": {
        "word": "VARY",
        "phonetic": "(vair'-E)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to change, become different \nWhen something VARIES it becomes different. \n\"The colors of the sky at sunset VARY from minute to minute.\" \nTo VARY something is to make it different, to change it. \n\"She never VARIES her hairstyle; she has always worn it short and curly.\" \n\"He tried to VARY the way he taught the class so that his students wouldn't get bored.\" \nAn adjective form of VARY is VARIABLE, which means _changeable_. \n\"The forecast for today says that there will be VARIABLE winds and sunny skies.\" \nOther forms of the word: VARIABLE, adj. VARIOUS, adj."
      },
      "DEFINITE": {
        "word": "DEFINITE",
        "phonetic": "(def'-ÔøΩnit)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "exact, clear, precise \nWhatever is clear, exact, and leaves no room for doubt is DEFINITE. \n\"We have made DEFINITE plans to leave on Saturday morning.\" \n\"Can you be more DEFINITE about the place where I'm supposed to meet you? So far you've been rather vague.\" \n\"He made a DEFINITE promise to help us.\" The adverb form, DEFINITELY, is often used to mean _surely_, _positively_, _precisely_. \n\"He DEFINITELY has a hearing problem. Three separate ear examinations have confirmed it.\" \n\"I will DEFINITELY be there by ten o'clock.\""
      },
      "SCARCE": {
        "word": "SCARCE",
        "phonetic": "(skÔøΩrs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "rare, not enough, uncommon \nWhen something is SCARCE, it is rare or in very short supply. There is hardly any of it. \n\"Before these animals were protected by law, they were becoming very SCARCE.\" \n\"When food gets SCARCE, the price goes up.\" \n\"During the strike, steel became very SCARCE in some parts of the country.\" \nThe noun from SCARCE is SCARCITY, which means a _short supply_ of something. \n\"There were long lines at gasoline stations because of the SCARCITY of fuel.\" \nOther forms of the word: SCARCITY, n."
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "AFFECTION",
        "DISTRICT",
        "LURE",
        "OBSERVE",
        "SLUMP",
        "CERTAIN",
        "FLING",
        "MOUND",
        "OVERCAST",
        "SPECTATOR",
        "CONSIDER",
        "HESITATE",
        "NEGLECT",
        "PLUNGE",
        "TRICKLE",
        "COURTEOUS",
        "INTERRUPT",
        "NUDGE",
        "RECOMMEND",
        "WILT",
        "DELEGATE",
        "AGONY",
        "DEFINITE",
        "IDENTICAL",
        "PORTION",
        "SOLUTION",
        "ATTENDANCE",
        "DIRECT",
        "INTRUDE",
        "POSSIBILITY",
        "STRESS",
        "CALCULATE",
        "DUPLICATE",
        "MODERN",
        "PURCHASE",
        "TRAGEDY",
        "CHUCKLE",
        "DURABLE",
        "OBJECTION",
        "SCARCE",
        "VARY",
        "COMICAL",
        "GLOSSY",
        "PERSPIRATION",
        "SNUG"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "The day was completely",
          "part2": "; there wasn't even a patch of blue in the sky.",
          "answer": "overcast"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Each state elected two",
          "part2": "to represent it at the conference.",
          "answer": "delegates"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The city had a large shopping",
          "part2": "where all the major department stores were located.",
          "answer": "district"
        },
        {
          "part1": "John liked to",
          "part2": "the way the birds were building their nest.",
          "answer": "observe"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The teacher had a small",
          "part2": "of papers that she had to correct.",
          "answer": "mound"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The bus driver was very",
          "part2": "He helped the blind lady to her seat and let her know when he reached her stop.",
          "answer": "courteous."
        },
        {
          "part1": "Even though he knows the answers perfectly well, he always",
          "part2": "a bit before replying.",
          "answer": "hesitates"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The pipes were partially clogged, so the water just",
          "part2": "out.",
          "answer": "trickled"
        },
        {
          "part1": "When Jimmy started to",
          "part2": "his chores around the house his mother scolded him.",
          "answer": "neglect"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Donna was",
          "part2": "that she passed the test, so she went out to celebrate right away.",
          "answer": "certain"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We have had good results with this floor cleaner, so we",
          "part2": "that you use it too.",
          "answer": "recommend"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He needs lots of love and",
          "part2": "to make him feel worthwhile.",
          "answer": "affection"
        },
        {
          "part1": "There were thousands of",
          "part2": "on hand to watch the race.",
          "answer": "spectators"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Our interest in the job started out fresh and strong, but it began to",
          "part2": "when we saw how difficult the work was.",
          "answer": "wilt"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She",
          "part2": "the conversation to announce that her father had fallen ill.",
          "answer": "interrupted"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The attractive surroundings and beautiful weather in Hawaii",
          "part2": "many people into moving there.",
          "answer": "lure"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He",
          "part2": "his arm into the water to see how cold it was.",
          "answer": "plunged"
        },
        {
          "part1": "People have always",
          "part2": "him one of the greatest players who ever lived.",
          "answer": "considered"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He",
          "part2": "Ann to let her know the teacher was looking at her.",
          "answer": "nudged"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They were yelling at him to",
          "part2": "the ball back to them.",
          "answer": "fling"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She was very bad about studying and doing her homework; as a result her grades",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "slumped"
        },
        {
          "part1": "In spite of the storm outside our tent, we felt quite",
          "part2": "in our sleeping bags.",
          "answer": "snug"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Cars are",
          "part2": "around here; you could go for days without seeing one.",
          "answer": "scarce"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It's easy to give your table a(n)",
          "part2": "surface with this furniture polish.",
          "answer": "glossy"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The principal requested his",
          "part2": "at the meeting after school.",
          "answer": "attendance"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Ben liked to",
          "part2": "the meals he prepared for them so that they wouldn't get bored.",
          "answer": "vary"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He ate his entire",
          "part2": "of food, then asked for some of mine.",
          "answer": "portion"
        },
        {
          "part1": "These marble floors are so",
          "part2": "they can last for hundreds of years.",
          "answer": "durable"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He told us a(n)",
          "part2": "story that had us laughing very hard.",
          "answer": "comical"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The teacher had no",
          "part2": "to the students' plan to go to the museum.",
          "answer": "objection"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Their vacation plans aren't very",
          "part2": "yet; they think they might go on a cruise somewhere.",
          "answer": "definite"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We could see by the",
          "part2": "on his face that he'd been working hard in the heat.",
          "answer": "perspiration"
        },
        {
          "part1": "For several days the newspapers carried stories about the",
          "part2": "in which many people were killed.",
          "answer": "tragedy"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The man at the door said they had to",
          "part2": "tickets to get inside.",
          "answer": "purchase"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We decided to wear",
          "part2": "costumes to the party so that no one could tell us apart.",
          "answer": "identical"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The soldier was in great",
          "part2": "until the doctor treated his wounds.",
          "answer": "agony"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I don't want to",
          "part2": ", but if you're not busy I'd like to see you for a minute.",
          "answer": "intrude"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Scientists spent several years searching for a(n)",
          "part2": "to the problem, but they haven't yet succeeded.",
          "answer": "solution"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Her dress was an exact",
          "part2": "of the one her friend was wearing. They must have shopped at the same store.",
          "answer": "duplicate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They traveled to the city by a(n)",
          "part2": "route.",
          "answer": "direct"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He thought there was too much",
          "part2": "placed on coming in first in these contests.",
          "answer": "stress"
        },
        {
          "part1": "In",
          "part2": "times people live much longer than they did centuries ago.",
          "answer": "modern"
        },
        {
          "part1": "If there is any",
          "part2": "that you can make it, please let us know.",
          "answer": "possibility"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Ed found it difficult to",
          "part2": "the answer without a pencil and paper.",
          "answer": "calculate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Other people were laughing noisily at the show, but we just",
          "part2": "quietly.",
          "answer": "chuckled"
        }
      ]
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "1.10",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "NAVIGATE the ship.",
          "answers": [
            "sink",
            "clean",
            "board",
            "steer",
            "find"
          ],
          "word": "NAVIGATE",
          "correct": "steer"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FAINT memories.",
          "answers": [
            "odd",
            "pleasant",
            "dim",
            "old",
            "powerful"
          ],
          "word": "FAINT",
          "correct": "dim"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A case of HOMICIDE.",
          "answers": [
            "robbery",
            "lying",
            "false arrest",
            "bribery",
            "murder"
          ],
          "word": "HOMICIDE",
          "correct": "murder"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They SHRIEK.",
          "answers": [
            "scream",
            "weep",
            "fly",
            "fight",
            "hide"
          ],
          "word": "SHRIEK",
          "correct": "scream"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ELEMENTARY ideas.",
          "answers": [
            "basic",
            "useless",
            "important",
            "advanced",
            "incorrect"
          ],
          "word": "ELEMENTARY",
          "correct": "basic"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To INCINERATE it.",
          "answers": [
            "save",
            "dump",
            "crush",
            "burn",
            "search"
          ],
          "word": "INCINERATE",
          "correct": "burn"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OCCASIONALLY late.",
          "answers": [
            "always",
            "already",
            "often",
            "sometimes",
            "never"
          ],
          "word": "OCCASIONALLY",
          "correct": "sometimes"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ASSAULT him.",
          "answers": [
            "help",
            "dislike",
            "attack",
            "rob",
            "laugh at"
          ],
          "word": "ASSAULT",
          "correct": "attack"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MUFFLE up carefully.",
          "answers": [
            "give",
            "wrap",
            "wash",
            "open",
            "move"
          ],
          "word": "MUFFLE",
          "correct": "wrap"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Began to HOBBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "jump",
            "crawl",
            "run",
            "yell",
            "limp"
          ],
          "word": "HOBBLE",
          "correct": "limp"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LINK the wires.",
          "answers": [
            "drop",
            "join",
            "cut",
            "hold",
            "twist"
          ],
          "word": "LINK",
          "correct": "join"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He may RESIST it.",
          "answers": [
            "help",
            "attack",
            "need",
            "hate",
            "oppose"
          ],
          "word": "RESIST",
          "correct": "oppose"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The cause of her GRIEF.",
          "answers": [
            "smile",
            "delight",
            "sadness",
            "anger",
            "sickness"
          ],
          "word": "GRIEF",
          "correct": "sadnÔøΩss"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His MOOD.",
          "answers": [
            "idea",
            "way of life",
            "happiness",
            "state of mind",
            "decision"
          ],
          "word": "MOOD",
          "correct": "state of mind"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Fear made them QUAKE.",
          "answers": [
            "tremble",
            "run",
            "fight",
            "stop",
            "hide"
          ],
          "word": "QUAKE",
          "correct": "tremble"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Should a pilot be able to NAVIGATE a plane?",
          "word": "NAVIGATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it easy to see a FAINT star?",
          "word": "FAINT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is running over a dog HOMICIDE?",
          "word": "HOMICIDE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a person SHRIEK from fear?",
          "word": "SHRIEK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are reading, writing, and arithmetic ELEMENTARY subjects?",
          "word": "ELEMENTARY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it easy to INCINERATE gold and silver?",
          "word": "INCINERATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are most people OCCASIONALLY angry?",
          "word": "OCCASIONALLY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you only ASSAULT someone by hitting him?",
          "word": "ASSAULT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people MUFFLE up in order to keep warm?",
          "word": "MUFFLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a good racehorse HOBBLE?",
          "word": "HOBBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are a father and his son LINKED in any way?",
          "word": "LINK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does wood RESIST fire?",
          "word": "RESIST",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does an airplane crash usually cause GRIEF?",
          "word": "GRIEF",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a MOOD change quickly?",
          "word": "MOOD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could an explosion cause buildings to QUAKE?",
          "word": "QUAKE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The captain let his son NAVIGATE the ship through the canal.",
          "word": "NAVIGATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her cries were too FAINT to be heard in the next room.",
          "word": "FAINT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was accused of HOMICIDE in the death of his wife.",
          "word": "HOMICIDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The baby's constant SHRIEKS kept us from getting a good night's sleep.",
          "word": "SHRIEK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "There are some ELEMENTARY things you have to know before you can drive a car.",
          "word": "ELEMENTARY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They INCINERATED that we had made a mistake.",
          "word": "INCINERATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Alice was OCCASIONALLY late for school; she was almost never on time.",
          "word": "OCCASIONALLY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The cruel strangers ASSAULTED him with clubs and rocks.",
          "word": "ASSAULT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The fielder MUFFLED the easy ground ball.",
          "word": "MUFFLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He HOBBLED to the other side of the room to pick up his crutches.",
          "word": "HOBBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They LINKED the boat from the dock by cutting the rope.",
          "word": "LINK",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "There was considerable RESISTANCE in Congress to the president's plan.",
          "word": "RESIST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Only the passage of time could ease the GRIEF she felt over his death.",
          "word": "GRIEF",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Beth is very MOODY today. She may yell at you for no reason.",
          "word": "MOOD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The explosions made the nearby buildings QUAKE.",
          "word": "QUAKE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "NAVIGATE",
          "answers": [
            "fly",
            "sit",
            "sail"
          ],
          "word": "NAVIGATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FAINT",
          "answers": [
            "strange",
            "unclear",
            "distant"
          ],
          "word": "FAINT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HOMICIDE",
          "answers": [
            "beating",
            "killing",
            "murder"
          ],
          "word": "HOMICIDE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHRIEK",
          "answers": [
            "cry",
            "yell",
            "weep"
          ],
          "word": "SHRIEK",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ELEMENTARY",
          "answers": [
            "basic",
            "common",
            "simple"
          ],
          "word": "ELEMENTARY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INCINERATE",
          "answers": [
            "flame",
            "burn",
            "explode"
          ],
          "word": "INCINERATE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OCCASIONALLY",
          "answers": [
            "rarely",
            "sometimes",
            "usually"
          ],
          "word": "OCCASIONALLY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ASSAULT",
          "answers": [
            "hit",
            "hurt",
            "trick"
          ],
          "word": "ASSAULT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MUFFLE",
          "answers": [
            "hide",
            "cover",
            "lose"
          ],
          "word": "MUFFLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HOBBLE",
          "answers": [
            "slide",
            "limp",
            "bother"
          ],
          "word": "HOBBLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LINK",
          "answers": [
            "connect",
            "tie",
            "shorten"
          ],
          "word": "LINK",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RESIST",
          "answers": [
            "refuse",
            "prevent",
            "disturb"
          ],
          "word": "RESIST",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GRIEF",
          "answers": [
            "despair",
            "rage",
            "sorrow"
          ],
          "word": "GRIEF",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MOOD",
          "answers": [
            "anger",
            "memory",
            "joy"
          ],
          "word": "MOOD",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "QUAKE",
          "answers": [
            "cry",
            "shiver",
            "shake"
          ],
          "word": "QUAKE",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "NAVIGATE": {
        "word": "NAVIGATE",
        "phonetic": "(nav'-ÔøΩgAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to steer, sail \nNAVIGATE is related to the word navy. Both come from a Latin word meaning _ship_. The basic meaning of NAVIGATE is to \"steer a ship.\" Now the word also means to steer or direct your course anywhere, in the water, on the ground, or in the air. \"The pilot NAVIGATED the damaged plane to a successful landing.\" \n\"Can you NAVIGATE the boat through the rapids?\" \n\"We expect you to be able to NAVIGATE anywhere after you have finished this course in sailing.\" \nOther forms of the word: NAVIGATION, n. \nNAVIGATOR, n."
      },
      "FAINT": {
        "word": "FAINT",
        "phonetic": "(fAnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "dim, weak, unclear, indistinct \nSomething that is FAINT lacks strength. A person who \"feels FAINT\" feels sick and dizzy, as if he or she were about to pass out. FAINT can be used about sounds, lights, smells, memories, and other things. \n\"There was a FAINT smell of roses in the air as they approached the garden.\" \n\"He could barely hear the FAINT sound of the distant train whistle.\" \n\"There is only a very FAINT hope that any of the trapped miners will survive.\" \nThe verb to FAINT is usually used about people and means \"to lose consciousness,\" to _pass out_. \n\"Many people FAINTED in the heat during the long speech.\""
      },
      "HOMICIDE": {
        "word": "HOMICIDE",
        "phonetic": "(hom'-ÔøΩsld)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "the killing of a human being, murder \nHOMICIDE is the killing of a person by another person. \"The medical examiner ruled that the death was a HOMICIDE.\" \n\"The detective was assigned to investigate cases of HOMICIDE.\" \nHOMICIDE and _murder_ have almost the same meaning, but there is a slight difference. _Murder_ is the _unlawful_ killing of a person. If you kill someone in self-defense, that would be HOMICIDE, but it wouldn't be _murder_, since the killing would be legal. All _murders_ are HOMICIDES, but not all HOMICIDES are _murders_."
      },
      "SHRIEK": {
        "word": "SHRIEK",
        "phonetic": "(shrEk)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to scream, screech, cry out \nTo SHRIEK is to scream or screech suddenly or loudly, usually with a very high sound. \n\"She SHRIEKED when she heard the unexpected knock on the door.\" \nSHRIEK is also a noun meaning a _scream_. \n\"She let out a piercing SHRIEK when she saw the accident.\" \n\"The SHRIEKS of the angry birds disturbed my nap.\""
      },
      "ELEMENTARY": {
        "word": "ELEMENTARY",
        "phonetic": "(el-ÔøΩmen'-tÔøΩrE)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "basic, fundamental, simple \nAn ELEMENT is a basic part of something. The chemical ELEMENTS, for example, are the basic substances like oxygen and carbon which combine to form all matter. Something that is ELEMENTARY, therefore, has to do with the basic or first parts of a subject or a thing. \n\"He learned some of the ELEMENTARY steps, but he never became an expert dancer.\" \n\"You have to pass ELEMENTARY French before you can take advanced courses.\" \nAn ELEMENTARY school teaches children basic subjects like reading, writing, and arithmetic. Other forms of the word: ELEMENT, n."
      },
      "INCINERATE": {
        "word": "INCINERATE",
        "phonetic": "(in-sin'-ÔøΩrAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to burn, reduce to ashes \nINCINERATE comes from the Latin word for ashes and means to \"burn to ashes.\" \n\"He INCINERATED the pile of leaves in the backyard.\" \nAn INCINERATOR is a place for INCINERATING, a furnace. \n\"We placed all the trash in the INCINERATOR.\" \nOther forms of the word: INCINERATOR, n."
      },
      "OCCASIONALLY": {
        "word": "OCCASIONALLY",
        "phonetic": "(:;i-kA'-zhÔøΩn-ÔøΩ1-E)",
        "pos": "adv.",
        "deftext": "sometimes, now and then, at times \nOCCASIONALLY is an adverb from OCCASIONAL, which means \"happening now and then.\" \n\"There were OCCASIONAL mistakes in the book, but in general it was quite good.\" \nOCCASIONALLY means _at times_, _now and then_. On the Pretest, many people pick _often_ as the meaning of OCCASIONALLY, but something that happens OCCASIONALLY doesn't happen very _often_ at all. \n\"She OCCASIONALLY went to the movies, but preferred watching television.\" \n\"We have turkey only OCCASIONALLY—maybe two or three times a year.\" \nOther forms of the word: OCCASION, n. \nOCCASIONAL, adj."
      },
      "ASSAULT": {
        "word": "ASSAULT",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩsolt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to attack \nTo ASSAULT someone is to attack him, usually violently or suddenly. \n\"The three youths ASSAULTED the defenseless girl.\" \n\"The soldiers ASSAULTED the enemy positions.\" \nASSAULT is also a noun. \n\"We managed to turn back the enemy's ASSAULT.\" \nSometimes an ASSAULT can be in words. \n\"The mayor considered the newspaper articles to be an ASSAULT on his good reputation.\""
      },
      "MUFFLE": {
        "word": "MUFFLE",
        "phonetic": "(muhf'-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to wrap up, cover over; to deaden the sound of \nTo MUFFLE or MUFFLE up something is to wrap it up. You can MUFFLE something to keep it warm or hide it. \n\"She MUFFLED her neck with a scarf.\" \n\"He MUFFLED up in a heavy coat before going out into the cold.\" \nOr you can MUFFLE something to keep it from being noisy. \n\"They tried to MUFFLE the noise of the machine by wrapping it in cotton.\" \nOn a car, a MUFFLER is a device that deadens the sound of the engine. Many people choose move as the meaning of MUFFLE, perhaps because MUFFLE sounds like shuffle, which is a kind of movement. \nOther forms of the word: MUFFLER, n. \nUsage: MUFFLE is sometimes followed by up."
      },
      "HOBBLE": {
        "word": "HOBBLE",
        "phonetic": "(hob'-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to limp, move awkwardly; to hamper the action of \nTo HOBBLE is to walk with difficulty, as if your feet or legs were hurt. \n\"The old man HOBBLED down the street, leaning heavily on his cane.\" \n\"With his broken ankle Don can barely HOBBLE.\" \nTo HOBBLE someone or something is to cause it to move awkwardly, to hamper or bother it. \n\"The tight-fitting shoes HOBBLED her as she tried to walk across the room.\""
      },
      "LINK": {
        "word": "LINK",
        "phonetic": "(lingk)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to join, connect \nA LINK is one of the rings or loops in a chain. To LINK things is to connect them, to join them together the way LINKS are joined in a chain. \n\"They built a bridge to LINK the two sides of the river.\" \n\"Our common interest in fishing LINKS us together.\" \nLINK is often used with _up_. \n\"The two ends were LINKED up with one another by means of a rope.\""
      },
      "RESIST": {
        "word": "RESIST",
        "phonetic": "{ri-zist')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to oppose, withstand \nTo RESIST something is to withstand its power or force. \n\"The enemy RESISTED our attack.\" \n\"The youth was charged with RESISTING arrest.\" \n\"I couldn't RESIST buying this necklace.\" \n\"This glass can RESIST temperatures of up to a thousand degrees.\" \nRESISTANCE is the power of RESISTING. \n\"The insects had developed a RESISTANCE to that poison\"—that is, they could withstand its effects. \nOther forms of the word: RESISTANCE, n. \nRESISTANT, adj."
      },
      "GRIEF": {
        "word": "GRIEF",
        "phonetic": "(grEf)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "deep sorrow, sadness, mental suffering, misery \nGRIEF is a very strong degree of _sadness_ or _sorrow_. \nGRIEF usually suggests sadness that is caused by loss, pain, regret, or despair, and that lasts for a long time or is very deep. \n\"No one could ease her GRIEF when she discovered that her son had died.\" \n\"Jim's GRIEF over her decision to leave him was almost unbearable.\" \nThe phrase \"to come to GRIEF\" means \"to meet misfortune or disappointment.\" \n\"This project will come to GRIEF unless we work harder.\" \nThe most commonly chosen incorrect answer is _anger_. _Anger_ is another strong emotion, but it is not the same as GRIEF. Other forms of the word: GRIEVE, v."
      },
      "MOOD": {
        "word": "MOOD",
        "phonetic": "(mUd)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a state of mind, feeling \nA MOOD is a state of mind, the way a person feels mentally at a certain time. \n\"His MOODS change constantly. He's happy one minute and sad the next.\" \n\"She said she isn't in the MOOD to work right now.\" \nMOOD is also used about the general spirits of a group of people. \n\"The country is in an angry MOOD.\" \n\"His writings reflect the MOOD of the times.\" \nA person who is MOODY has MOODS that often change. MOODY is usually used about a person who often has unhappy or angry MOODS. \n\"He becomes MOODY and won't talk to anyone whenever he loses a game.\" \nOther forms of the word: MOODY, adj."
      },
      "QUAKE": {
        "word": "QUAKE",
        "phonetic": "(kwAk)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to shake, tremble \nQUAKE means to _shake_, usually violently. \n\"Every time the train roared by the entire house would QUAKE.\" \nPeople QUAKE from cold or fear. \n\"When I saw the monster I started QUAKING so badly that I couldn't run.\" \nQUAKE, as a noun, is short for _earthquake_. In an _earthquake_ the ground starts shaking, which causes great damage to buildings and property."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "1.11",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Real DEVOTION.",
          "answers": [
            "excitement",
            "trickery",
            "faithfulness",
            "dislike",
            "happiness"
          ],
          "word": "DEVOTION",
          "correct": "faithfulness"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Similar CIRCUMSTANCES.",
          "answers": [
            "conditions",
            "accidents",
            "choices",
            "outlines",
            "changes"
          ],
          "word": "CIRCUMSTANCE",
          "correct": "conditions"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ABOLISH it.",
          "answers": [
            "give in to",
            "be angry at",
            "make up for",
            "do away with",
            "dislike"
          ],
          "word": "ABOLISH",
          "correct": "do away with"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DECEASED relatives.",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "additional",
            "distant",
            "dead",
            "aged"
          ],
          "word": "DECEASED",
          "correct": "dead"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Began to DOZE.",
          "answers": [
            "be tired",
            "dream",
            "sleep lightly",
            "go crazy",
            "wake up"
          ],
          "word": "DOZE",
          "correct": "sleep lightly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The child BAWLED.",
          "answers": [
            "cried loudly",
            "coughed",
            "whispered",
            "played",
            "fought wildly"
          ],
          "word": "BAWL",
          "correct": "cried loudly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Caught the ASSASSIN.",
          "answers": [
            "physician",
            "disease",
            "kidnapper",
            "murderer",
            "bully"
          ],
          "word": "ASSASSIN",
          "correct": "murderer"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She ENCOURAGED her students.",
          "answers": [
            "urged on",
            "advised",
            "asked",
            "disappointed",
            "improved"
          ],
          "word": "ENCOURAGE",
          "correct": "urged on"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONVENIENT shelf.",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "high",
            "handy",
            "broken",
            "big"
          ],
          "word": "CONVENIENT",
          "correct": "handy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Noticed the DEFECT.",
          "answers": [
            "foreigner",
            "scratch",
            "favor",
            "fault",
            "official"
          ],
          "word": "DEFECT",
          "correct": "fault"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They CIRCULATED.",
          "answers": [
            "grew dark",
            "became hot",
            "stopped",
            "increased",
            "moved around"
          ],
          "word": "CIRCULATE",
          "correct": "moved around"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Brief ENCOUNTER.",
          "answers": [
            "story",
            "meeting",
            "walk",
            "trip",
            "stop"
          ],
          "word": "ENCOUNTER",
          "correct": "meeting"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Recognized their AUTHORITY.",
          "answers": [
            "greatness",
            "weakness",
            "founder",
            "power",
            "service"
          ],
          "word": "AUTHORITY",
          "correct": "power"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Completely DEFORMED.",
          "answers": [
            "understood",
            "cured",
            "disfigured",
            "opposed",
            "destroyed"
          ],
          "word": "DEFORMED",
          "correct": "disfigured"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Very CONFIDENT.",
          "answers": [
            "mysterious",
            "worried",
            "sure",
            "happy",
            "clever"
          ],
          "word": "CONFIDENT",
          "correct": "sure"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Would a DEVOTED musician enjoy playing music?",
          "word": "DEVOTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are the CIRCUMSTANCES of a decision the results of it?",
          "word": "CIRCUMSTANCE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most students like to have summer vacations ABOLISHED?",
          "word": "ABOLISH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are you DECEASED?",
          "word": "DECEASED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can cats DOZE?",
          "word": "DOZE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a baby BAWL if it hadn't been fed for a day?",
          "word": "BAWL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Was Abraham Lincoln ASSASSINATED?",
          "word": "ASSASSIN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a coach ENCOURAGE his team to win?",
          "word": "ENCOURAGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people find it CONVENIENT to go to school next door to where they live?",
          "word": "CONVENIENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people want to buy a DEFECTIVE watch?",
          "word": "DEFECTIVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can ideas be CIRCULATED?",
          "word": "CIRCULATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can an ENCOUNTER be friendly?",
          "word": " ENCOUNTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do children usually have AUTHORITY over their parents?",
          "word": "AUTHORITY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are cars that have been in accidents DEFORMED?",
          "word": "DEFORMED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a CONFIDENT person worry that he was going to fail?",
          "word": "CONFIDENT",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "No one could match the lawyer's DEVOTION to the cause of justice for all.",
          "word": "DEVOTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "These are not the proper CIRCUMSTANCES in which to discuss your problems.",
          "word": "CIRCUMSTANCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The teacher ABOLISHED them not to talk so loud.",
          "word": "ABOLISH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The children always became very sad when they spoke about their DECEASED uncle.",
          "word": "DECEASED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She DOZED the baby by singing softly to it.",
          "word": "DOZE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Pete lost his balance and BAWLED down the stairs.",
          "word": "BAWL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The ASSASSIN followed his victim for days before killing him.",
          "word": "ASSASSIN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We were ENCOURAGED by the favorable response to our request.",
          "word": "ENCOURAGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It costs more, but Mrs. Jones likes the CONVENIENCE of having her groceries delivered right to her door.",
          "word": "CONVENIENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "There was only one DEFECT in the engine, but it was enough to keep the car from running.",
          "word": "DEFECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He CIRCULATED the right answer with his pencil and went on to the next question.",
          "word": "CIRCULATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A quick ENCOUNTER showed that we were missing six dollars.",
          "word": "ENCOUNTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Who gave you the AUTHORITY to close the school?",
          "word": "AUTHORITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Larry DEFORMED his letters the way the teacher taught him to.",
          "word": "DEFORMED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Everyone on the team was CONFIDENT that we would win.",
          "word": "CONFIDENT",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "DEVOTION",
          "answers": [
            "faithfulness",
            "truthfulness",
            "love"
          ],
          "word": "DEVOTION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CIRCUMSTANCE",
          "answers": [
            "condition",
            "situation",
            "difference"
          ],
          "word": "CIRCUMSTANCE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ABOLISH",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "give in",
            "end"
          ],
          "word": "ABOLISH",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DECEASED",
          "answers": [
            "dead",
            "ill",
            "lifeless"
          ],
          "word": "DECEASED",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DOZE",
          "answers": [
            "nap",
            "sit",
            "rest"
          ],
          "word": "DOZE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BAWL",
          "answers": [
            "yell",
            "argue",
            "cry"
          ],
          "word": "BAWL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ASSASSIN",
          "answers": [
            "robber",
            "murderer",
            "poisoner"
          ],
          "word": "ASSASSIN",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENCOURAGE",
          "answers": [
            "urge",
            "help",
            "wonder"
          ],
          "word": "ENCOURAGE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONVENIENT",
          "answers": [
            "close",
            "sudden",
            "easy"
          ],
          "word": "CONVENIENT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEFECT",
          "answers": [
            "break",
            "fault",
            "ache"
          ],
          "word": "DEFECT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CIRCULATE",
          "answers": [
            "drop",
            "move",
            "spread"
          ],
          "word": "CIRCULATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENCOUNTER",
          "answers": [
            "battle",
            "party",
            "meeting"
          ],
          "word": "ENCOUNTER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AUTHORITY",
          "answers": [
            "power",
            "knowledge",
            "beauty"
          ],
          "word": "AUTHORITY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEFORMED",
          "answers": [
            "lost",
            "twisted",
            "misshapen"
          ],
          "word": "DEFORMED",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONFIDENT",
          "answers": [
            "certain",
            "happy",
            "assured"
          ],
          "word": "CONFIDENT",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "DEVOTION": {
        "word": "DEVOTION",
        "phonetic": "(di-vO'-shÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "faithfulness, dedication, loyalty \nSomeone who is DEVOTED is attached or dedicated to a purpose, cause, or person. \n\"They are DEVOTED to the idea of world peace.\" DEVOTION is the quality of being DEVOTED; it is _faithfulness_, _dedication_, _loyalty_. \n\"Everyone admired her DEVOTION to her sick parents.\" \n\"He was fired because he didn't show enough DEVOTION to his duties.\" \nOther forms of the word: DEVOTE, v. \nDEVOTED, adj."
      },
      "CIRCUMSTANCE": {
        "word": "CIRCUMSTANCE",
        "phonetic": "(ser'-kÔøΩm-stans)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a condition, fact \nCIRCUMSTANCES are the conditions or facts surrounding some event or situation. \n\"I cannot make a decision about this until I know all the CIRCUMSTANCES.\" \n\"We were unaware of the terrible CIRCUMSTANCES at his home; both parents were ill and there was no food in the house.\" \n\"Each CIRCUMSTANCE must be taken into account before we decide what to do.\" \n\"She died under mysterious CIRCUMSTANCES.\" \nUsage: CIRCUMSTANCE is generally used in the plural: CIRCUMSTANCES."
      },
      "ABOLISH": {
        "word": "ABOLISH",
        "phonetic": "{ÔøΩ-bol'-ish)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to do away with, end \nTo ABOLISH something is to put an end to it or to do away with it. The word is used especially about laws, customs, and practices rather than about physical objects. \n\"President Lincoln ABOLISHED slavery in America.\" \n\"Our family voted to ABOLISH the tradition of giving expensive gifts on birthdays.\" \n\"Will mankind ever ABOLISH war?\" \nThe noun from ABOLISH is ABOLITION. \n\"The student council voted for the ABOLITION of the dress code. They said students should wear whatever they like.\" \nOther forms of the word: ABOLITION, n."
      },
      "DECEASED": {
        "word": "DECEASED",
        "phonetic": "(di-sEst')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "dead \nDECEASED means _dead_. It is used only about people, and often refers to someone who is recently dead. \n\"The DECEASED man's will was read to his relatives a month after he died.\" \n\"Al Johnson is now DECEASED, but he was once the richest man in town.\" DECEASED is also a noun and means the dead person. \n\"The wishes of the DECEASED must be respected in this matter.\""
      },
      "DOZE": {
        "word": "DOZE",
        "phonetic": "(dOz)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to sleep lightly \nTo DOZE is to fall into a light sleep. \n\"He DOZED for a while, then awoke with a start and realized he had missed the TV show.\" \n\"I must have DOZED off while doing my homework.\" \nDOZE is also a noun. \n\"The speech was so boring Joan fell into a DOZE after the first few minutes.\" \nUsage: DOZE is often followed by _off_."
      },
      "BAWL": {
        "word": "BAWL",
        "phonetic": "(bol)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to cry loudly, shout \nTo BAWL means \"to cry or shout loudly and continuously.\" Babies BAWL; animals BAWL; children who are very unhappy BAWL. \n\"We could hear the baby BAWLING in the next room.\" \n\"The cattle in the stockyard BAWLED in fear and confusion.\" \nWhen you get \"BAWLED out\" you get a loud scolding; someone shouts at you for doing something wrong. \n\"Her mother BAWLED her out for coming home late.\""
      },
      "ASSASSIN": {
        "word": "ASSASSIN",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩsas'-in)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a murderer, killer \nAn ASSASSIN is a _killer_, especially one who is paid for killing or who kills a public official. \n\"They caught the ASSASSIN of the president.\" \n\"The ASSASSIN prepared very carefully to murder his victim.\" \nThe verb from ASSASSIN is ASSASSINATE. \n\"Several Roman emperors were ASSASSINATED.\" \n\"The madman ASSASSINATED the mayor.\" \nOther forms of the word: ASSASSINATE, v. \nASSASSINATION, n."
      },
      "ENCOURAGE": {
        "word": "ENCOURAGE",
        "phonetic": "(en-kuhr'-ij)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to put courage into, urge on, stimulate, hearten, foster \nSee _in-_ under Prefixes. \nENCOURAGE basically means \"to put courage into.\" \n\"The soldiers needed to be ENCOURAGED before the battle.\" \nAs the word is used today it means to _urge_ or _help_ someone to do something, through words or example or in some other way. \n\"Her presence ENCOURAGED him to try again.\" \n\"My parents ENCOURAGED me to be a doctor.\" What is ENCOURAGED can be either good or bad. \n\"His early success ENCOURAGED him in his life of crime.\" \nIt doesn't have to be a person who is ENCOURAGED. \n\"The plan was designed to ENCOURAGE small businesses.\" \nOther forms of the word: ENCOURAGEMENT, n. \nENCOURAGING, adj."
      },
      "CONVENIENT": {
        "word": "CONVENIENT",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-vEn'-yÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "handy, useful, suitable \nSomething that is CONVENIENT is near at hand or easy to use. It is well suited for your comfort or ease. \n\"He found a CONVENIENT spot near the river and pitched his tent there.\" \n\"I don't care when you come. Pick the time that is most CONVENIENT for you.\" \n\"The soap comes in a CONVENIENT new package that we're sure you'll like.\" \nThe noun from CONVENIENT is CONVENIENCE. \n\"He arranged the schedule for his own CONVENIENCE. He didn't care if it caused problems for other people.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONVENIENCE, n."
      },
      "DEFECT": {
        "word": "DEFECT",
        "phonetic": "(dE'-fekt)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a fault, flaw, imperfection \nA DEFECT is something wrong or damaged, a _fault_. \n\"The DEFECT in the jacket was hardly noticeable. It was just a tiny hole near the button.\" \n\"The DEFECT in his plan was that there was no way we could get the money to carry it out.\" \n\"He admitted that his quick temper was a DEFECT in his character.\" \nThe adjective from DEFECT is DEFECTIVE. DEFECTIVE means _damaged_ or _not working_, \"having flaws or faults.\" \n\"The lamp was DEFECTIVE: sometimes it would light and sometimes it wouldn't.\" \n\"We didn't realize the air conditioner was DEFECTIVE until we tried to use it.\" \nOther forms of the word: DEFECTIVE, adj."
      },
      "CIRCULATE": {
        "word": "CIRCULATE",
        "phonetic": "(ser'-kyÔøΩIAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to move around, spread, flow freely \nCIRCULATE is related to the word _circle_. It means \"to move around and around.\" \n\"Blood CIRCULATES in our bodies; it takes about ten minutes for a complete cycle.\" \n\"We could hear the water CIRCULATING in the pipes.\" CIRCULATE also means \"to go freely from one place to another,\" to _spread around_. In this sense the word can be used about ideas, information, and the like. \n\"The news of her arrival CIRCULATED through the waiting crowd within a few moments.\" \n\"They CIRCULATED a petition asking that there be less homework on the weekends.\" \nOther forms of the word: CIRCULATION, n."
      },
      "ENCOUNTER": {
        "word": "ENCOUNTER",
        "phonetic": "(en-kown'-tÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a chance meeting; a battle, conflict \nAn ENCOUNTER is a meeting, especially a face-to-face meeting. There are two different uses of ENCOUNTER. The first is for any casual, unplanned meeting. \n\"John had an unexpected ENCOUNTER with his old friend yesterday.\" \nThe second use is for a sudden and perhaps violent coming together of enemies. \n\"The bloody ENCOUNTER left six men injured.\" \nENCOUNTER is also used as a verb, and means to _come upon_, _meet_, _confront_. \n\"The two old enemies ENCOUNTERED each other in the middle of the battle.\""
      },
      "AUTHORITY": {
        "word": "AUTHORITY",
        "phonetic": "(::,-thor'-::,-tE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "power, right \nAUTHORITY is the power or right to make people do something. \n\"He received the AUTHORITY to collect taxes in his district.\" \n\"The AUTHORITY of the laws was disregarded by the rebels.\" \n\"As they grew older, Mrs. Smith's children resisted her AUTHORITY more and more.\" \nAnother meaning of AUTHORITY is \"a person who has expert knowledge of something.\" \n\"He became the AUTHORITY on the development of young children.\" \n\"She is an AUTHORITY on Shakespeare.\""
      },
      "DEFORMED": {
        "word": "DEFORMED",
        "phonetic": "(di-formd')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "disfigured, misshapen \nTo DEFORM something is to take it out of its natural form or shape. See _de-_ under Prefixes. When something is DEFORMED, then, it is not shaped properly; it is disfigured. \n\"His leg was DEFORMED as a result of the accident.\" \n\"The baby survived, but it was permanently DEFORMED.\" \nDEFORMED usually suggests something that is ugly or offensive. \n\"When he was very upset, his face would become DEFORMED with rage.\" \nIn the Pretest, many people choose _destroyed_ as the meaning of DEFORMED. Something that is DEFORMED still exists, it is just misshapen; it has not been _destroyed_. \nOther forms of the word: DEFORM, v. \nDEFORMITY, n."
      },
      "CONFIDENT": {
        "word": "CONFIDENT",
        "phonetic": "(kon'-f::,-dÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "sure, assured \nSomeone who is CONFIDENT firmly believes that he is right or that he can do something. He doesn't have any fears or doubts about himself. \n\"I am CONFIDENT that I will succeed. No one can stop me now.\" \n\"She was CONFIDENT she had passed the exam, but she was surprised she earned an A.\" \n\"The salesman walked CONFIDENTLY up to them and told them why they should buy this car.\" \nA person who is CONFIDENT has CONFIDENCE. \n\"Every success he had gave him a little more CONFIDENCE that he could do the job.\" \n\"All Jim lacks is CONFIDENCE. He just doesn't think he's good enough.\" \nThe most commonly chosen incorrect answer is _mysterious_. This may be because CONFIDENT looks like _confidential_, which means _secret_. \nOther forms of the word: CONFIDENCE, n."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "1.12",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "She ESTABLISHED the business.",
          "answers": [
            "announced",
            "bought",
            "sold",
            "improved",
            "set up"
          ],
          "word": "ESTABLISH",
          "correct": "set up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Enjoying the EXPEDITION.",
          "answers": [
            "visit",
            "display",
            "journey",
            "boat race",
            "sights"
          ],
          "word": "EXPEDITION",
          "correct": "journey"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Best way to INSTRUCT.",
          "answers": [
            "forget",
            "teach",
            "learn",
            "punish",
            "build"
          ],
          "word": "INSTRUCT",
          "correct": "teach"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GNARLED branches.",
          "answers": [
            "old",
            "decorated",
            "smooth",
            "diseased",
            "twisted"
          ],
          "word": "GNARLED",
          "correct": "twisted"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Tried to FLATTER him.",
          "answers": [
            "insult",
            "improve",
            "over praise",
            "crush",
            "agree with"
          ],
          "word": "FLATTER",
          "correct": "over praise"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were EXTERMINATED.",
          "answers": [
            "wiped out",
            "stopped",
            "beaten up",
            "cured",
            "thrown away"
          ],
          "word": "EXTERMINATE",
          "correct": "wiped out"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Began to LAG.",
          "answers": [
            "sink",
            "give up",
            "breathe heavily",
            "fall behind",
            "catch up"
          ],
          "word": "LAG",
          "correct": "fall behind"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FATAL blows.",
          "answers": [
            "deadly",
            "soft",
            "natural",
            "first",
            "painful"
          ],
          "word": "FATAL",
          "correct": "deadly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Powerful HEX.",
          "answers": [
            "evil",
            "prayer",
            "tool",
            "fear",
            "curse"
          ],
          "word": "HEX",
          "correct": "curse"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Clever IMPOSTOR.",
          "answers": [
            "detective",
            "customer",
            "magician",
            "faker",
            "thief"
          ],
          "word": "IMPOSTOR",
          "correct": "faker"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GLUM people.",
          "answers": [
            "mean",
            "cheerful",
            "gloomy",
            "stupid",
            "clumsy"
          ],
          "word": "GLUM",
          "correct": "gloomy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were FEROCIOUS.",
          "answers": [
            "huge",
            "fierce",
            "loud",
            "clever",
            "mild"
          ],
          "word": "FEROCIOUS",
          "correct": "fierce"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Examined the INTERIOR.",
          "answers": [
            "tomb",
            "decoration",
            "inside",
            "room",
            "outside"
          ],
          "word": "INTERIOR",
          "correct": "inside"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was worth the EXPENSE.",
          "answers": [
            "price",
            "income",
            "protection",
            "time",
            "effort"
          ],
          "word": "EXPENSE",
          "correct": "price"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Everyone was GLEEFUL.",
          "answers": [
            "worried",
            "dangerous",
            "excited",
            "merry",
            "warm"
          ],
          "word": "GLEEFUL",
          "correct": "merry"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do wreckers ESTABLISH buildings?",
          "word": "ESTABLISH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can there be only one person on an EXPEDITION?",
          "word": "EXPEDITION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a teacher INSTRUCT a class?",
          "word": "INSTRUCT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do babies usually have GNARLED hands?",
          "word": "GNARLED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If you tell someone he is ugly, mean, and stingy, are you FLATTERING him?",
          "word": "FLATTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Have rats been completely EXTERMINATED?",
          "word": "EXTERMINATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a speedy person usually LAG behind?",
          "word": "LAG",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a cold usually FATAL?",
          "word": "FATAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a HEX meant to help a person?",
          "word": "HEX",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an IMPOSTOR trying to fool someone?",
          "word": "IMPOSTOR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does losing often make people feel GLUM?",
          "word": "GLUM",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can wolves be FEROCIOUS?",
          "word": "FEROCIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is the skin on the INTERIOR of the body?",
          "word": "INTERIOR",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If you can get something at no EXPENSE, is it free?",
          "word": "EXPENSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does the loser of a game generally feel GLEEFUL?",
          "word": "GLEEFUL",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Beth tried to ESTABLISH a reputation as a hard worker.",
          "word": "ESTABLISH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The EXPEDITION of jewelry was beautifully arranged in the store window.",
          "word": "EXPEDITION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We were INSTRUCTED to leave our coats outside the examination room.",
          "word": "INSTRUCT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The dog GNARLED on the bone for a while before he buried it.",
          "word": "GNARLED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The painting FLATTERED the lady by making her look twenty years younger.",
          "word": "FLATTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We tried to EXTERMINATE all the insects in the house.",
          "word": "EXTERMINATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He LAGGED at them for not working harder.",
          "word": "LAG",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His one error proved to be FATAL, because his team lost as a result of it.",
          "word": "FATAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Al believed he was HEXED, because nothing ever seemed to go right for him.",
          "word": "HEX",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was a true IMPOSTOR, always trying to help people.",
          "word": "IMPOSTOR",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Catherine became GLUM when she heard that she had won the scholarship.",
          "word": "GLUM",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The FEROCIOUS look the teacher gave us made us all quiet down immediately.",
          "word": "FEROCIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The INTERIOR of Australia is mostly desert.",
          "word": "INTERIOR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The watch was so EXPENSIVE we couldn't afford to buy it.",
          "word": "EXPENSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "With GLEEFUL cries, the children opened their presents on Christmas morning.",
          "word": "GLEEFUL",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "ESTABLISH",
          "answers": [
            "build",
            "start",
            "change"
          ],
          "word": "ESTABLISH",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXPEDITION",
          "answers": [
            "view",
            "voyage",
            "trip"
          ],
          "word": "EXPEDITION",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INSTRUCT",
          "answers": [
            "teach",
            "compare",
            "command"
          ],
          "word": "INSTRUCT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GNARLED",
          "answers": [
            "knotty",
            "heavy",
            "twisted"
          ],
          "word": "GNARLED",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FLATTER",
          "answers": [
            "pretend",
            "lie",
            "insult"
          ],
          "word": "FLATTER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXTERMINATE",
          "answers": [
            "kill",
            "hurt",
            "destroy"
          ],
          "word": "EXTERMINATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LAG",
          "answers": [
            "follow",
            "slow",
            "win"
          ],
          "word": "LAG",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FATAL",
          "answers": [
            "destructive",
            "illegal",
            "harmful"
          ],
          "word": "FATAL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HEX",
          "answers": [
            "spell",
            "curse",
            "threat"
          ],
          "word": "HEX",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IMPOSTOR",
          "answers": [
            "robber",
            "phony",
            "faker"
          ],
          "word": "IMPOSTOR",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GLUM",
          "answers": [
            "silent",
            "tired",
            "sad"
          ],
          "word": "GLUM",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FEROCIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "cruel",
            "wild",
            "unhealthy"
          ],
          "word": "FEROCIOUS",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTERIOR",
          "answers": [
            "top",
            "inside",
            "center"
          ],
          "word": "INTERIOR",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXPENSE",
          "answers": [
            "charge",
            "cost",
            "quantity"
          ],
          "word": "EXPENSE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GLEEFUL",
          "answers": [
            "happy",
            "pleased",
            "healthy"
          ],
          "word": "GLEEFUL",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "ESTABLISH": {
        "word": "ESTABLISH",
        "phonetic": "(e-stab'-lish)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to set up, make firm, start up, bring about, found \nESTABLISH is related to the adjective _stable_, which means _solid_, _fixed_, _not easily moved_. The basic meaning of ESTABLISH is \"to make something stable.\" The word is usually used in the sense \"to set up or bring about something,\" usually on a firm or stable basis. It is often used about businesses: \n\"This company was ESTABLISHED in 1959.\" \nAbout customs: \n\"Who ESTABLISHED the custom of kissing underneath mistletoe?\" \nAbout rights, claims, facts, and the like: \n\"It took a long time to ESTABLISH the facts of the case.\" \nAnd about people: \n\"They were comfortably ESTABLISHED in their new headquarters.\" \nIn all cases, ESTABLISH has the idea of setting something up, putting something on a firm foundation. \nOther forms of the word: ESTABLISHMENT, n."
      },
      "EXPEDITION": {
        "word": "EXPEDITION",
        "phonetic": "(ek-spÔøΩdish'-::m)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a journey, voyage \nAn EXPEDITION is a journey or voyage which usually is made for a definite reason. It is usually well organized, and its purpose is often to explore. \n\"He went on an EXPEDITION into the jungle to study the rare plants that grow there.\" \n\"When we had everything packed for our vacation, it looked like we were going on an EXPEDITION to Alaska.\" \n\"The military EXPEDITION lasted two months.\""
      },
      "INSTRUCT": {
        "word": "INSTRUCT",
        "phonetic": "(in-struhkt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to teach, educate, inform; to order \nTo INSTRUCT someone is to give knowledge to him. Often it means just about the same as teach. \n\"The teacher INSTRUCTED the class about how to do multiplication.\" \n\"The piano teacher comes to the house to INSTRUCT Sue.\" \nSometimes INSTRUCT has a stronger meaning—to _order_ or _direct_. \n\"The teacher INSTRUCTED us to return to our seats immediately.\" \nThe adjective from INSTRUCT is INSTRUCTIVE, which means _giving knowledge_, _informative_. \n\"The class was very INSTRUCTIVE. I think we all learned a lot.\" \nOther forms of the word: INSTRUCTION, n. \nINSTRUCTIVE, adj. \nINSTRUCTOR, n."
      },
      "GNARLED": {
        "word": "GNARLED",
        "phonetic": "(nahrld)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "twisted, rugged, knotty \nGNARLED is used about the rough, twisted, knotty appearance of the branches on oak and other trees. \n\"The kite was caught in the GNARLED branches of the tree.\" \nFrom this use the word has come to be applied to anything or anyone that looks rugged, tough, or weatherbeaten. \n\"His hands were GNARLED from years of hard work.\" \n\"The GNARLED old cowboy told us many exciting tales of his younger days.\" \nOther forms of the word: GNARL, v."
      },
      "FLATTER": {
        "word": "FLATTER",
        "phonetic": "(flat'-ÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to over praise; to show favorably \nTo FLATTER someone is to praise him more than he deserves, usually with the hope of gaining something. \n\"The noblemen FLATTERED the king by telling him what a great leader he was.\" \n\"Ted tried to FLATTER her, but she realized he wasn't sincere with his compliments.\" \nIn a related sense, FLATTER means \"to show off to advantage.\" \n\"That photograph FLATTERS her. She's not really that good-looking.\" \nOther forms of the word: FLATTERY, n."
      },
      "EXTERMINATE": {
        "word": "EXTERMINATE",
        "phonetic": "(ek-ster'-mÔøΩnAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to destroy completely, wipe out, put an end to, get rid of \nTo EXTERMINATE something is to wipe it out, to destroy it totally. The word is used about people, ideas, pests, diseases, and other things. \n\"The enemy tried to EXTERMINATE us, but somehow a few of us managed to survive.\" \n\"Our attempt to EXTERMINATE this new disease was completely successful; no cases of it were reported last year.\" \nAn EXTERMINATOR is someone who EXTERMINATES, particularly someone whose job is to EXTERMINATE insects, rats, or other pests. \n\"The new house was so filled with bugs, we had to call the EXTERMINATOR.\" \nIn the Pretest, _stop_ is often chosen as the meaning of EXTERMINATE. EXTERMINATE is a much stronger word than stop, however. To EXTERMINATE means to _destroy completely_. \nOther forms of the word: EXTERMINATION, n. \nEXTERMINATOR, n."
      },
      "LAG": {
        "word": "LAG",
        "phonetic": "(lag)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to fall behind, fail to keep up To \nLAG is to go too slow, to fail to keep up the pace. \n\"All the runners kept on going, but Jim was tired and LAGGED behind.\" \n\"The two of us LAGGED behind the others so that we could talk some more.\" \nSometimes LAG is used to mean \"to weaken little by little, to become less active.\" \"After a while his interest in history began to LAG.\" \nUsage: LAG is often followed by _behind_."
      },
      "FATAL": {
        "word": "FATAL",
        "phonetic": "(fAt'-1)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "deadly, mortal, disastrous \nFATE is the influence or power that is supposed to control our lives. \nFATAL is an adjective from FATE. See _-al_ under Suffixes. The basic meaning of FATAL is \"determining one's FATE.\" \nThe word is generally used about death, which is everyone's ultimate FATE. A FATAL accident is one that causes death; a FATAL dose of a drug is one large enough to bring about death. Sometimes the word is used about things that are so bad or disastrous that they seem deadly. \n\"This one FATAL mistake caused many problems for her later on.\" \nA FATALITY is a death, usually one caused by an accident or a disaster. \n\"The police reported seven FATALITIES on the icy highway that night.\" \nOther forms of the word: _FATE_, n. _FATALITY_, n."
      },
      "HEX": {
        "word": "HEX",
        "phonetic": "(heks)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a curse, evil spell, jinx \nA HEX is an evil spell, a curse that a witch might put on someone. \n\"When the machine kept breaking down, it began to look as though someone had put a HEX on it.\" \n\"There must be a HEX on those people; everything they do turns out wrong.\" \nHEX can also be used as a verb. \n\"Dave thought that if anyone even mentioned losing it might somehow HEX the team.\""
      },
      "IMPOSTOR": {
        "word": "IMPOSTOR",
        "phonetic": "{im-pos'-tÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a pretender, faker, fraud \nAn IMPOSTOR is a person who pretends to be someone he is not. \n\"The man said he was from the F.B.I., but he turned out to be an IMPOSTOR.\" \n\"The doctor knew so little about medicine that we accused him of being an IMPOSTOR.\" \n\"It would be impossible for an IMPOSTOR to fool us.\""
      },
      "GLUM": {
        "word": "GLUM",
        "phonetic": "(gluhm)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "gloomy, sad, dejected \nGLUM is related to the word _gloom_. Someone who is GLUM is in low spirits; he is in a silent, unhappy mood. \n\"The student looked very GLUM as he waited in the principal's office.\" \n\"The GLUM athletes sat silently in the locker room after losing the game.\" \n\"Our mailman always looks GLUM. I don't think he likes his job.\""
      },
      "FEROCIOUS": {
        "word": "FEROCIOUS",
        "phonetic": "(fÔøΩrO'-sh:)s)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "fierce, savage, cruel, violently aggressive \nFEROCIOUS is used about animals and people and the way they act. It means \"extremely cruel, wild, and savage.\" \n\"The dog was small but FEROCIOUS: it would attack dogs three times its size.\" \n\"The FEROCIOUS battle lasted all day, with neither side giving an inch.\" \nThe noun from FEROCIOUS is FEROCITY. \n\"The FEROCITY of his criticism surprised us; we didn't think he had disliked it that much.\" \n\"His FEROCITY when he was angry made everyone afraid of him.\" \nOther forms of the word: FEROCITY, n."
      },
      "INTERIOR": {
        "word": "INTERIOR",
        "phonetic": "(in-tir'-E-:)r)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "the inside \nSee _in-_ under Prefixes. The INTERIOR of something is its inside. \n\"She liked the house from the outside, but thought its INTERIOR was very ugly.\" \n\"He traveled from the coast to the INTERIOR of the country.\" An \"INTERIOR decorator\" is a person who decorates the insides of houses and buildings. The opposite of INTERIOR is _exterior_, the _outside_. \n_Decoration_ is often chosen as the meaning of INTERIOR. People who pick decoration have probably heard the phrase INTERIOR _decoration_ but don't know exactly what it means."
      },
      "EXPENSE": {
        "word": "EXPENSE",
        "phonetic": "(ek-spens')",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "price, cost, spending \nThe EXPENSE of something is how much it costs, how much you have to pay for it. This cost is usually calculated in terms of money. \n\"I want that car, no matter what the EXPENSE.\" \n\"He worried about the EXPENSE of the trip.\" \nEXPENSE can refer to other things besides money. \n\"He stayed outside in the snowstorm, at great EXPENSE to his health\"—that is, he paid the price for staying outside by becoming sick. \n\"We managed to finish the project, but it required a tremendous EXPENSE of time and energy.\" Something that is EXPENSIVE causes EXPENSE—costs a lot of money or more than it is worth. \n\"This car is too EXPENSIVE; I have to find one that costs less.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXPEND, v. EXPENSIVE, adj."
      },
      "GLEEFUL": {
        "word": "GLEEFUL",
        "phonetic": "(glE'-fal)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "merry, joyous, glad \nGLEE is _joy_, especially joy caused by triumph or success. \n\"He shouted with GLEE as they called out his name as the winner.\" \nGLEEFUL means \"full of GLEE.\" \n\"He was GLEEFUL at the news that he had been accepted at college.\" \n\"The GLEEFUL child got onto her new bicycle.\" \n_Excited_ is a common choice as the meaning of GLEEFUL. A GLEEFUL person will usually be _excited_, but GLEEFUL has to do with joy and happiness, not with excitement. \nOther forms of the word: GLEE, n."
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "ASSASSIN",
        "CONFIDENT",
        "ENCOURAGE",
        "GRIEF",
        "LAG",
        "ASSAULT",
        "DECEASED",
        "EXPENSE",
        "HEX",
        "NAVIGATE",
        "AUTHORITY",
        "DEVOTION",
        "FATAL",
        "HOBBLE",
        "RESIST",
        "BAWL",
        "DOZE",
        "GNARLED",
        "IMPOSTOR",
        "SHRIEK",
        "CIRCUMSTANCE",
        "ABOLISH",
        "ELEMENTARY",
        "FAINT",
        "HOMICIDE",
        "MOOD",
        "CIRCULATE",
        "ENCOUNTER",
        "FEROCIOUS",
        "INCINERATE",
        "MUFFLE",
        "CONVENIENT",
        "ESTABLISH",
        "FLATTER",
        "INSTRUCT",
        "OCCASIONALLY",
        "DEFECT",
        "EXPEDITION",
        "GLEEFUL",
        "INTERIOR",
        "QUAKE",
        "DEFORMED",
        "EXTERMINATE",
        "GLUM",
        "LINK"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "The company paid for the entire",
          "part2": "of his trip to New York.",
          "answer": "expense"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Fred",
          "part2": "off while watching television, and didn't wake up until midnight.",
          "answer": "dozed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Billy started to",
          "part2": "when we told him he couldn't come to the movies with us.",
          "answer": "bawl"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The governor gave them the",
          "part2": "to arrest people caught stealing.",
          "answer": "authority"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Sam knew he would get into trouble if he called Jane a liar, so he",
          "part2": "the temptation to speak his mind.",
          "answer": "resisted"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Ted claimed a witch had put a(n)",
          "part2": "on him, and that was why he did so poorly on the test.",
          "answer": "hex"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The coach was impressed by Jim's",
          "part2": "to the team. He was at every practice, even when he was injured.",
          "answer": "devotion"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The police claimed that Jones was the",
          "part2": "who shot the politician.",
          "answer": "assassin"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I've never seen such",
          "part2": "over the death of a bird. Poor Judy is crying day and night.",
          "answer": "grief"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The children",
          "part2": "with fear when they saw the lion running toward them.",
          "answer": "shrieked"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Whenever he felt the pain in his foot he could only",
          "part2": "; it hurt too much to walk normally.",
          "answer": "hobble"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He is now",
          "part2": ", but he was a wonderful fellow when he was alive.",
          "answer": "deceased"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The younger children started to",
          "part2": "behind and had to run to catch up with the others.",
          "answer": "lag"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The villain underestimating the police proved a",
          "part2": "mistake in his grand plans.",
          "answer": "fatal"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I am",
          "part2": "that when you see what I have done you will approve of it.",
          "answer": "confident"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Her praise will",
          "part2": "me to try even harder next time.",
          "answer": "encourage"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They had to",
          "part2": "the ship through some dangerous rocks to reach the harbor.",
          "answer": "navigate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Under no",
          "part2": "will you be allowed to go outside by yourself.",
          "answer": "circumstances"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Some people like the",
          "part2": ", weatherbeaten look of old log cabins.",
          "answer": "gnarled"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The drunk tried to",
          "part2": "the police officer.",
          "answer": "assault"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We thought they were real policemen, but later found out they were",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "impostors"
        },
        {
          "part1": "All the insects in the house have been",
          "part2": ", so you needn't worry about them.",
          "answer": "exterminated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They said he died of natural causes, but the detective suspected it was actually",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "homicide"
        },
        {
          "part1": "When the new king came to power he",
          "part2": "all the harsh laws of the old king.",
          "answer": "abolished"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The janitor",
          "part2": "all the rubbish until there was nothing but ashes left.",
          "answer": "incinerated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Tom began to",
          "part2": "with fear when he was told to go to the principal's office.",
          "answer": "quake"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Many soldiers were injured in the brief military",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "encounter"
        },
        {
          "part1": "If you want him to like you, you have to",
          "part2": "him by telling him how clever he is.",
          "answer": "flatter"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Each elephant held the next one's tail in its trunk, so that they were all",
          "part2": "together in a chain for the parade.",
          "answer": "linked"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The doctor told him that his badly injured hand would always be slightly",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "deformed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I felt pretty",
          "part2": "when I didn't make the team.",
          "answer": "glum"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The people at the funeral did not feel particularly",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "gleeful"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Jennifer was in such a good",
          "part2": "that she even said hello to her worst enemy.",
          "answer": "mood"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She kept the iron in a place that wasn't very",
          "part2": "for me, since I needed a ladder to reach it.",
          "answer": "convenient"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He had only heard about the book from friends, so he only had a(n)",
          "part2": "idea of what it was about.",
          "answer": "faint"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The lawyer",
          "part2": "the fact that the witness was at the scene of the murder.",
          "answer": "established"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They",
          "part2": "went on camping trips—once a year or so.",
          "answer": "occasionally"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Arthur",
          "part2": "a statement around the classroom saying why he should be elected class president.",
          "answer": "circulated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The lioness gave a(n)",
          "part2": "snarl whenever anyone tried to pick up one of her cubs.",
          "answer": "ferocious"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He put a blanket over his drum to",
          "part2": "the noise when he was practicing.",
          "answer": "muffle"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The doctor",
          "part2": "the patient to take the medicine three times a day.",
          "answer": "instructed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Almost every kind of learning starts with the",
          "part2": "principles and then progresses to more advanced study.",
          "answer": "elementary"
        },
        {
          "part1": "There are so many",
          "part2": "in his work that we don't know where to begin telling him what's wrong.",
          "answer": "defects"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They bought supplies and equipment for their",
          "part2": "into the jungle.",
          "answer": "expedition"
        },
        {
          "part1": "From the outside the place looked like a barn, but the",
          "part2": "was very beautiful.",
          "answer": "interior"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
]